<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>BicycleTips.com Tips, Tricks, Product and Ride Reviews</title>
    <description>A cycling website dedicated to bringing you the latest tips, tricks, product and ride reviews, primarily focused on gravel cycling.</description>
    <link>https://www.bicycletips.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://www.bicycletips.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 05:45:50 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 05:45:50 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.3.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Unbound Gravel 2024: Your Guide to Registration Options</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;So Unbound Gravel 2024 is coming up, with registrations opening already (depending on your status and distance).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are you gearing up for the Unbound Gravel 2024? Here’s everything you need to know about registration:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;random-selection-process-lotto&quot;&gt;Random Selection Process (Lotto)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due to overwhelming demand, a random selection process determines participants for the 350-mile, 200-mile, 100-mile, 50-mile, and 25-mile events. Registration is free, but credit card details are required upon application. Charges apply only upon acceptance. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.unboundgravel.com/&quot;&gt;More info&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;lottery-registration-dates&quot;&gt;Lottery Registration Dates&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;UNBOUND Gravel XL Lottery: December 1-15, 2023.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;UNBOUND Gravel 200, 100, 50, and 25 Lotteries: January 5-20, 2024.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;life-time-members-early-access&quot;&gt;Life Time Members Early Access&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Life Time members, with a minimum of six months’ membership, get early access to event registrations and guaranteed spots in lotteries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(sourced from social media)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The LT early access doesn’t open until a week prior to the lottery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Gravel XL – May 31, 2024&lt;br /&gt;
Member Guaranteed Registration: November 24, 2023&lt;br /&gt;
General Lottery: December 1-15, 2023&lt;br /&gt;
Member registration opens at 10 AM MST on 11/24/23&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;UNBOUND Gravel 200/100 –June 1, 2024&lt;br /&gt;
Member Guaranteed Registration: December 29, 2023&lt;br /&gt;
General Lottery: Jan 5-20, 2024&lt;br /&gt;
Member registration opens at 10 AM MST on 12/29/23&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;notification-and-fees&quot;&gt;Notification and Fees&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Selected participants will be notified by email. Event fees, processing fees, and taxes will be charged upon selection. Entry fees for various distances are yet to be determined.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;registration-rules&quot;&gt;Registration Rules&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Only one application per person is allowed. Special consideration is given to multi-time finishers nearing the 1,000 Mile Club status. Life Time members with a qualifying membership duration can bypass the lottery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;deferral-policy&quot;&gt;Deferral Policy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Participants can defer their entry to the following year, with varying fees based on how far in advance the deferral is requested. No refunds or transfers are allowed. (deferred registration was November 2023, and is closed now)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;alternative-entry-options&quot;&gt;Alternative Entry Options&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apart from the lottery, you can gain entry by collaborating with charity partners, signing up for UNBOUND Gravel Training Camp, or opting for a coaching package. Volunteering at the event also offers future participation benefits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stay tuned for more updates and start planning your journey to one of the most challenging and rewarding gravel events in the world!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2023 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.bicycletips.com/unbound-gravel-2024-lotto</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bicycletips.com/unbound-gravel-2024-lotto</guid>
        
        
        <category>Bike</category>
        
        <category>Gravel</category>
        
        <category>Unbound</category>
        
        <category>LifeTime</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Bicycle Maintenance Tips and Instructions</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Bike Maintenance Instructions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cleaning:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Regular cleaning is an essential part of bike maintenance. Before performing any maintenance, you should start by cleaning the bike frame, chain, gears, and other parts.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;To clean the bike, you’ll need a degreaser and a soft cloth. Apply the degreaser to the areas that need cleaning, such as the chain, gears, and frame, and scrub gently with the cloth.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;This will help remove grime and dirt that can build up over time. Once you’ve finished cleaning, rinse the bike with water to remove any leftover degreaser.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lubrication:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;After cleaning, you should lubricate the chain and gears.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;A good lubricant will help protect the metal parts from rust and corrosion, and it will also make the bike run more smoothly.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Apply a few drops of lubricant to the chain, and then use a clean cloth to spread it evenly. Be sure to lubricate the gears as well, especially those that are exposed to the elements.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tires:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Check the tires for proper pressure and inspect them for damage or wear.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;If you’re using a road bike, you should aim for a pressure of around 100-130 psi, while mountain bikes typically require a lower pressure of around 30-50 psi.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;If the pressure is too low, use a pump to fill the tires to the correct level.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Check the tires for cuts, punctures, or other signs of damage, and replace the tire if necessary.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Brakes:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Check the brake pads for wear and adjust if needed.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;If the brake pads are worn down to the metal, they will need to be replaced.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Check the brake cables as well, and make sure they are tightened properly.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;If the brakes are not functioning properly, you may need to take the bike to a professional mechanic for a more in-depth inspection.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Drivetrain:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Check the tightness of the bolts on the crank arm, pedals, and bottom bracket, and tighten any that are loose.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Check the gears to make sure they are shifting smoothly.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;If the gears are not shifting properly, you may need to adjust the derailleur.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Steering:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Check the tightness of the stem bolts, headset, and handlebar, and tighten any that are loose.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Make sure the handlebars are positioned correctly, and that the bike is easy to steer.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;If the steering feels loose or wobbly, you may need to take the bike to a professional mechanic for further inspection.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Suspension:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;If your bike has suspension, it’s important to check it regularly to make sure it’s functioning properly.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Check for proper suspension function and adjust accordingly.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;If the suspension feels stiff or bouncy, you may need to make some adjustments.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Wheel true:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Ensure that the wheels spin straight and true.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;If the wheels are not true, you may need to make some adjustments to keep the bike riding smoothly.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Chain wear:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Over time, the chain will start to wear down and stretch.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;To check for chain wear, use a chain wear indicator tool.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;If the chain is worn, it will need to be replaced to avoid damage to the gears.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;A worn chain will cause shifting problems, so it’s important to replace it promptly.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Final Inspection:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;After performing all the above checks and maintenance, give the bike a final inspection.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Test ride the bike to ensure it is running smoothly and everything is functioning properly.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Check the brakes, gears, and steering, and make any necessary adjustments.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;If anything seems out of place, take the bike back to a professional mechanic for further inspection.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note:&lt;/em&gt; Regular maintenance is important to keep your bike running smoothly and to extend its lifespan. If you are unsure about performing any of these maintenance tasks, take the bike to a professional mechanic for assistance.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.bicycletips.com/bicyce-maintenance</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bicycletips.com/bicyce-maintenance</guid>
        
        
        <category>Bike</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Getting into Unbound Gravel 2023</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Did you know that the Lotto for entry into Unbound Gravel 2023 opens today? (January 5th, 2023). If you are interested in getting into the event, you should definitely check out our post from last year on various registration options &lt;a href=&quot;/unbound-gravel-2022-registration-options&quot;&gt;Unbound Gravel Registration Options&lt;/a&gt; page for more information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good luck if you are trying to get in! I just got my registration squared away and will be riding 100 miles again this year, planning to drop time from my finish last year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t forget, if you don’t get in through the Lotto, you can still volunteer in ‘23, if it is like past years, if you volunteer 10 hours, you get to bypass the lotto for ‘24.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.bicycletips.com/unbound-gravel-2023-lotto</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bicycletips.com/unbound-gravel-2023-lotto</guid>
        
        
        <category>Bike</category>
        
        <category>Gravel</category>
        
        <category>Unbound</category>
        
        <category>LifeTime</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Finding a place to stay at Unbound Gravel</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;So you’re thinking you might want to go to Unbound Gravel 2023? The lottery won’t open up until January 2023, but if you haven’t booked a hotel already, you’re out of luck.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Emporia’s hotels book up really quickly. If you haven’t booked already, you are likely out of luck, but if you follow some of the tips below, we’ll try to help you find a place to stay that doesn’t take you an hour plus of driving each way (Topeka).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(6/30/2022) I was able to book a room at a hotel this morning, so there are still some available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So here are the tricks to finding a hotel in Emporia Kansas for Unbound Gravel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Start early. I start looking at hotel websites the weekend of the current year’s event. Most hotels don’t open up their booking windows that far in advance, but some do, and the rest have them open soon there after.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Look often. Check your hotel websites DAILY, if not morning and evening, to increase your odds of finding when they open up the booking window.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Check all the hotels in Emporia&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Avoid the Knight’s Inn. People apparently are able to book here, but from what I hear the past two years, it actually doesn’t exist anymore, it isn’t open.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Check again&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Don’t fret if you don’t find a hotel, keep looking! In January people who don’t make the lottery will start cancelling their bookings.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Look into the college dorms, they typically open up for registration in January or February, but sell out quickly. Their rates include meals as well.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;As we get closer to the ride, pay attention to the Unbound Gravel (unofficial) Facebook Group. People often times post there when 9hey are cancelling their rooms.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Look outside of Emporia, get a room that can be cancelled at no charge in case you find something in town.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Keep looking!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re diligent, you can almost assuredly get yourself a hotel room in Emporia for Unbound Gravel!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2022 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.bicycletips.com/unbound-gravel-hotels</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bicycletips.com/unbound-gravel-hotels</guid>
        
        
        <category>Bike</category>
        
        <category>Gravel</category>
        
        <category>Unbound</category>
        
        <category>LifeTime</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Unbound Gravel 100 2022 Ride Review</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Unbound Gravel 2022, was awesome…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Planning for this adventure started in 2019 after I completed the 100 mile event at what was then known as Dirty Kanza. In July 2019, Wagner (Wags) and I went to Emporia for the Lunar Kanza, there I got a golden ticket, allowing me to bypass the lotto for 2020.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I signed up for 2020, covid happened. I deferred to 2021. 2021 happened. I had a worse year in 2021 than I did in 2020, found out I had a heart issue (Afib) and kidney stones, random other things. I deferred out of 2021. Wags and I went to Emporia in June anyways. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bicycletips.com/unbound-gravel-2021&quot;&gt;It was an absolute f’n blast&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year was going to be different, I used my 2021 deferral, Wagner used his 2021 volunteer hours, and we brought Myckel along with us as well as he had also gone and volunteered in ‘21. Myckel and I signed up for 200 Miles, Wagner was realistic and signed up for 100 miles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Training for 2022 was off and on. I ended up going into AFib again in February, so I was derailed for a couple of weeks with that, and then came down with a cold. Outside of that, life simply got in the way, kids sports, work commitments, weather, etc, led to not riding near enough to try and ride 200 miles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Going into the weekend, Myckel had switched to the 100 route, I knew I was going to when I got onsite, but I was hoping I could get my number plate with my name on it, so I didn’t change until I was onsite (more on that later).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;thursday&quot;&gt;Thursday&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We left St. Louis Thursday morning. The group this year was Myckel, Wagner and myself, along with Wagner’s wife there to provide SAG for us misfits. Myckel picked me up, I got a few work calls in on the drive. The Wagner family left town around the same time. The drive out to Kansas was easy, St. Louis to Emporia is not a bad drive at all, ~5.5 hours I think for us with a stop along the way to grab some Chick-Fil-A outside of Kansas City.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-1-800-f872d056a.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Stopped at Chick-Fil-A&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-1-200-f872d056a.jpg 200w, /assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-1-400-f872d056a.jpg 400w, /assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-1-800-f872d056a.jpg 800w, /assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-1-1600-f872d056a.jpg 1600w, /assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-1-2000-f872d056a.jpg 2000w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We arrived and went straight to the hotel, I had two rooms booked at the Econolodge (same location we stayed in 2021) and Myckel had a room booked at the ESU dorm. He dropped me off and I got checked in, things loaded into the room, and then got the bike ready to head downtown for a shake out ride. The guy at Econolodge tried to offer us two connected rooms, with only one working bathroom, for a $10/night discount. I declined, the discount got moved to $20 a night, but still declined. If it was 4 dudes in the two rooms, perhaps, but with Wags’ wife there, it didn’t make sense to try to save a little dough for the inconvenience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;check-in&quot;&gt;Check In&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once we had the room squared way, we suited up and headed downtown. The goal was to get in on a group ride with the Major Taylor Cycling Club out of KC, and also spend some time walking around the Expo, in addition, we needed to get checked in for the weekend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The check in for Unbound is always in the same place, a beautiful three story building, the &lt;a href=&quot;Lyon County History Center&quot;&gt;https://www.flickr.com/photos/chammond/47997788691&lt;/a&gt;. We trek’d upstairs and got into our appropriate check in areas. I checked in to the 200 route, while Wags checked into 100. I then immediately got into the “change” line. There I was easily able to switch from the 200 mile route to the 100 mile route. But I was told I had to turn in my 200 mile number plate and timing chip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a few attempts at asking very nicely, I was able to get the lady who helped me to rip the timing chip off the plate so I could keep the one with my name on it. I was given a different plate, with no name, for the 100 route. I totally get why they wouldn’t want to have extra plates out there, and extra timing chips. I was very thankful that she let me keep mine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-2-800-6dd1d11a0.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Unbound Gravel Sign Selfie&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-2-200-6dd1d11a0.jpg 200w, /assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-2-400-6dd1d11a0.jpg 400w, /assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-2-800-6dd1d11a0.jpg 800w, /assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-2-1500-6dd1d11a0.jpg 1500w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;expo&quot;&gt;Expo&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After check in, we headed to the Expo. I think this year there were something like 290 vendors at the expo. This expo at Unbound/DK is just amazing. The swag you can get, the gear you can buy, the people you can meet, is absolutely one of the best parts of the weekend! One thing to keep in mind with the Unbound Gravel expo is that it ends at 5pm on Friday evening, it is gone by about 5:15pm. You won’t find 99% of the vendors on Saturday or Sunday, though you can find Muc-Off after the event (more later).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I saw Isabel King taking a selfie with someone, so I went up and asked if I could have one too. She’s easy to spot as she is almost always in bright orange, I dig that look.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-3-800-ed938b799.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Unbound Gravel Sign Selfie with Isabel King&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-3-200-ed938b799.jpg 200w, /assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-3-400-ed938b799.jpg 400w, /assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-3-800-ed938b799.jpg 800w, /assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-3-1500-ed938b799.jpg 1500w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wags and I also make it a point to get a selfie with Big Tall Wayne, Stetina’s mechanic. He’s a great guy, and always up for a chat whenever we see him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-4-800-e8f0cd930.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Unbound Gravel Sign Selfie with Big Tall Wayne and Wags&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-4-200-e8f0cd930.jpg 200w, /assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-4-400-e8f0cd930.jpg 400w, /assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-4-800-e8f0cd930.jpg 800w, /assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-4-1600-e8f0cd930.jpg 1600w, /assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-4-2000-e8f0cd930.jpg 2000w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;shake-out-ride&quot;&gt;Shake out ride&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the expo we headed back to the car to get ready for a group ride. Group rides are a plenty at Unbound. Thursday afternoon’s ride was our first, but not the first of the weekend, and not our last. We met at the Major Taylor booth in the Expo and headed out with a couple hundred people for a 13-14 mile ride south east of Emporia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ride was tame, not a race, not very well organized. A couple of times the lead group didn’t know where to make a turn and would have to turn around to catch a turn they missed. I had the route on my computer, so I knew where I was going. I spent a bit of time talking with a guy from Smithville, MO. He was in town just for the group rides and the expo. He told me his first gravel ride was about an hour earlier when he joined a different group ride. He mentioned that he helped with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bikereg.com/humphrey-100-gravel-grinder&quot;&gt;Humphrey’s Gravel Grinder&lt;/a&gt; put on in Smithville, which happened a few weeks earlier. I may have to try to put that one on the calendar next year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ride was good, nothing too technical, not too fast, not too slow. &lt;a href=&quot;https://nelsonvails.com/&quot;&gt;Nelson Vails&lt;/a&gt; was the guest for the ride, he spoke before the ride, and then was friendly and chatting it up with various folks on the ride. I passed him at one point because he was slowing down on his cell phone, of course I chose the muddiest section of the ride and coated my Grizl in mud.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-5-800-f17fc182f.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Unbound Gravel Sign Selfie with Nelson Vails and Wags&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-5-200-f17fc182f.jpg 200w, /assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-5-400-f17fc182f.jpg 400w, /assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-5-800-f17fc182f.jpg 800w, /assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-5-1600-f17fc182f.jpg 1600w, /assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-5-2000-f17fc182f.jpg 2000w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Post ride we put the bikes back on the rack and walked around town a bit to find a place for dinner. We ended up at the Mexican place right on Commercial St, putting our names on the list and then wandering a bit more. The restaurant was packed with gravel riders and crew. We had a good meal, though service was slow, it was packed as previously stated, so I am completely fine with the slowness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;friday&quot;&gt;Friday&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Friday morning started with a 730am wake up. I haven’t slept well in hotels in years, most definitely not when I am coming up on a big event, so sleeping until 730 was a pleasant surprise. A quick shower and then we headed out the door to get over towards the next group ride. This group ride was supposed to be the Chamois Buttr ride, we found the CB tent setup behind Mulready’s, grabbed a little swag from the HED table, and then walked up the street to the donut shop on Commercial. We learned last year that their donuts are excellent, and we weren’t disappointed for 2022.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;shake-out-ride-1&quot;&gt;Shake out ride&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a few donuts and juice we headed back to the car to get the bikes ready. A quick check over, change into our riding gear, and we were back at the Expo lining up for the ride. If there were a few hundred at the Thursday evening ride, it felt like there were a thousand for this one (likely 500, but maybe more). Once again I had the ride loaded up in my Garmin, so when we took off, and the entire group took a turn that wasn’t on the route in my computer, we went off on our own. Exactly one block later we were back with the group as they simply took an extra turn VS the route we went.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-7-800-61235baaf.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Friday Morning Shake Out Ride Selfie&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-7-200-61235baaf.jpg 200w, /assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-7-400-61235baaf.jpg 400w, /assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-7-800-61235baaf.jpg 800w, /assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-7-1500-61235baaf.jpg 1500w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ride was uneventful, but once again beautiful. Post ride we loaded the bikes back up on the car and ventured into the Expo again. Grabbing swag, and a few selfies along the way. I went to the Canyon booth and had them &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bicycletips.com/ordering-a-bike-from-canyon&quot;&gt;swap out a chain ring on my bike that I’ve had bend 3 times since I received the bike back in December&lt;/a&gt;. The tech there was super helpful and had it swapped out in a few minutes. I am still waiting on Shimano to send the replacement ring, fortunately my brother sent me one earlier in May. I tried to stop by the Orange Seal booth to get my sealant topped off, but was told I would need to come back because it was too busy. I stopped at the Polar Bottle booth and had a great conversation with those guys. I got a bottle or two, along with a t-shirt, for posting a dirty bike on social media. Little did they know that the next day they would have plenty of dirty bikes to post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-9-800-f012cf811.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Canyon Support&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-9-200-f012cf811.jpg 200w, /assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-9-400-f012cf811.jpg 400w, /assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-9-800-f012cf811.jpg 800w, /assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-9-1600-f012cf811.jpg 1600w, /assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-9-2000-f012cf811.jpg 2000w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-10-800-b055a30ec.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Canyon Truck&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-10-200-b055a30ec.jpg 200w, /assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-10-400-b055a30ec.jpg 400w, /assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-10-800-b055a30ec.jpg 800w, /assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-10-1600-b055a30ec.jpg 1600w, /assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-10-2000-b055a30ec.jpg 2000w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Around 1230 we headed over to the Granada Theater to catch a presentation from Nelson Vails. I’ll be blunt, it was an odd presentation. He talked about his pro riding after his olympic medal, mostly time spent in Japan I believe. Why was it odd? I am not even sure, the way he talked about himself I guess. I was hoping to hear more of his life story, I honestly had never heard of him prior to Friday, so I was hoping to learn more. Instead we got an overview of how racing in Japan in the 90s worked. It sounded like Horse racing, but guys on bikes instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;expo-1&quot;&gt;Expo&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After that we spent another couple of hours in the Expo grabbing more swag for the kids (right?). A guy that I know from work (Matt) arrived that afternoon and joined us. His hotel was closed even though you could make bookings online, so he bunked up in my room as I had two beds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The prior two years while in Emporia I was able to get a selfie with Alison Tetrick, so this year I wanted to make sure and try to make it three times. I was able to get a photo with her in the Expo this year, as opposed to at the finish afterwards. I figured I would get one on Friday, knowing I might not be around the finish line much on Saturday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-12-800-24cbb2fb9.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Expo Selfie with Alison Tetrick&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-12-200-24cbb2fb9.jpg 200w, /assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-12-400-24cbb2fb9.jpg 400w, /assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-12-800-24cbb2fb9.jpg 800w, /assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-12-1500-24cbb2fb9.jpg 1500w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We made a stop at the local Wal Mart to get a couple of supplies, primarily breakfast for Saturday morning. I think I grabbed a couple of donuts, and some pop-tarts, a super healthy setup for sure. I also picked up a gallon of water, being not 100% sure what the water situation would be like at the checkpoint.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Friday evening was spent with a quick meal, a local food truck that has a building they attach to for normal business. Then final prep getting everything ready for Saturday. I made it a point to try to have the lights off and be sleeping by 10pm. Did I meet that goal? Perhaps, closer than I figured I would be at least.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;saturday&quot;&gt;Saturday&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Saturday morning started early. I think I had my alarm set for 4:40am, possibly a little earlier. My daily wake up shower followed by getting into the bike kit for the day, lathering up with Chamois Buttr. I scarfed down the donuts at the hotel and a Starbucks Frappuccino as we got into town. We wanted to try to get over and catch the start of the 200 mile ride. I ran up towards the front and watched those riders take off. The 200 ride was delayed by about 5 minutes as there was a train crossing the road not too far from the starting line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-15-800-2786e406a.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Unbound Gravel 200 Start Line&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-15-200-2786e406a.jpg 200w, /assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-15-400-2786e406a.jpg 400w, /assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-15-800-2786e406a.jpg 800w, /assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-15-1600-2786e406a.jpg 1600w, /assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-15-2000-2786e406a.jpg 2000w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After that it was time to start getting ourselves ready. We headed back to the car, got the bikes off the rack, took any extra layers of clothing off. Final prep on the bikes, ensuring that we had all the appropriate gear, helmets, glasses, gloves, water bottles, food, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From there we made a quick stop at the local church. I knew from 2019 that the church offered up breakfast, and even more importantly, bathrooms! Indoor bathrooms even, always a plus!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-17-800-9ade15ab1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Unbound Gravel 100 10 Hour Group&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-17-200-9ade15ab1.jpg 200w, /assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-17-400-9ade15ab1.jpg 400w, /assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-17-800-9ade15ab1.jpg 800w, /assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-17-1500-9ade15ab1.jpg 1500w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the restroom we headed up into the starting shute. I went towards the 10 hour finishers section, knowing that I wasn’t planning on finishing much faster than that. My time in 2019 was 11.5 hours I think, with a 1 hour break at the aid station. This year I was hoping to minimize the time spent on my stop, and also just overall ride faster, knowing that the weather was looking cooler than the prior 2 years I’ve been in Emporia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-16-800-80fb32c72.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Unbound Gravel 100 Starting Selfie&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-16-200-80fb32c72.jpg 200w, /assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-16-400-80fb32c72.jpg 400w, /assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-16-800-80fb32c72.jpg 800w, /assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-16-1600-80fb32c72.jpg 1600w, /assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-16-2000-80fb32c72.jpg 2000w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ride started out slowly, as one does with over a thousand people starting out. We headed south out of town with a police escort, after a couple of miles we hit gravel, then things got REALLY slow. I guess some people went down in the first corner on gravel, my assumption is that slowed things down to start. We ended up getting slowed mainly by a mud puddle pinch point. Basically a section of gravel road that was wet on both sides, but there was a dry route through it, but it ultimately choked things down as everyone was trying to stay dry and mud free (heh, more on that later).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-18-800-079e366d8.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Choke point for the first mud&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-18-200-079e366d8.jpg 200w, /assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-18-400-079e366d8.jpg 400w, /assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-18-800-079e366d8.jpg 800w, /assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-18-1500-079e366d8.jpg 1500w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shortly after this, I was riding solo. Wagner and Myckel were off, I figured that would be the case, I just didn’t figure I would be solo before 10 miles. Oh well, I was going to go my pace and make sure I finished.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-19-800-f2eea5c03.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Solo riding&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-19-200-f2eea5c03.jpg 200w, /assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-19-400-f2eea5c03.jpg 400w, /assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-19-800-f2eea5c03.jpg 800w, /assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-19-1500-f2eea5c03.jpg 1500w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The weather for the first 40 miles was simply amazing. While it did spit rain here and there, it was not enough to collect anywhere, or even make the road wet. I tried to make myself drink fluids ever 5 miles to ensure I stayed hydrated. It was cool, some might even say chilly (not me), so I was trying to be diligent about drinking my Scratch Labs mix. I started out with a frozen water bladder, so I couldn’t drink a lot at once as I was waiting for it to melt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first shot of fluid I got was shocking, apparently I hadn’t mixed the Scratch in very well before freezing, so I got a super rich burst of flavor. I immediately thought that if I had a full bag of that much flavor there was no way I was going to be able to drink it, it was far too strong. Thankfully as the rest of the ice pack melted it watered things down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-22-800-63dde9492.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A Llama&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-22-200-63dde9492.jpg 200w, /assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-22-400-63dde9492.jpg 400w, /assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-22-800-63dde9492.jpg 800w, /assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-22-1500-63dde9492.jpg 1500w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those first 40 miles, the route itself was absolutely beautiful. We went though a section they called the Cattle Pens, I feel like some of this was private land, not public roads. We crossed over the highway a couple of times, we saw a big life sized Lama (cutout) and people cheering us on. There was also a printed sign about Nickelback, I don’t remember exactly what it said, but I was highly offended by it, as with anything Nickelback related.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-23-800-191ec2c78.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A curious cow&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-23-200-191ec2c78.jpg 200w, /assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-23-400-191ec2c78.jpg 400w, /assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-23-800-191ec2c78.jpg 800w, /assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-23-1500-191ec2c78.jpg 1500w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At one point I had two riders in front of me that I was coming up on. Off to the right was a lone cow that was making its way over towards the gravel road, and more importantly, making its way to us. Based on what I had seen from a ride earlier this year, where a bull charged and hit multiple riders I had no intention of being someone hit by a cow. I did however pull my camera out and take some photos as I started speaking with the cow, saying something along the lines of “Hey buddy, how are you? Good buddy, good buddy, stay over there”. I passed the cow without incident, and then noticed that both the riders I was coming up on, had put themselves to my left, placing me directly between themselves and the cow. Thanks guys.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-26-800-914c970ba.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Neutral water stop&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-26-200-914c970ba.jpg 200w, /assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-26-400-914c970ba.jpg 400w, /assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-26-800-914c970ba.jpg 800w, /assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-26-1600-914c970ba.jpg 1600w, /assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-26-2000-914c970ba.jpg 2000w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Around mile 41 or so, we came across the neutral water stop. This was an area where everyone could reload on water, but not via the help of your support crews. I stopped here and filled up my now empty water bladder, had a couple of snacks, and then got back on the route. Shortly after the stop was a Y, where you could go right for the 200 mile route, and left for the 100 mile route.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-25-800-99d137963.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Rain&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-25-200-99d137963.jpg 200w, /assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-25-400-99d137963.jpg 400w, /assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-25-800-99d137963.jpg 800w, /assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-25-1500-99d137963.jpg 1500w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shortly after the water stop, the skies opened up. It rained pretty darn good for the next 30 miles. I think at one point I heard thunder, but only once that I recall. At another point I had a rider ask me if I heard thunder (at that point all I heard was wind). The more it rained, the less photos I took.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I felt like the surface conditions of the route, at least one the 100 mile route I did, were actually far more tame than those conditions I remember on the northern route from 2019. I don’t recall any really rocky areas, maybe they were there but perhaps masked by water later in the ride.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only real dangers I saw were the cattle grates, as things got wet, they definitely could have caused some issues, but for me, I didn’t have any problems with them. I did come across one group after going through what appeared to be an entrance to a ranch, that was stopped to help a downed rider. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bicycletips.com/big-sugar-gravel-2021&quot;&gt;I had flashbacks to Big Sugar 2021&lt;/a&gt;. I don’t know what condition the rider was in, but it didn’t look good as I went by.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 30 miles after the water stop were pretty much all rain, all the time. At some point I realized I could see WAY better if I took my glasses off, otherwise they were wet and almost fogged over. I was riding pretty much solo, so I didn’t have to worry about rooster tails from anyone else covering me in dirt or water from the gravel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do recall at one point thinking, it’s raining hard enough that my tires are actually clean, there was so much water that they simply weren’t covered in dirt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I pulled into the check point looking for Wagner’s wife in the sag vehicle. I ended up almost out of town when &lt;a href=&quot;https://instagram.com/bigtallwayne&quot;&gt;BigTallWayne&lt;/a&gt; came over and asked me if I needed any help. Told him I was looking for my SAG vehicle, parked in front of a church. His response was “that could be anywhere in Kansas”, which was accurate. A local overheard me, and told me where I needed to head to to find the church, a quick backtrack with a right turn and I came across Mrs. Wags.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The aid stop was much appreciated, I had 2 or 3 Uncrustables (fake PB&amp;amp;J sandwiches), swapped to my second frozen (mostly) water bladder, chugged another bottle of water, emptied some trash and refilled some food. I also took off my gloves, sticking them into a jersey pocket. My gloves were actually difficult to take off, I don’t know if my fingers were swollen, or the gloves were just super wet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I considered changing jerseys, but figured it was pointless, it was still raining, or supposed to. I changed to a different pair of glasses that were in the SAG vehicle. This pair was setup with trail lenses, which I figured would be easier to see through in the overcast conditions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the aid station I got another loud cheer from the Canyon guys and headed out of town. There were a couple of folks heading out around the same time as me, but I was off again essentially solo. Wags and Myckel had gone through the aid station at least 45 minutes ahead of me, if not more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the aid station, the rain got worse. Around Mile 71 I came across the muddy section of road. Up until that point, even with the rain, the surfaces were great, but this mud was thick. People were starting to walk, but I wanted to try to ride as much as I could. I ended up passing by a guy who fell pretty hard, but was okay. Shortly there after I decided I was going to jump from the right track to the left track on the road, that was my mistake. I hit the thick soft mud and fell down to my right side. So this was two 100 mile rides in a row in Emporia where I fell. In 2019 I took a spill in the aid station, I got myself off balance when trying to get on the bike and went down on the same knee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-28-800-9ca1278ee.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Muddy Grizl&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-28-200-9ca1278ee.jpg 200w, /assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-28-400-9ca1278ee.jpg 400w, /assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-28-800-9ca1278ee.jpg 800w, /assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-28-1500-9ca1278ee.jpg 1500w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After taking the spill I decided I would walk. People were walking up the left side of the road, in the grass, along a barbed wire fence. I went that route, for a brief moment trying to carry my bike, but ultimately just walking with it. Eventually I got to a point where the grass was a good 5 to 6 feet above the road itself. The grass was all mashed down from the thousands of feet that had passed before me on the ride. The area to walk was getting narrower, and harder to walk and maintain control of the bike, so I decided I would try to get back down into the mud.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As soon as I started to try to scale down the hill, I slipped and flailed my arms. I managed to scratch my left arm down one of the barbs on the fence. I checked it out, fortunately it was just a scratch, but it was a good four to five inches in length, and immediately started to bleed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-27-800-7b9a6fadd.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Bloody arm&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-27-200-7b9a6fadd.jpg 200w, /assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-27-400-7b9a6fadd.jpg 400w, /assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-27-800-7b9a6fadd.jpg 800w, /assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-27-1500-7b9a6fadd.jpg 1500w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I walked my way through the muddy section, occasionally stopping to scrape some of the peanut butter off the bike, though I found the most effective way to do that was simply to pick the bike up and slam it back down a couple of times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-29-800-b7b13b70d.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Muddy Grizl&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-29-200-b7b13b70d.jpg 200w, /assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-29-400-b7b13b70d.jpg 400w, /assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-29-800-b7b13b70d.jpg 800w, /assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-29-1500-b7b13b70d.jpg 1500w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just after the muddy section was a water crossing that was probably 4 to 5 inches deep. I took this opportunity to wash the bike off, laying it down in the creek to try to help clear off a majority of the mud. I was just about to consider laying down in the water myself when I look back and see the 200 mile leaders racing through the mud right towards the group of us washing off in the creek.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-30-800-a2ee14990.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;200 Mile Leaders coming through&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-30-200-a2ee14990.jpg 200w, /assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-30-400-a2ee14990.jpg 400w, /assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-30-800-a2ee14990.jpg 800w, /assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-30-1500-a2ee14990.jpg 1500w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We all cleared out of the way as they made their way through, never stopping or getting off the bike through the mud section as far as I could tell. Four or five of the leaders came through then Peter Stetina came by, he stopped and washed his hands in the creek before continuing on with the race.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I recall, after the mud/water, the weather turned for the better. We were heading north, back into mostly dry and even sunny country. The course ended up back on some of the routes we had done in the pre-rides, though coming in from the opposite direction. At one point I came across a guy, about my size, who was standing on the side of the road working on his bike. I asked if he needed any help, to which he replied: “I’ve only got one gear”. I was slowly climbing up an incline, couldn’t really help him, so I kept going.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still heading up the climb a short time later, I heard a voice behind me. It was the one gear guy, he was on my wheel (or close enough). We had a brief conversation, I learned he was from Hays Kansas, I mentioned to him I was from St. Louis. Once we got onto flat ground I pulled away from him a bit, having multiple gears and all. He did end up passing me a later when I stopped to refill water from my bottle into my backpack, and cleaned my glasses. I recall seeing him on one of the final climbs near the finish, I cried out “You’ve got this Hays”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After stopping and talking with the family who was passing out water at the end of their driveway, I headed for the final ~12 miles of the ride. I was feeling pretty good, definitely getting tired, but not bad by any means. Normally on long rides between miles 85 and 95, I get pretty beat down and just want to be done, but on this ride I never got into that lull. It was definitely warming up, and I was ready to be done, but I was happy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-31-800-204de1c8c.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;More 200 Mile riders coming through&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-31-200-204de1c8c.jpg 200w, /assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-31-400-204de1c8c.jpg 400w, /assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-31-800-204de1c8c.jpg 800w, /assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-31-1600-204de1c8c.jpg 1600w, /assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-31-2000-204de1c8c.jpg 2000w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I came under the highway and started into the final hill I was ready to be done and ready to get the last hill out of the way. There was a KOM (King of the mountain) challenge on the hill, I knew I wasn’t going to be competing for that. I figured maybe I was in for a PR, but looking at the Strava data, it was my slowest climb up that hill (4th attempt), oh well. It was my highest heart rate effort of the day, closing in on 170 BPM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A quick jaunt through campus and you are back on Commercial street heading towards the finish. This is where I sprinted, best I could, towards the finish line. In 2019 I finished with my buddy Steve at the same time, for 2022 I was on my own, so I took off as hard as I could. I finished this segment 7 seconds faster than I had in 2019.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-33-800-b64a7d33e.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Unbound Gravel 100 Finisher Selfie&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-33-200-b64a7d33e.jpg 200w, /assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-33-400-b64a7d33e.jpg 400w, /assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-33-800-b64a7d33e.jpg 800w, /assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-33-1500-b64a7d33e.jpg 1500w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Post ride I grabbed my finisher’s bag and immediately got in line for the Muc-Off bike wash. The line was enormous, and I ended up waiting in it for well over an hour. Totally worth the clean bike, but it was pretty darn warm standing there. I saw Wags and Myckel in line, they finished about 45 minutes ahead of me, and were about 45 minutes ahead of me in the wash line as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-34-800-ece6e827e.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Muc-Off line&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-34-200-ece6e827e.jpg 200w, /assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-34-400-ece6e827e.jpg 400w, /assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-34-800-ece6e827e.jpg 800w, /assets/images_out/Content/2022/UnboundGravel/UnboundGravel2022-34-1500-ece6e827e.jpg 1500w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Matt brought me a nice cold Coke, at my request, while I waited in line. Writing this more than two weeks after Unbound, I question if I should have just requested he bring me a water. More on why later. He had done the 50 mile route and spent most of that 50 miles in the rain as well. Though he finished early enough that he had already been back to the hotel, showered and cleaned up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the bike was cleaned up, Wags and I grabbed a bite to eat from the food trucks. Finishers had a $10 credit for food and a free beer. I don’t even recall what I got? I think maybe a couple of hotdogs and another soda. We planned to grab a bigger meal after cleaning up at the hotel, but figured it would be good to get something in us before then. We made our way back to the Econolodge. I made sure to not actually lay down, knowing that if my head hit a pillow I would likely be out for too many hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For dinner we found a pizza place that was open and ordered a pie. It was easier to eat out on the west side of town, rather than trying to find something around the start/finish area with thousands of other people hanging around. After dinner it was an early night in. I brought along my camera equipment in case I was motivated to try to get out on the course and take photos as Wags and I had done last year, but there was no way that was happening after riding 104 miles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;sunday&quot;&gt;Sunday&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I thought I slept okay on Saturday night, but when I woke up, I looked at my resting heart rate data from my Whoop I noticed it was about 35 BPM higher than normal. I immediately knew what was wrong. I was in Afib. This would be the 4th time I have gone into Afib, and the third time it has happened after a bike ride. Unfortunately I didn’t have the brains to bring my blood thinner with me on the trip, which I am supposed to start taking if I am in atrial fibrillation, so I would be spending time in Afib without blood thinner until we got home to St. Louis later in the day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sunday morning was spent packing things up, albeit a little more slowly because when in Afib my heart rate pretty much runs really high, and I get winded easily. Myckel came and helped me load up my things into his truck and we hit the road back to St. Louis. The ride back to St. Louis was a little faster than our trip to Emporia, but it was Sunday morning, so we expected less traffic. We made a stop at a gas station to grab some breakfast before leaving Emporia then one more stop in Kansas City.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got home and unloaded the bike and the rest of my gear from Myckel’s truck and then planted myself on the couch (after taking my blood thinner). The bike didn’t get physically touched for almost a week, maybe more. Sitting in the garage in the exact same spot from when I got home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Monday morning I started calling my cardiologist. I knew I was in Afib, I wanted to get converted as quickly as possible so that I could get back on the bike. I spent all day trying to get an appointment setup, and finally into Tuesday they set something up for Friday. Riding my bike while in Afib is not advised, why? The one time I knowingly rode while in Afib, my heart rate was north of 220 BPM. At the time, I didn’t know I was in Afib, or that I even had Afib, but I know from looking at data from September 2020 that I was in it. So, while I might be able to get out and ride, riding at 220 BPM is definitely not something I need to be putting my heart through, the real problem is that it isn’t even beating normally when it beats that fast, so it is not efficient at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I ended up getting scheduled for a cardioversion on Friday, basically they put you under, send a probe down your esophagus to check for blood clots in the heart, if they don’t find any, they shock you back into a normal rhythm and I would be good to go. Unfortunately when they did the check for clots, they found one. As of right now, that means I am stuck in Afib (I have only self converted once, the first time in September 2020) until the clot dissolves, then they will convert me. That means another 5 to 6 weeks of no riding. No real activity or exercise. Another summer shot (last summer it was a combo of kidney stones and recovery from a cardiac cath).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;whats-next-in-2022-and-2023&quot;&gt;What’s next in 2022 and 2023?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, my plan was to keep riding all summer, keeping up the fitness I had going into Unbound so that I was ready for a couple more rides later this year. Here in St. Louis I ride Pedal The Cause every year, this year I’m planning on 150 miles over two days, towards the end of September. Wags and I are also signed up for Big Sugar Gravel in Bentonville in late October. I still hope to ride both of those, but I don’t know if I will have my fitness back or not by then, so we will see. I also need to see about getting a more permanent fix in place to try to prevent Afib from happening again, so that recovery will likely cut into training time as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I still have every intention of riding Unbound 2023. I am also hoping to do the 200 mile route for the first time, but we will see how training goes as I get back to health and start riding again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;thanks&quot;&gt;Thanks!&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A big thank you to LaDonna Wagner for providing SAG support for us boys out there playing around on our bikes. Your help was appreciated! Thanks to Matt for helping out as well with things around the hotel and post ride. Myckel, thanks for the ride and all the training time we managed to get in. Wags, also thanks for the help training all spring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To the event organizers, thank you for a great event! I had a blast, and look forward to doing at least one more (never say never after that).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;strava-ride&quot;&gt;Strava Ride&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;strava-embed-placeholder&quot; data-embed-type=&quot;activity&quot; data-embed-id=&quot;7255972732&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;script src=&quot;https://strava-embeds.com/embed.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2022 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.bicycletips.com/unbound-gravel-2022-ride-review</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bicycletips.com/unbound-gravel-2022-ride-review</guid>
        
        
        <category>Bike</category>
        
        <category>Gravel</category>
        
        <category>Unbound</category>
        
        <category>LifeTime</category>
        
        <category>Mud</category>
        
        <category>Ride Review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Ordering a bike from Canyon</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;For the past few years I’ve had dreams of buying a new bicycle. I went back and forth on what to get, where to get it, etc. Last year when Canyon announced the Grizl, I knew what I was going to buy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was a little concerned about purchasing a direct to consumer brand, but after seeing Canyon’s support of the gravel scene last year, and getting some of their swag at Unbound, I decided I felt safe enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ordered-a-canyon-grizl&quot;&gt;Ordered a Canyon Grizl&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was early/mid December when the bike finally came in stock in my size, so I placed the order. The first two rides were great, I was getting adjusted to the bike, the new shimano components (first time with Shimano components on a bike). On the third ride I noticed that the big ring up front seemed to have issues, like it was deformed/bent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Originally I thought it was just a bent tooth on the ring, I’ve experienced that before, but upon further inspection I wasn’t able to find a single tooth that was off. I was able to see when hand pedalling that the chain looked to shift over when it got to a couple of teeth, causing the bike to feel like it wanted to shift to the smaller ring up front. I was able to ride, but if the rear cassette was in any of the 4 or 5 larger rings, pedalling was inconsitant as it wanted to continually downshift up front.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;canyon-grizl-with-a-bent-front-chain-ring&quot;&gt;Canyon Grizl with a bent front chain ring&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Upon getting home from the ride I inspected further and was able to determine that the main chain ring looks to be misshapen. I ended up calling Canyon’s support number, was told it would likely be under warranty as I hadn’t had the bike for long, and that I needed to go online and submit a support request with photos of the problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2022/CanyonSupport/Canyon-2-800-9bfb9a93a.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2022/CanyonSupport/Canyon-2-200-9bfb9a93a.jpg 200w, /assets/images_out/Content/2022/CanyonSupport/Canyon-2-400-9bfb9a93a.jpg 400w, /assets/images_out/Content/2022/CanyonSupport/Canyon-2-800-9bfb9a93a.jpg 800w, /assets/images_out/Content/2022/CanyonSupport/Canyon-2-1166-9bfb9a93a.jpg 1166w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;canyon-customer-service&quot;&gt;Canyon Customer Service&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I did that, I went through the process of putting together photos trying to document the problem for them. I uploaded those photos and submitted the form on February 2nd, 2022. I immediately received an email with a case number, and in the email it said something to the effect of “if you don’t hear from us in 12-15 business days, please give us a call”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From a customer service perspective, this is NOT a great first introduction to direct to consumer customer service. Actually, my first experience was calling them and they told me to submit the form, so that was a pretty poor experience initially, followed by an even worse one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So here we are, February 17th, 2022. I went for another ride the other day, the chain ring definiteyl still has problems, making riding in the big ring a chore unless I’m really up to speed, causing me to run the small ring more than I typically would. I called Canyon’s customer support line today, and after waiting on hold for 15 minutes (their call back option wouldn’t take my button press for some reason) I finally spoke with a rep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;great-news&quot;&gt;Great News&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He asked me for my case number, read the case, looked at the photos, then informed me that I had a 2 year warranty on components.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;bad-news&quot;&gt;Bad News&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would have to go direct to Shimano for the warranty work for the chain ring. He provided a phone number I would need to call to open up a support request.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;15 days, two weeks, and I had to call Canyon, to be told that I would need to call Shimano to get support instead? Why couldn’t someone at Canyon have told me that two weeks ago?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So now I have a call back request in with Shimano. I called them 30 minutes ago. I’ll update this post as I find out how big of an ordeal it is trying to actually get support from a direct to consumer bicycle brand….&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;update-after-response-from-shimano&quot;&gt;Update after response from Shimano&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Got a call back from Shimano today. They provided me two options to get the warranty work done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) I can go to a local bike shop (assuming they need to sell shimano, but he didn’t say that directly) and they can do the inspection and file the warranty request with Shimano.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) I can fill out a form on Shimano’s website, then I can mail in the part and have them inspect it and determine if it is under warranty….&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I will lean towards option 1 and hope that Trailhead will help me out on this one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;direct-to--consumer-bicycles-is-it-good-for-you&quot;&gt;Direct To  Consumer Bicycles, is it good for you?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am not sure….&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2022 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.bicycletips.com/ordering-a-bike-from-canyon</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bicycletips.com/ordering-a-bike-from-canyon</guid>
        
        
        <category>Online</category>
        
        <category>Bike</category>
        
        <category>Gravel</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>2021 Year in Review and 2022 Coming Into View</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s January 10th already? I’ve only been on the bike once so far this year? Sounds like last year, but I can’t fall into that hole again…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So let’s talk a little bit about 2021 before we get into what’s coming in 2022.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So 2021 started off with plans of riding quite a few miles, in 2020 I rode 2100 miles, my highest total ever, so I had hopes of following that up, but ultimately 2021 didn’t play out that way. In late February I hadn’t put any real mileage in, and I started to feel off. It wasn’t until mid-March that I found out I had afib and my heart had been beating crazily for a month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a couple of months of dealing with that Unbound Gravel was upon us. Wagner and I went down and volunteered at the event, and got a little riding in, but didn’t actually join the race. In July I thought I was all healed up and then I got a kidney stone that stuck around for a little bit too long and took away another 2 months of riding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It wasn’t until late August that I started riding again, prepping for Pedal The Cause in late September and Big Sugar Gravel in late October. Overall for the year I barely got in 1k miles, a big drop from my ‘20 numbers, and hopefully only a blip compared to what I can get in this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;coming-in-2022&quot;&gt;Coming in 2022&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what’s coming in 2022? Well, I got myself a new ride, a Canyon Grizl, and it is awesome (see above). I put about 4200 miles on the Niner RLT over the past 5 years, figured it was time to upgrade. I haven’t yet decided what I will do with the RLT, I may hold on to it until at least March, but then sell it after that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My goal is to ride it at least 2,000 miles this year. I am signed up for The Mid South (100 miles in March) and Unbound Gravel (200 miles in June) so I really need to get my training started ASAP. I am going to have a hell of a time getting ready for those rides. My biggest struggle right now is finding time, or rather, making time. I need to quit staying up late and start getting up and getting on the trainer each morning…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am also planning on being back at Big Sugar Gravel in late October as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See you out on the trails.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 16:31:57 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.bicycletips.com/2021-year-in-review-2022-coming-into-view</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bicycletips.com/2021-year-in-review-2022-coming-into-view</guid>
        
        
        <category>Life</category>
        
        <category>2021</category>
        
        <category>2022</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to enter Unbound Gravel for 2022</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;So you think you want to try to take on Unbound Gravel, but you aren’t sure how to get in?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, to be honest, for 2022, your options are limited. There are two ways available to you right now, one is a “random” draw, and the other requires you to spend some serious moolah ($$$).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;gravel-camp&quot;&gt;Gravel Camp&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So the “guarantee your entry” way for 2022 is to sign up and attend the Gravel Camp(s). There are actually two options for the Camp, one that includes an entry for 2022 ($2200) and one that doesn’t include entry ($1000). The camp looks to be a 4 day adventure, be sure to check out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.unboundgravel.com/trainingcamp/&quot;&gt;Unbound Gravel Camp page&lt;/a&gt; for more info.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;lottery-entry&quot;&gt;Lottery Entry&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you aren’t interested in spending $2200 and doing the camp, the primary option people use to get into Unbound Gravel is the Lottery. The Lottery is open from January 5th through 18th, and is basically a lotto based system for getting an entry. The demand for entries for Unbound is greater than the number of entrants that the course and stops can support, so the lotto is how they control the registration, trying to make it a little more “fair” for people trying to get in, instead of a land rush type registration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;so-how-does-the-lottery-work&quot;&gt;So how does the lottery work?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basically you sign up for Unbound, you put all the information in as if you were registering, including Payment information. You won’t be charged however until the selection process occurs and you are chosen. If you aren’t picked in the Lotto, you will not be charged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In past years, you could also put in the name of a group that you want to ride with, and if all members of the group don’t make it in, you don’t get charged. This is useful if you want to ensure that you ride with friends, but means that one of you might actually get picked, and not be able to enter because the others in the group didn’t get picked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometime in early February they will choose who gets in, notify people, and charged the credit cards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;hotel-info&quot;&gt;Hotel Info&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you don’t have a hotel reservation already, you should get on that! Last I checked all the hotels are full, but once the lotto selection process occurs you may see some rooms open up. Also in early February the dorms should open up for reservation, that will likely be your best option if you don’t have a room yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;2023-entry&quot;&gt;2023 Entry&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don’t get in for 2022? Start planning for 2023 right now!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;volunteer-registration&quot;&gt;Volunteer Registration&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you or a loved one put in 10 volunteer hours you can bypass the lotto for 2023! If you don’t get in for 2022, definitely considering volunteering, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bicycletips.com/unbound-gravel-2021&quot;&gt;we did it in 2021 and had a hell of a time&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;closing-thoughts&quot;&gt;Closing Thoughts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good luck getting into the event! Hope you do, and if you don’t, you should considering going to Emporia that weekend anyway. There are organized rides before the event, you can get out and see some beautiful Kansas gravel, as well as experience the atmosphere around Unbound all the same!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2022 09:31:57 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.bicycletips.com/unbound-gravel-2022-registration-options</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bicycletips.com/unbound-gravel-2022-registration-options</guid>
        
        
        <category>Industry</category>
        
        <category>Gravel</category>
        
        <category>Unbound Gravel</category>
        
        <category>UnboundGravel</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>2022 Unbound Gravel Details - October 2021</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Details for Unbound Gravel 2022 are starting to be shared, I’ll try to make it a point to update this post with info as it becomes available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;event-date-and-location&quot;&gt;Event Date and Location&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;June 4th, 2022&lt;br /&gt;
Emporia, Kansas&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;registration-dates&quot;&gt;Registration Dates:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;deferral-or-volunteer-registration&quot;&gt;Deferral or Volunteer Registration&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you deferred in 20 or 21, Registration for 2022 is November 1st through November 30th, if you didn’t get that email, you’ve missed out!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;volunteer-registration&quot;&gt;Volunteer Registration&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you put in 10 volunteer hours, Registration for 2022 is in December (currently open), Treva did send out an email regarding usage of your volunteer hours in November, be sure to follow up on that!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;xl-350-lotto&quot;&gt;XL (350) Lotto&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unbound XL (350) lottery registration opened in early December (12/1-12/15), with announcements for who is picked before the end of the year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;2550100200-lotto&quot;&gt;25/50/100/200 Lotto&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lottery opens for registration on January 5th through January 18th. Announcements of if you got in the lotto in early February.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;life-time-club&quot;&gt;Life Time Club?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is something new I found on the website earlier today, likely too late for 2022, but perhaps they do something like this in 2023 as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Are you looking for a way to bypass the lottery for the 2022 or 2023 UNBOUND Gravel 200 or 100? Life Time members who have held a digital or in-club membership for at least 12 months (by 11/24/21) are eligible for early entry into the 200 or 100 mile event lotteries! In order to claim your preferred spot, you’ll need to register with your member number here (200) &amp;amp; here (100). The deadline to claim early entry for Life Time members is 1/4/22.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;going-south&quot;&gt;Going South&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the past two years (‘19 and ‘21) the Unbound route has gone to the North, for ‘22 it will be back to the South side of Emporia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;camps-are-back&quot;&gt;Camps are back&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They’re bringing the Spring Camps back, if you’ve got the time and funds, they are a great option for getting into the event, as well as getting training in. Registration opens soon!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More coming soon!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2021 11:31:57 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.bicycletips.com/unbound-gravel-2022-details</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bicycletips.com/unbound-gravel-2022-details</guid>
        
        
        <category>Industry</category>
        
        <category>Gravel</category>
        
        <category>Unbound Gravel</category>
        
        <category>UnboundGravel</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The 2021 Big and Little Sugar Gravel Ride Review</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Where to start on this one, it’s been an interesting year, not the best to be honest with a variety of things causing turmoil this year, I question how much I want to, or should share, so we’ll see what comes out in this post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;First and foremost, to the family that experienced tragedy this weekend, I am so sorry for your loss.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the rest of the weekend and ride review:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/Pre-BigSugarGravel-1-800-ad39141cf.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/Pre-BigSugarGravel-1-200-ad39141cf.jpg 200w, /assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/Pre-BigSugarGravel-1-400-ad39141cf.jpg 400w, /assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/Pre-BigSugarGravel-1-800-ad39141cf.jpg 800w, /assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/Pre-BigSugarGravel-1-1600-ad39141cf.jpg 1600w, /assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/Pre-BigSugarGravel-1-2000-ad39141cf.jpg 2000w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Monday morning I texted my buddy Wagner (Wags) to tell him I was out, I would not be going to Bentonville for Big Sugar Gravel. I had spent a few days fighting a sinus infection (I am vaccinated and tested negative for covid, though I was pretty sure before the test that it was a usual for me sinus thing). I had only been on my bike once in October, and was simply not ready to try to ride 100 miles in North West Arkansas and South West Missouri.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He let me stew on the message I sent him for a bit then suggested we could still do the 50 mile ride, the Little Sugar. By early afternoon that simple reply from him had flipped my mindset. We went out for a ride that afternoon and I was back in the game, though with an adjusted plan to ride 50 miles and still be back home in St. Louis Saturday night so I could go to my daughter’s gymnastics competition on Sunday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Friday morning we left St. Louis County arriving in Bentonville shortly after 1pm. We went to the 8th Street Market to figure out where Outerbike was, and to grab some lunch before registration was supposed to open. At registration we were easily able to switch our entries from Big Sugar to Little Sugar, and I got a thank you from Treva for letting them know about a bridge that was out on the 100 mile route.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/Pre-BigSugarGravel-2-800-85942cde1.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/Pre-BigSugarGravel-2-200-85942cde1.jpg 200w, /assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/Pre-BigSugarGravel-2-400-85942cde1.jpg 400w, /assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/Pre-BigSugarGravel-2-800-85942cde1.jpg 800w, /assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/Pre-BigSugarGravel-2-1600-85942cde1.jpg 1600w, /assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/Pre-BigSugarGravel-2-2000-85942cde1.jpg 2000w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Side Note:&lt;/em&gt; So this trip was not my first to Bentonville, I had actually been down there for the first time one week prior, meeting with a potential customer about a software project. On my drive back, last Friday the 15th, I decided to cruise along some of the gravel roads to see what we were in for. I wasn’t more than a mile off the highway when I came across a closed road, which I knew from looking at the Ride With GPS map was part of the route for Big Sugar. I drove down the closed road (don’t try this at home kids) and came across a crew working feverishly on a bridge. Before I got home on Friday I reached out to the LifeTime crew to ask if they knew about the bridge. They reached out on Monday and made sure to get out and check it out. In their defense, they had recently covered the course, but the bridge was damaged sometime after that scouting run.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/Pre-BigSugarGravel-4-800-4c7f898cb.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/Pre-BigSugarGravel-4-200-4c7f898cb.jpg 200w, /assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/Pre-BigSugarGravel-4-400-4c7f898cb.jpg 400w, /assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/Pre-BigSugarGravel-4-800-4c7f898cb.jpg 800w, /assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/Pre-BigSugarGravel-4-1600-4c7f898cb.jpg 1600w, /assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/Pre-BigSugarGravel-4-2000-4c7f898cb.jpg 2000w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From there we walked around Outerbike. I must admit, the Dirty Kanza/Unbound Gravel expo puts all other expos at events (besides my one trip to Sea Otter) to shame. I was kind of expecting Outerbike to compete, but it was much smaller. It was most definitely there for the MTB crew, and while the Gravel folks were accepted, the focus was on mountain bikes and demos, primarily. That being said, we picked up a number of swag items, including waffles from both Untapped and Honeystinger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wags found and geeked out with Jom from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gravelcyclist.com/race-reports/big-sugar-gravel-race-day-results-highlights-photos/&quot;&gt;GravelCyclist&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another local, Adelmann, from St. Louis showed up at the expo, so we organized a brief afternoon ride. He wanted to check out the beginning of the course, and I was really more interested in trying to see some of Bentonville and some of the trails. Wags and I ended up heading up towards the Slaughter Pen trail, which also happened to be the finish area for both Big and Little Sugar. We headed off into some single track on our gravel steeds and had a blast trying not to injure ourselves before Saturday. From there we headed out the road up and under the highway. We ended up only putting in about 10.5 miles, but it was enough to get our legs moving a bit and see some of Bentonville.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We stopped at the Phat Bike shop and eached picked up a t-shirt, while I picked up some new cleats for my shoes thinking that my old ones were wearing out (they weren’t, the new ones felt just as loose as the old ones).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/BigSugarGravel-1-800-68cc682f5.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/BigSugarGravel-1-200-68cc682f5.jpg 200w, /assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/BigSugarGravel-1-400-68cc682f5.jpg 400w, /assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/BigSugarGravel-1-800-68cc682f5.jpg 800w, /assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/BigSugarGravel-1-1600-68cc682f5.jpg 1600w, /assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/BigSugarGravel-1-2000-68cc682f5.jpg 2000w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Saturday morning we checked out of the hotel and headed up to find a parking spot. We ended up parking near the Square in Bentonville, which worked out fricken amazingly. There was a public bathroom right there, and we were 1 block from the finish line so that after the ride we could easily get the bikes back on the rack and we could change clothes. We had hoped to make it to the start line for the 7am Big Sugar start, to see Adelmann off, but ended up not making it down there until closer to 720am.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/BigSugarGravel-6-800-9bd6f696f.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The Momentary&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/BigSugarGravel-6-200-9bd6f696f.jpg 200w, /assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/BigSugarGravel-6-400-9bd6f696f.jpg 400w, /assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/BigSugarGravel-6-800-9bd6f696f.jpg 800w, /assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/BigSugarGravel-6-1600-9bd6f696f.jpg 1600w, /assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/BigSugarGravel-6-2000-9bd6f696f.jpg 2000w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The start was at the Momentary, which to be honest, is a cool looking building, but I have no idea what it actually is, the assumption is it is some sort of art space. (Runs off to google: The Momentary brings together contemporary visual, performing, and culinary arts into a welcoming, communal space in Northwest Arkansas.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/BigSugarGravel-7-800-fb008e8b6.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Little Sugar Start&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/BigSugarGravel-7-200-fb008e8b6.jpg 200w, /assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/BigSugarGravel-7-400-fb008e8b6.jpg 400w, /assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/BigSugarGravel-7-800-fb008e8b6.jpg 800w, /assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/BigSugarGravel-7-1600-fb008e8b6.jpg 1600w, /assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/BigSugarGravel-7-2000-fb008e8b6.jpg 2000w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Little Sugar ride went off right as scheduled at 8am with a lead out of town, we were back far enough that we couldn’t see the lead, but I believe it was local police doing the work on that. Before too long we were on Gravel and off into the beautiful country known as North West Arkansas (and southwest Missouri).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/BigSugarGravel-8-800-d666f5ced.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Little Sugar Gravel right before I dropped my gopro&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/BigSugarGravel-8-200-d666f5ced.jpg 200w, /assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/BigSugarGravel-8-400-d666f5ced.jpg 400w, /assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/BigSugarGravel-8-800-d666f5ced.jpg 800w, /assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/BigSugarGravel-8-1600-d666f5ced.jpg 1600w, /assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/BigSugarGravel-8-2000-d666f5ced.jpg 2000w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was a threat of rain, but that didn’t materialize. We did get a pretty scary looking storm at the rest stop, to the north of there it was dark and the wind started blowing pretty good for a bit, but for use on the Little Sugar course we remained dry with only a couple of seconds of spitting drops here or there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/BigSugarGravel-9-800-a965a29ab.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Whistling Springs Brewery&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/BigSugarGravel-9-200-a965a29ab.jpg 200w, /assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/BigSugarGravel-9-400-a965a29ab.jpg 400w, /assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/BigSugarGravel-9-800-a965a29ab.jpg 800w, /assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/BigSugarGravel-9-1600-a965a29ab.jpg 1600w, /assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/BigSugarGravel-9-2000-a965a29ab.jpg 2000w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The course itself was amazing, hilly but the hills were not TOO much. I did get off and walk on a couple of those hills however. I was able to hop back on and finish the climbs each time I did though. We made it to the the aid station at Whistling Springs Brewery without any noticeable trouble, though neither Wags nor I drank enough fluids in that first 2 hours on the ride. I chugged a bottle of Scratch that I had to try to force fluids in me and then grabbed some water at the brewery to fill both bottles back up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The aid station was stocked with Untapped Maple products, as well as other assorted items. I tried their “MapleAid” which I pictured as lemonade, had someone told me it was Tea I might have taken to it better, but expecting lemonade with maple flavor, I quickly poored out the sample that I had put in my bottle and just grabbed water instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wags went inside and grabbed himself a beer, as we all had “drink” tickets that we could use there. I grabbed some snacks and looked around a bit. With the storm appearing to be moving our way, I wasn’t too intersted in standing around, but I did get to see some of the beautiful property there, including a pig and dog wandering around saying hello to people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To get out of the brewery you climb up Whistling Springs road, I was chugging along the climb when I decided to stand up and put a little effort into it. This caused my rear tire to lose traction, my foot to immediately fall down to the bottom of my stroke, a quick unclip and I was hoofing it for a little while up the hill.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was shortly after leaving the brewery that we came across a maroon Toyota Tacoma, first coming at us, then after it turned around, it passed us going back the way from which it came. Not a minute or two later and we came across the same Tacoma stopped in the middle of the road. He stopped because a rider had fallen on the downhill, we could see a rider down in front of the truck.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I immedatiately jumped off my bike, called 911 and began trying to figure out where we actually were so that we could get help to us. For now, for the families sake, I will leave out any additional details, if anyone from the family would like more info, please feel free to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.chrishammond.com/contact&quot;&gt;contact me&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wags and I stayed on the scene for about 45 minutes, before heading back out on the road. On the way out the ambulance was coming in, we were glad to see that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/BigSugarGravel-10-800-cd00dd6fd.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Dennis Van Winden&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/BigSugarGravel-10-200-cd00dd6fd.jpg 200w, /assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/BigSugarGravel-10-400-cd00dd6fd.jpg 400w, /assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/BigSugarGravel-10-800-cd00dd6fd.jpg 800w, /assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/BigSugarGravel-10-1600-cd00dd6fd.jpg 1600w, /assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/BigSugarGravel-10-2000-cd00dd6fd.jpg 2000w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/BigSugarGravel-11-800-916078b93.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Luke Hall&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/BigSugarGravel-11-200-916078b93.jpg 200w, /assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/BigSugarGravel-11-400-916078b93.jpg 400w, /assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/BigSugarGravel-11-800-916078b93.jpg 800w, /assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/BigSugarGravel-11-1600-916078b93.jpg 1600w, /assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/BigSugarGravel-11-2000-916078b93.jpg 2000w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/BigSugarGravel-12-800-783d6a1a4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Colin Strickland&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/BigSugarGravel-12-200-783d6a1a4.jpg 200w, /assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/BigSugarGravel-12-400-783d6a1a4.jpg 400w, /assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/BigSugarGravel-12-800-783d6a1a4.jpg 800w, /assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/BigSugarGravel-12-1600-783d6a1a4.jpg 1600w, /assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/BigSugarGravel-12-2000-783d6a1a4.jpg 2000w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/BigSugarGravel-13-800-58d2a54ff.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Peter Stetina&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/BigSugarGravel-13-200-58d2a54ff.jpg 200w, /assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/BigSugarGravel-13-400-58d2a54ff.jpg 400w, /assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/BigSugarGravel-13-800-58d2a54ff.jpg 800w, /assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/BigSugarGravel-13-1600-58d2a54ff.jpg 1600w, /assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/BigSugarGravel-13-2000-58d2a54ff.jpg 2000w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rest of the ride kind of blurs together, at one point Wags and I were talking about how we hadn’t had any of the 100 mile competitors pass us since the accident (maybe 15 came through while we were there, a BIG thank you to those who slowed down, to those of you who didn’t, a couple of the top 5 men’s riders, show some decency next time). We began to wonder if the organizers had closed the course at the Brewery for weather or something.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It wasn’t until shortly after this conversation that we started to get riders coming by us from the 100, we found out later talking to a gentleman who finished in the 21st spot that they had actually shut the course down where the ambulance arrived on the scene.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/BigSugarGravel-14-800-b3dd75c66.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Arkansas Gravel&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/BigSugarGravel-14-200-b3dd75c66.jpg 200w, /assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/BigSugarGravel-14-400-b3dd75c66.jpg 400w, /assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/BigSugarGravel-14-800-b3dd75c66.jpg 800w, /assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/BigSugarGravel-14-1600-b3dd75c66.jpg 1600w, /assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/BigSugarGravel-14-2000-b3dd75c66.jpg 2000w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the trickle started as 100 mile riders were passing us, the flood came. Mostly we were passed by the top men, but a number of women passed by as well, including Amity Rockwell. A big shout out to all the riders who passed us slower guys with words of encouragement, it was much appreciated each and every time someone said something.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The finish required you to climb back up into the park area around the start of Slaughter Pen, you were on paved roads at this point, but was a slog for someone who wasn’t in shape and ready for a 50 mile ride. Wags waited for me and helped motivate me towards the finish as we crossed the line together, 5 hours and 21 minutes after we started, in 254th and 255th spot. I definitely had hoped to finish this ride in under 5 hours, hoping for closer to 4 hours, but with over 3k feet of elevation, and stopping for 45 minutes to assist, I am please that we still finished in 5:21.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Post ride you were given a mug/mason jar of Untapped Maple syrup and a big lollipop (lots of SUGAR). Wags and I headed back to the car, loaded up the bikes and changed into some street clothing to be comfortable before heading back to the finish area to grab food from a food truck with our meal tickets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We sat down and talked to a few fellow competitors, and I chatted with &lt;a href=&quot;https://instagram.com/bigtallwayne&quot;&gt;Big Tall Wayne&lt;/a&gt; again (Wags and I spoke to him Friday at the 8th street market, as well as at Unbound earlier this year). Adelmann wandered up to us after he finished and he downed a bottle of my Scratch Labs drink that I had made while at the truck. He was struggling with nutritional issues and said he was fortunate to have finished having vision concerns the last ~30 miles of his ride. He averaged 14.98mph on his ride, while Wagner and I averaged 9.94mph.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.strava.com/activities/6156217101&quot;&gt;Strava Ride&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got all sorts of comments on my jersey for the ride on Saturday. I wore my 2019 Cuban Gravel Crisis jersey. That WAS a real ride, and I gotta say, the best named gravel race in the history of gravel races. Unfortunately I hear rumors that the organizer of the ride no longer has rights to the name and is changing the name going forward, that’s unfortunate (looks like they let the domain expire even, that’s a shame)!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/BigSugarGravel-4-800-329af525e.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cuban Gravel Crisis Jersey&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/BigSugarGravel-4-200-329af525e.jpg 200w, /assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/BigSugarGravel-4-400-329af525e.jpg 400w, /assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/BigSugarGravel-4-800-329af525e.jpg 800w, /assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/BigSugarGravel-4-1600-329af525e.jpg 1600w, /assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/BigSugarGravel-4-2000-329af525e.jpg 2000w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve not made your way to North West Arkansas yet, definitely check it out. Bentonville, you are amazing. See you soon, next time my family is coming too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be sure to check out &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.BigSugarGravel.com&quot;&gt;BigSugarGravel.com&lt;/a&gt; for information on when registration will open for next year, you don’t want to miss this event!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A big thanks goes out to the event organizers, and to the folks at LifeTime for reaching out on Sunday as well. My thoughts again go out to the family.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2021 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.bicycletips.com/big-sugar-gravel-2021</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bicycletips.com/big-sugar-gravel-2021</guid>
        
        
        <category>Industry</category>
        
        <category>Gravel</category>
        
        <category>Big Sugar Gravel</category>
        
        <category>LifeTime</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
