<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>BicycleTips.com Tips, Tricks, Product and Ride Reviews</title>
    <description>A cycling website dedicated to bringing you the latest tips, tricks, product and ride reviews, primarily focused on gravel cycling.</description>
    <link>/</link>
    <atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2021 17:05:46 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2021 17:05:46 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.1.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>The 2021 Unbound Gravel Weekend Review</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Where to start on this one, it’s been an interesting year, not the best to be honest with a variety of things causing turmoil this year, I question how much I want to, or should share, so we’ll see what comes out in this post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First and foremost, to the family that experienced tragedy this weekend, I am so sorry for your loss. I rode up just as people were stopping to try to assist and immediately called 911. I was very optomistic as they were able to communicate with the folks who were tending to the individual. To learn via a phone call Sunday morning that the rider passed, I was crushed, but I can’t imagine the pain that his family is and will be going through.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the rest of the weekend and ride review:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/Pre-BigSugarGravel-1-800-e55fd82fa.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/Pre-BigSugarGravel-1-400-e55fd82fa.jpg 400w, /assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/Pre-BigSugarGravel-1-600-e55fd82fa.jpg 600w, /assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/Pre-BigSugarGravel-1-800-e55fd82fa.jpg 800w, /assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/Pre-BigSugarGravel-1-1000-e55fd82fa.jpg 1000w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Monday morning I texted my buddy Wagner (Wags) to tell him I was out, I would not be going to Bentonville for Big Sugar Gravel. I had spent a few days fighting a sinus infection (I am vaccinated and tested negative for covid, though I was pretty sure before the test that it was a usual for me sinus thing). I had only been on my bike once in October, and was simply not ready to try to ride 100 miles in North West Arkansas and South West Missouri.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He let me stew on the message I sent him for a bit then suggested we could still do the 50 mile ride, the Little Sugar. By early afternoon that simple reply from him had flipped my mindset. We went out for a ride that afternoon and I was back in the game, though with an adjusted plan to ride 50 miles and still be back home in St. Louis Saturday night so I could go to my daughter’s gymnastics competition on Sunday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Friday morning we left St. Louis County arriving in Bentonville shortly after 1pm. We went to the 8th Street Market to figure out where Outerbike was, and to grab some lunch before registration was supposed to open. At registration we were easily able to switch our entries from Big Sugar to Little Sugar, and I got a thank you from Treva for letting them know about a bridge that was out on the 100 mile route.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/Pre-BigSugarGravel-2-800-1e26f7272.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/Pre-BigSugarGravel-2-400-1e26f7272.jpg 400w, /assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/Pre-BigSugarGravel-2-600-1e26f7272.jpg 600w, /assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/Pre-BigSugarGravel-2-800-1e26f7272.jpg 800w, /assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/Pre-BigSugarGravel-2-1000-1e26f7272.jpg 1000w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Side Note:&lt;/em&gt; So this trip was not my first to Bentonville, I had actually been down there for the first time one week prior, meeting with a potential customer about a software project. On my drive back, last Friday the 15th, I decided to cruise along some of the gravel roads to see what we were in for. I wasn’t more than a mile off the highway when I came across a closed road, which I knew from looking at the Ride With GPS map was part of the route for Big Sugar. I drove down the closed road (don’t try this at home kids) and came across a crew working feverishly on a bridge. Before I got home on Friday I reached out to the LifeTime crew to ask if they knew about the bridge. They reached out on Monday and made sure to get out and check it out. In their defense, they had recently covered the course, but the bridge was damaged sometime after that scouting run.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/Pre-BigSugarGravel-4-800-665933af1.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/Pre-BigSugarGravel-4-400-665933af1.jpg 400w, /assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/Pre-BigSugarGravel-4-600-665933af1.jpg 600w, /assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/Pre-BigSugarGravel-4-800-665933af1.jpg 800w, /assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/Pre-BigSugarGravel-4-1000-665933af1.jpg 1000w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From there we walked around Outerbike. I must admit, the Dirty Kanza/Unbound Gravel expo puts all other expos at events to shame. I was kind of expecting outerbike to compete, but it simply wasn’t that type of thing. It was most definitely there for the MTB crew, and while the Gravel folks were accepted, the focus was on mountain bikes and demos, primarily. That being said, we picked up a number of swag items, including waffles from both Untapped and Honeystinger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wags found and geeked out with Jom from [GravelCyclist])https://www.gravelcyclist.com/race-reports/big-sugar-gravel-race-day-results-highlights-photos/).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another local, Adelmann, from St. Louis showed up at the expo, so we organized a brief afternoon ride. He wanted to check out the beginning of the course, and I was really more interested in trying to see some of Bentonville and some of the trails. Wags and I ended up heading up towards the Slaughter Pen trails, which also happened to be the finish area for both Big and Little Sugar. We headed off into some single track on our gravel steeds and had a blast trying not to injure ourselves before Saturday. From there we headed out the road up and under the highway. We ended up only putting in about 10.5 miles, but it was enough to get our legs moving a bit and see some of Bentonville.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We stopped at the Phat Bike shop and eached picked up a t-shirt, while I picked up some new cleats for my shoes thinking that my old ones were wearing out (they weren’t, the new ones felt just as loose as the old ones).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/BigSugarGravel-1-800-74c043c97.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/BigSugarGravel-1-400-74c043c97.jpg 400w, /assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/BigSugarGravel-1-600-74c043c97.jpg 600w, /assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/BigSugarGravel-1-800-74c043c97.jpg 800w, /assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/BigSugarGravel-1-1000-74c043c97.jpg 1000w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Saturday morning we checked out of the hotel and headed up to find a parking spot. We ended up parking near the Square in Bentonville, which worked out fricken amazingly. There was a public bathroom right there, and we were 1 block from the finish line so that after the ride we could easily get the bikes back on the rack and we could change clothes. We had hoped to make it to the start line for the 7am Big Sugar start, to see Adelmann off, but ended up not making it down there until closer to 720am.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/BigSugarGravel-6-800-475bdf5d8.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/BigSugarGravel-6-400-475bdf5d8.jpg 400w, /assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/BigSugarGravel-6-600-475bdf5d8.jpg 600w, /assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/BigSugarGravel-6-800-475bdf5d8.jpg 800w, /assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/BigSugarGravel-6-1000-475bdf5d8.jpg 1000w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The start was at the Momentary, which to be honest, is a cool looking building, but I have no idea what it actually is, the assumption is it is some sort of art space. (Runs off to google: The Momentary brings together contemporary visual, performing, and culinary arts into a welcoming, communal space in Northwest Arkansas.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/BigSugarGravel-7-800-72794096c.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/BigSugarGravel-7-400-72794096c.jpg 400w, /assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/BigSugarGravel-7-600-72794096c.jpg 600w, /assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/BigSugarGravel-7-800-72794096c.jpg 800w, /assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/BigSugarGravel-7-1000-72794096c.jpg 1000w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Little Sugar ride went off right as scheduled at 8am with a lead out of town, we were back far enough that we couldn’t see the lead, but I believe it was local police doing the work on that. Before too long we were on Gravel and off into the beautiful country known as North West Arkansas (and southwest Missouri).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/BigSugarGravel-8-800-e22330177.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/BigSugarGravel-8-400-e22330177.jpg 400w, /assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/BigSugarGravel-8-600-e22330177.jpg 600w, /assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/BigSugarGravel-8-800-e22330177.jpg 800w, /assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/BigSugarGravel-8-1000-e22330177.jpg 1000w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was a threat of rain, but that didn’t materialize. We did get a pretty scary looking storm at the rest stop, to the north of there it was dark and the wind started blowing pretty good for a bit, but for use on the Little Sugar course we remained dry with only a couple of seconds of spitting drops here or there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/BigSugarGravel-9-800-747895cc5.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/BigSugarGravel-9-400-747895cc5.jpg 400w, /assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/BigSugarGravel-9-600-747895cc5.jpg 600w, /assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/BigSugarGravel-9-800-747895cc5.jpg 800w, /assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/BigSugarGravel-9-1000-747895cc5.jpg 1000w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The course itself was amazing, hilly but the hills were not TOO much. I did get off and walk on a couple of those hills however. I was able to hop back on and finish the climbs each time I did though. We made it to the the aid station at Whistling Springs Brewery without any noticeable trouble, though neither Wags nor I drank enough fluids in that first 2 hours on the ride. I chugged a bottle of Scratch that I had to try to force fluids in me and then grabbed some water at the brewery to fill both bottles back up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The aid station was stocked with Untapped Maple products, as well as other assorted items. I tried their “MapleAid” which I pictured as lemonade, had someone told me it was Tea I might have taken to it better, but expecting lemonade with maple flavor, I quickly poored out the sample that I had put in my bottle and just grabbed water instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wags went inside and grabbed himself a beer, as we all had “drink” tickets that we could use there. I grabbed some snacks and looked around a bit. With the storm appearing to be moving our way, I wasn’t too intersted in standing around, but I did get to see some of the beautiful property there, including a pig and dog wandering around saying hello to people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To get out of the brewery you climb up Whistling Springs road, I was chugging along the climb when I decided to stand up and put a little effort into it. This caused my rear tire to lose traction, my foot to immediately fall dow the bottom of my stroke, a quick unclip and I was hoofing it for a little while up the hill.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was shortly after leaving the brewery that we came across a maroon Toyota Tacoma, first coming at us, then after it turned around, it passed us going back the way from which it came. Not a minute or two later and we came across the same Tacoma stopped in the middle of the road, we could see a rider down in front of the truck.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I immedatiately jumped off my bike, called 911 and began trying to figure out where we actually were so that we could get help to us. For now, for the families sake, I will leave out any additional details, if anyone from the family would like more info, please feel free to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.chrishammond.com/contact&quot;&gt;contact me&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wags and I stayed on the scene for about 45 minutes, before heading back out on the road. On the way out the ambulance was coming in, we were glad to see that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/BigSugarGravel-10-800-44eb6908e.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/BigSugarGravel-10-400-44eb6908e.jpg 400w, /assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/BigSugarGravel-10-600-44eb6908e.jpg 600w, /assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/BigSugarGravel-10-800-44eb6908e.jpg 800w, /assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/BigSugarGravel-10-1000-44eb6908e.jpg 1000w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/BigSugarGravel-11-800-1b73a5b32.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/BigSugarGravel-11-400-1b73a5b32.jpg 400w, /assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/BigSugarGravel-11-600-1b73a5b32.jpg 600w, /assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/BigSugarGravel-11-800-1b73a5b32.jpg 800w, /assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/BigSugarGravel-11-1000-1b73a5b32.jpg 1000w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/BigSugarGravel-12-800-1e02938f7.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/BigSugarGravel-12-400-1e02938f7.jpg 400w, /assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/BigSugarGravel-12-600-1e02938f7.jpg 600w, /assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/BigSugarGravel-12-800-1e02938f7.jpg 800w, /assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/BigSugarGravel-12-1000-1e02938f7.jpg 1000w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/BigSugarGravel-13-800-907e8889f.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/BigSugarGravel-13-400-907e8889f.jpg 400w, /assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/BigSugarGravel-13-600-907e8889f.jpg 600w, /assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/BigSugarGravel-13-800-907e8889f.jpg 800w, /assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/BigSugarGravel-13-1000-907e8889f.jpg 1000w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rest of the ride kind of blurs together, at one point Wags and I were talking about how we hadn’t had any of the 100 mile competitors pass us since the accident (maybe 15 came through while we were there, a BIG thank you to those who slowed down, to those of you who didn’t, a couple of the top 3 men’s riders, show some decency next time). We began to wonder if the organizers had closed the course at the Brewery for weather or something.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It wasn’t until shortly after this conversation that we started to get riders coming by us from the 100, we found out later talking to a gentleman who finished in the 20th spot that they had actually shut the course down where the ambulance arrived on the scene.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/BigSugarGravel-14-800-e5cc08e94.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/BigSugarGravel-14-400-e5cc08e94.jpg 400w, /assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/BigSugarGravel-14-600-e5cc08e94.jpg 600w, /assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/BigSugarGravel-14-800-e5cc08e94.jpg 800w, /assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/BigSugarGravel-14-1000-e5cc08e94.jpg 1000w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the trickle started as 100 mile riders were passing us, the flood came. Mostly we were passed by the top men, but a number of women passed by as well, including Amity Rockwell. A big shout out to all the riders who passed us slower guys with words of encouragement, it was much appreciated each and every time someone said something.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The finish required you to climb back up into the park area around the start of Slaughter Pen, you were on paved roads at this point, but was a slog for someone who wasn’t in shape and ready for a 50 mile ride. Wags waited for me and helped motivate me towards the finish as we crossed the line together, 5 hours and 21 minutes after we started, in 254th and 255th spot. I definitely had hoped to finish this ride in under 5 hours, hoping for closer to 4 hours, but with over 3k feet of elevation, and stopping for 45 minutes to assist, I am please that we still finished in 5:21.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Post ride you were given a mug/mason jar of Untapped Maple syrup and a bike ole lollipop (lots of SUGAR). Wags and I headed back to the car, loaded up the bikes and changed into some street clothign to be comfortable before heading back to the finish area to grab food from a food truck with our meal tickets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We sat down and talked to a few fellow competitors, and I chatted with &lt;a href=&quot;https://instagram.com/bigtallwayne&quot;&gt;Big Tall Wayne&lt;/a&gt; again (Wags and I spoke to him Friday at the 8th street market). Adelmann wandered up to us after he finished and he downed a bottle of my Scratch Labs drink that I had made while at the truck. He was struggling with nutritional issues and said he was fortunate to have finished having vision concerns the last ~30 miles of his ride. He averaged 14.98mph on his ride, while Wagner and I averaged 9.94mph.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.strava.com/activities/6156217101&quot;&gt;Strava Ride&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got all sorts of comments on my jersey for the ride on Saturday. I wore my 2019 Cuban Gravel Crisis jersey. That WAS a real ride, and I gotta say, the best named gravel race in the history of gravel races. Unfortunately I hear rumors that the organizer of the ride no longer has rights to the name and is changing the name going forward, that’s unfortunate (looks like they let the domain expire even, that’s a shame)!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/BigSugarGravel-4-800-e742d4a63.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/BigSugarGravel-4-400-e742d4a63.jpg 400w, /assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/BigSugarGravel-4-600-e742d4a63.jpg 600w, /assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/BigSugarGravel-4-800-e742d4a63.jpg 800w, /assets/images_out/Content/2021/BigSugarGravel/BigSugarGravel-4-1000-e742d4a63.jpg 1000w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve not made your way to North West Arkansas yet, definitely check it out. Bentonville, you are amazing. See you soon, next time my family is coming too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be sure to check out &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.BigSugarGravel.com&quot;&gt;BigSugarGravel.com&lt;/a&gt; for information on when registration will open for next year, you don’t want to miss this event!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A big thanks goes out to the event organizers, and to the folks at LifeTime for reaching out on Sunday as well. My thoughts again go out to the family.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2021 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/big-sugar-gravel-2021</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/big-sugar-gravel-2021</guid>
        
        
        <category>Industry</category>
        
        <category>Gravel</category>
        
        <category>Big Sugar Gravel</category>
        
        <category>LifeTime</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The 2021 Unbound Gravel Weekend Review</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;While we were at Unbound Gravel we took almost 2k photos, not all of those lives up to our standards, but here is a link to each of the four galleries of shots we took, these will open up in a new tab over on Chris' Photography site. Please stick around and read our writeup from the event too!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Unbound Gravel Photos from Rainbow Marks Photography&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;row&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;card&quot; style=&quot;width: 18rem;&quot;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://rainbowmarks.com/Events/2021/06/unbound-gravel-west-of-americus&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://rainbowmarks.com/generated/img/posts/UnboundGravel/AlmaCheckPoint/AlmaCheckPoint-49-400-596335fdd.jpg&quot; class=&quot;card-img-top&quot; alt=&quot;Alma Checkpoint&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;card-body&quot;&gt;
      &lt;h5 class=&quot;card-title&quot;&gt;Alma Checkpoint&lt;/h5&gt;
      &lt;p class=&quot;card-text&quot;&gt;Shots from the Alma Checkpoint of the 200 mile route.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;a href=&quot;https://rainbowmarks.com/Events/2021/06/unbound-gravel-west-of-americus&quot; class=&quot;btn btn-primary&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;View Photos&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;card&quot; style=&quot;width: 18rem;&quot;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://rainbowmarks.com/Events/2021/06/unbound-gravel-west-of-americus&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://rainbowmarks.com/generated/img/posts/UnboundGravel/WestOfAmericus/WestOfAmericus-274-400-9a7664468.jpg&quot; class=&quot;card-img-top&quot; alt=&quot;Afternoon West of Americus&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;card-body&quot;&gt;
      &lt;h5 class=&quot;card-title&quot;&gt;Afternoon West of Americus&lt;/h5&gt;
      &lt;p class=&quot;card-text&quot;&gt;Between 3 and 4pm west of Americus, KS. Top 5 men from the 200 mile race plus a number of 100 mile riders.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;a href=&quot;https://rainbowmarks.com/Events/2021/06/unbound-gravel-west-of-americus&quot; class=&quot;btn btn-primary&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;View Photos&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;card&quot; style=&quot;width: 18rem;&quot;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://rainbowmarks.com/Events/2021/06/unbound-gravel-finish-line&quot;  target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://rainbowmarks.com/generated/img/posts/UnboundGravel/FinishLine/FinishLine-11-400-09a9be44f.jpg&quot; class=&quot;card-img-top&quot; alt=&quot;Finish Line (only a handful)&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;card-body&quot;&gt;
      &lt;h5 class=&quot;card-title&quot;&gt;Finish Line (only a handful)&lt;/h5&gt;
      &lt;p class=&quot;card-text&quot;&gt;A handful of shots from the finish line around 730pm.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;a href=&quot;https://rainbowmarks.com/Events/2021/06/unbound-gravel-finish-line&quot; class=&quot;btn btn-primary&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;View Photos&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;div class=&quot;card&quot; style=&quot;width: 18rem;&quot;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://rainbowmarks.com/Events/2021/06/unbound-gravel-night-shots&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://rainbowmarks.com/generated/img/posts/UnboundGravel/Nightshots/Nightshots-226-400-5d6ddb371.jpg&quot; class=&quot;card-img-top&quot; alt=&quot;Night Shots with about 20.5 miles remaining&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;card-body&quot;&gt;
      &lt;h5 class=&quot;card-title&quot;&gt;Night Shots with about 20.5 miles remaining&lt;/h5&gt;
      &lt;p class=&quot;card-text&quot;&gt;Sunset and dark shots of 200 mile riders with about 20.5 miles remaining on the route.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;a href=&quot;https://rainbowmarks.com/Events/2021/06/unbound-gravel-night-shots&quot; class=&quot;btn btn-primary&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;View Photos&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Review&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two Years ago I was in Emporia Kansas for the Dirty Kanza, riding 100 miles on gravel for the first time. It wasn't easy, I was slow, and spent most of the second half helping a buddy get through the ride while he was having some serious cramping. Overall we had a great weekend of riding and I made it a point to try to get back. I made that easier by attending the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bicycletips.com/2019-lunar-kanza-ride-review&quot;&gt;Lunar Kanza in July 2019 and obtaining a lotto bypass for 2020&lt;/a&gt;. As for everyone, 2020 didn't go as planned, I did get a lot of riding in, but I wasn't going to be ready for 200 miles if it had happened. Earlier this year I failed to start training/riding early, and ultimately spent about 2 months dealing with some heart issues where I wasn't on the bike at all. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because of all that, I had to defer my 2021 entry to 2022 for the Unbound Gravel event. I already had a hotel room and wanted to be in Emporia to experience the fun that comes with the event so myself and Wagner (Wags) headed on down anyways. We signed up to volunteer to work 10 hours so that we could ensure that Wags got in for 2022, and hopefully bring my brother or another friend along with us too based on my hours worked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2021/Unbound2021/Tahoe-800-26986e255.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;The Tweeting Tahoe Loaded Up&quot;&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2021/Unbound2021/Tahoe-400-26986e255.jpg 400w, /assets/images_out/Content/2021/Unbound2021/Tahoe-600-26986e255.jpg 600w, /assets/images_out/Content/2021/Unbound2021/Tahoe-800-26986e255.jpg 800w, /assets/images_out/Content/2021/Unbound2021/Tahoe-1000-26986e255.jpg 1000w&quot;&gt;
 

&lt;p&gt;We headed down on Thursday afternoon so that we could make a quick pass through the expo before it closed down that evening. The drive down from St. Louis was uneventful, unlike our drive down in 2019, we did see a couple of gravel bikes on racks on the way west. We arrived in Emporia shortly before 6pm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once there we walked around the All Things Gravel Expo, checked out Gravel City and their shop and headed over to our hotel to get checked in to the Econo Lodge. While the Econo Lodge was cheap, and overall it was comfortable, we were severly disappointed the first night when we walked up to the second floor and it reeked of cigarette smoke and beer. Ultimately the hotel worked out okay, I think the guys who were smoking/drinking were workers and Friday they headed back to their homes for the weekend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2021/Unbound2021/GravelEnds-800-f4af66f67.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;Friday Morning Ride&quot;&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2021/Unbound2021/GravelEnds-400-f4af66f67.jpg 400w, /assets/images_out/Content/2021/Unbound2021/GravelEnds-600-f4af66f67.jpg 600w, /assets/images_out/Content/2021/Unbound2021/GravelEnds-800-f4af66f67.jpg 800w, /assets/images_out/Content/2021/Unbound2021/GravelEnds-1000-f4af66f67.jpg 1000w&quot;&gt;
 

&lt;p&gt;Friday morning we got up and headed back in to town, parking in the same lot from the night before. We took off on our bikes and rode the 25 mile route before we needed to be at our first volunteer assignment. The riding was great, it was definitely starting to warm up and we were thankful that we got the ride in early and that we would be &quot;working&quot; inside at the packet pickup area. We made another pass through the expo before work where Wags ran into a childhood friend he raced BMX with in St. Louis. In the Expo I saw Frankie Andreu and got introduced to Tinker Jaurez, BMX legend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2021/Unbound2021/FrankieAndTinker-800-8ce341d0c.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;Frankie Andreu and Tinker Juarez&quot;&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2021/Unbound2021/FrankieAndTinker-400-8ce341d0c.jpg 400w, /assets/images_out/Content/2021/Unbound2021/FrankieAndTinker-600-8ce341d0c.jpg 600w, /assets/images_out/Content/2021/Unbound2021/FrankieAndTinker-800-8ce341d0c.jpg 800w, /assets/images_out/Content/2021/Unbound2021/FrankieAndTinker-1000-8ce341d0c.jpg 1000w&quot;&gt;
 

&lt;p&gt;We checked in with the volunteer coordinator and I spent the next 3.5 hours handing out T-Shirts to mostly 200 mile riders, but a few 100 riders as well. I got to hand a shirt to Ashton Lamby and Amity Rockwell among many others. Wags was passing out bags during that time and got to give a bag to both of those riders as well. He also talked to Jeremiah about the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jgl-3INWMgA&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Impossible Route&lt;/a&gt;. After working we made another pass through the Expo to grab any additional swag we had missed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a Vegan (almost 1.5 year now) I was worried about what I might find to food. At Gravel City I saw a gentleman behind the counter with a tofu bowl, so I asked where he got it and he pointed me to Chi Em Eats, a vietnamese place just down the street. I ordered a bowl from them and picked it up, Wags grabbed another burrito from the food truck at the expo and we sat and talked to a few locals over dinner. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had a great experience with every local we ran into in Emporia, they all appear to love the event and all the people it brings into town. We even ran into a guy an hour out of town when filling up with gas that was happy we were heading down. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Saturday morning we got up early and headed north to Alma where we would be spending the morning working the first checkpoint on the 200 mile route. Most of my time there was spent directing/holding traffic at the one flashing light in town, stopping traffic when any riders were coming through, and letting the traffic through at appropriate times. Almost every one of those we had to stop was pleasant and supportive, though I do recall one truck that wasn't too happy about having to take 30 seconds out of his day to sit there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While in Alma I got to spend some time walking around with my camera, getting some photos of the leaders of the 200 coming through, and then various other riders coming through, getting service, and heading out of town, you can see those &lt;a href=&quot;https://rainbowmarks.com/Events/2021/06/unbound-gravel-alma&quot;&gt;linked here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After our volunteer time in Alma, Wags and I were starving, so we grabbed lunch at the local mexican joint before heading back towards Emporia. We were exhausted, and initially planned to head back to the hotel and rest of before heading back into the fun of the finish area. On the way down we checked the results and noticed that the leaders from the 200 race were just getting through Council Grove, this caused us to divert west over to Americus so that we could sit on the side of the road and get some photos and cheer people along.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2021/Unbound2021/BoswellandTenDam-800-1b29dd631.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;Ian Boswell and Laurens ten Dam at Unbound Gravel 200&quot;&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2021/Unbound2021/BoswellandTenDam-400-1b29dd631.jpg 400w, /assets/images_out/Content/2021/Unbound2021/BoswellandTenDam-600-1b29dd631.jpg 600w, /assets/images_out/Content/2021/Unbound2021/BoswellandTenDam-800-1b29dd631.jpg 800w, /assets/images_out/Content/2021/Unbound2021/BoswellandTenDam-1000-1b29dd631.jpg 1000w&quot;&gt;
 
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2021/Unbound2021/TedKing-800-b4221fd82.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;Ted King Unbound Gravel 200&quot;&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2021/Unbound2021/TedKing-400-b4221fd82.jpg 400w, /assets/images_out/Content/2021/Unbound2021/TedKing-600-b4221fd82.jpg 600w, /assets/images_out/Content/2021/Unbound2021/TedKing-800-b4221fd82.jpg 800w, /assets/images_out/Content/2021/Unbound2021/TedKing-1000-b4221fd82.jpg 1000w&quot;&gt;
 

&lt;p&gt;We got to see the top 5 200 mile riders pass by, and a number of 100 mile riders before we headed back into town. Later that evening we went back out to the finish area, I really wanted to try to get a selfie with Alison Tetrick to go with the one I got with her in 2019.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;instagram-media&quot; data-instgrm-captioned data-instgrm-permalink=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/CPwlsysD49H/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=loading&quot; data-instgrm-version=&quot;13&quot; style=&quot; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:540px; min-width:326px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&quot;&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding:16px;&quot;&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/CPwlsysD49H/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=loading&quot; style=&quot; background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding: 19% 0;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;display:block; height:50px; margin:0 auto 12px; width:50px;&quot;&gt;&lt;svg width=&quot;50px&quot; height=&quot;50px&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 60 60&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; xmlns=&quot;https://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot; xmlns:xlink=&quot;https://www.w3.org/1999/xlink&quot;&gt;&lt;g stroke=&quot;none&quot; stroke-width=&quot;1&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot;&gt;&lt;g transform=&quot;translate(-511.000000, -20.000000)&quot; fill=&quot;#000000&quot;&gt;&lt;g&gt;&lt;path d=&quot;M556.869,30.41 C554.814,30.41 553.148,32.076 553.148,34.131 C553.148,36.186 554.814,37.852 556.869,37.852 C558.924,37.852 560.59,36.186 560.59,34.131 C560.59,32.076 558.924,30.41 556.869,30.41 M541,60.657 C535.114,60.657 530.342,55.887 530.342,50 C530.342,44.114 535.114,39.342 541,39.342 C546.887,39.342 551.658,44.114 551.658,50 C551.658,55.887 546.887,60.657 541,60.657 M541,33.886 C532.1,33.886 524.886,41.1 524.886,50 C524.886,58.899 532.1,66.113 541,66.113 C549.9,66.113 557.115,58.899 557.115,50 C557.115,41.1 549.9,33.886 541,33.886 M565.378,62.101 C565.244,65.022 564.756,66.606 564.346,67.663 C563.803,69.06 563.154,70.057 562.106,71.106 C561.058,72.155 560.06,72.803 558.662,73.347 C557.607,73.757 556.021,74.244 553.102,74.378 C549.944,74.521 548.997,74.552 541,74.552 C533.003,74.552 532.056,74.521 528.898,74.378 C525.979,74.244 524.393,73.757 523.338,73.347 C521.94,72.803 520.942,72.155 519.894,71.106 C518.846,70.057 518.197,69.06 517.654,67.663 C517.244,66.606 516.755,65.022 516.623,62.101 C516.479,58.943 516.448,57.996 516.448,50 C516.448,42.003 516.479,41.056 516.623,37.899 C516.755,34.978 517.244,33.391 517.654,32.338 C518.197,30.938 518.846,29.942 519.894,28.894 C520.942,27.846 521.94,27.196 523.338,26.654 C524.393,26.244 525.979,25.756 528.898,25.623 C532.057,25.479 533.004,25.448 541,25.448 C548.997,25.448 549.943,25.479 553.102,25.623 C556.021,25.756 557.607,26.244 558.662,26.654 C560.06,27.196 561.058,27.846 562.106,28.894 C563.154,29.942 563.803,30.938 564.346,32.338 C564.756,33.391 565.244,34.978 565.378,37.899 C565.522,41.056 565.552,42.003 565.552,50 C565.552,57.996 565.522,58.943 565.378,62.101 M570.82,37.631 C570.674,34.438 570.167,32.258 569.425,30.349 C568.659,28.377 567.633,26.702 565.965,25.035 C564.297,23.368 562.623,22.342 560.652,21.575 C558.743,20.834 556.562,20.326 553.369,20.18 C550.169,20.033 549.148,20 541,20 C532.853,20 531.831,20.033 528.631,20.18 C525.438,20.326 523.257,20.834 521.349,21.575 C519.376,22.342 517.703,23.368 516.035,25.035 C514.368,26.702 513.342,28.377 512.574,30.349 C511.834,32.258 511.326,34.438 511.181,37.631 C511.035,40.831 511,41.851 511,50 C511,58.147 511.035,59.17 511.181,62.369 C511.326,65.562 511.834,67.743 512.574,69.651 C513.342,71.625 514.368,73.296 516.035,74.965 C517.703,76.634 519.376,77.658 521.349,78.425 C523.257,79.167 525.438,79.673 528.631,79.82 C531.831,79.965 532.853,80.001 541,80.001 C549.148,80.001 550.169,79.965 553.369,79.82 C556.562,79.673 558.743,79.167 560.652,78.425 C562.623,77.658 564.297,76.634 565.965,74.965 C567.633,73.296 568.659,71.625 569.425,69.651 C570.167,67.743 570.674,65.562 570.82,62.369 C570.966,59.17 571,58.147 571,50 C571,41.851 570.966,40.831 570.82,37.631&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding-top: 8px;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; color:#3897f0; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:550; line-height:18px;&quot;&gt; View this post on Instagram&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding: 12.5% 0;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #F4F4F4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;margin-left: 8px;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg)&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;margin-left: auto;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background-color: #F4F4F4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center; margin-bottom: 24px;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 224px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 144px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/CPwlsysD49H/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=loading&quot; style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;A post shared by Christopher Hammond (@thechristoc)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async src=&quot;//www.instagram.com/embed.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the finish line I wanted to see if we could get somewhere on course to try to get a good sunset shot with riders out on the course, and then some night sky photos out there as well, ideally with a rider or two. We headed west towards Lake Kahola, I remembered that area from my prior to rides there in Emporia, and I knew that some of the gravel roads out there might provide me a good place to shoot from.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2021/Unbound2021/Stars-800-8c795892f.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;The Night Sky over Unbound Gravel&quot;&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2021/Unbound2021/Stars-400-8c795892f.jpg 400w, /assets/images_out/Content/2021/Unbound2021/Stars-600-8c795892f.jpg 600w, /assets/images_out/Content/2021/Unbound2021/Stars-800-8c795892f.jpg 800w, /assets/images_out/Content/2021/Unbound2021/Stars-1000-8c795892f.jpg 1000w&quot;&gt;
 

&lt;p&gt;I ended up not getting the great Night Sky shots that I wanted, but we did sit out on the course on a climb just before the 20 miles left point, where we cheered on riders until just after midnight. I took photos until I just couldn't get any decent ones in the dark, with a couple of night sky shots turning out. It was a somewhat cloudy night and more clouds definitely moved in the longer we sat there. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The riders that came by mostly appeared to be appreciative of our cheering at them. We found that they either were thankful, or zombie like (understandable after 180 miles). I never thought I would have so much fun at an event not riding, but Wags and I had a blast all weekend. Being there, cheering people on, encouraging them to keep going, taking photos, helping out, it was great.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you don't get into the Unbound Gravel event next year through the lottery, you absolutely should look at volunteering. This year the deal was that you had to work at least 10 hours to get a bypass for 2022, I would assume they will do something similar for 2023, you should consider this! It's a great intro to the Emporia atmosphere and gives you time to get out there on the course and get some rides in for you as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to everyone within the LifeTime and Unbound organizations for a great weekend!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See you next year, I'm planning on 200 miles, training started last month.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2021 11:31:57 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/unbound-gravel-2021</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/unbound-gravel-2021</guid>
        
        
        <category>Industry</category>
        
        <category>Gravel</category>
        
        <category>Unbound Gravel</category>
        
        <category>UnboundGravel</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Mid South 2021 the incredibly socially distanced</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;So what’d you do this past weekend? Did you ride The Mid South? They shifted things up this year, went to a virtual “incredibly socially distant” version of the event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Everyone is getting 50% of their reg fee refunded starting today. It might take a few days to deposit so be patient!&lt;br /&gt;
We are physically mailing out your Mid South swag bag with t-shirt, water bottle, and more to your front door! It will be there before event weekend.&lt;br /&gt;
If you’re signed up for the race YOU’RE IN. All you will need to do moving forward is join the Ride With GPS challenge page and upload your ride/run. You must ride/run and record your activity on one of the dates between March 12-14. &lt;br /&gt;
Our partner bike shops are creating 50k, 50mi, 100mi routes in their areas for many of you to be able to ride/run. Sponsors will be sending swag to each of these shops for you to win on a first come, first serve basis after you’ve completed their specific Mid South partner route.&lt;br /&gt;
If you don’t live in one of the partner shop areas you can upload your own course/activity from your backyard to the Ride With GPS challenge page. You will not be able to win swag from the bike shops BUT you will be entered to win from a list of GRAND prizes. We will be drawing names from the complete list of all participants that uploaded their ride/run from the event weekend on Monday March 15th. Prizes include a Salsa Stormchaser, 5 free entries to Mid South 2022, free bike shipping to and from Mid South 2022 AND a free entry to thtruee race courtesy of Bike Flights, and our biggest prize of all the “Eternal Entry.” It lasts forever. More details soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had intentions of training and riding locally here in St. Louis for this, but 2021 got in the way. First, I had motivation issues starting out the year. I think I’ve been on the trainer once in 2021. Then in February I apparently started experiencing Atrial Fibrillation. My heart rate has been f’d up since the morning of 2/19. I went to bed late, around 1am, and according to my Garmin Fenix my heart rate has been f’d up ever since.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve got an appointment for a procedure tomorrow that will hopefully reset my heart rhythm that will hopefully get me back to normal and get me out on the bike again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Mid South 2022 will be March 11th and 12th, 2022. Registration for that will open in October.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They had a Facebook Live stream today after the weekend and awarded some prizes. The coolest being the Eternal Entry. Basically a free liftime entry to The Mid South. There’s a catch though. It has to be used every year or it goes away. It CAN be passed on though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’ll be cool to see that get tracked, will the same person use it every year? Will someone different get to use it every year?&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 10:31:57 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/the-mid-south-2021</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/the-mid-south-2021</guid>
        
        
        <category>Industry</category>
        
        <category>Gravel</category>
        
        <category>The Mid South</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Unbound Gravel 2021 Deferral Registration</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Today is November 16, 2020, why is that an important date? If you registered for the Dirty Kanza in 2020 and chose a deferral option, today is the day that deferral users have the ability to sign up for the 2021 race.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out your email for details on registration for Unbound Gravel 2021.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One side note: Personally we received an email saying that we had deferred to 2022 and wouldn’t be receiving a registration link today. Hopefully that was just an error and they’ll get it corrected today. I know personally I am planning on riding 2021.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have you started your training yet?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-Chris&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;update-11162020&quot;&gt;Update: 11/16/2020&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The marketing director from LifeTime posted in a private Facebook group acknowledging that some deferrals were errantly attributed to 2022, and they will be emailing those impacted with registration information for 2021.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2020 09:31:57 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/unbound-gravel-deferral-registration</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/unbound-gravel-deferral-registration</guid>
        
        
        <category>Industry</category>
        
        <category>Gravel</category>
        
        <category>Dirty Kanza</category>
        
        <category>Unbound Gravel</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Dirty Kanza is Unbound</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Hot off the presses, Dirty Kanza is no more, long may those who are unchained live Unbound!&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;FOR IMMEDIATE RELEASE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Media Contact: Jordan Titus | jtitus@lt.life | 218.780.6161&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Life Time Reveals New Brand for Emporia Gravel&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Event: UNBOUND Gravel&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Internationally renowned for the remote, rugged and unforgiving journey it provides riders, the former DK gravel event begins a new chapter in 2021&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EMPORIA, Kans., October 30, 2020&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;mdash;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a data-saferedirecturl=&quot;https://www.google.com/url?q=http://lifetime.life/&amp;amp;source=gmail&amp;amp;ust=1604085665088000&amp;amp;usg=AFQjCNHEHYdnDn0I3_U2YEu_BN8ewams7g&quot; href=&quot;http://lifetime.life/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Life Time&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;is&amp;nbsp;pleased to announce the new name for its wildly popular Emporia, Kans.-based gravel event.&amp;nbsp;&lt;em&gt;UNBOUND Gravel&lt;/em&gt;&amp;nbsp;will carry on the 15-year history, legacy and energy of the original event with a new identity. Garmin will remain on as title sponsor of the event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Our team agreed that we wanted a name, logo and colors that embody the Flint Hills of Kansas. This region, and the hilly, sharp gravel roads that accompany it, are what help make this event what it has become: known widely today as the World&amp;rsquo;s Premier Gravel Event. We know the life impact this event has on people and we wanted a strong brand that participants felt proud of, that we could tell stories around, and that tied literally and figuratively to the area,&amp;quot; said Michelle Duffy, Director of Off-Road Events Marketing at Life Time. &amp;quot;The word UNBOUND most literally means to be free. It represents the free-range cattle, wild mustangs and native bison in the prairie of the Flint Hills, who move freely and live wildly. It&amp;rsquo;s synonymous with our participants who experience a sense of freedom on the gravel roads outside of Emporia, and in those moments feel &amp;ldquo;unbound&amp;rdquo; from anything else. Just the rider and the tire-shredding, sun-baking, breathtaking Flint Hills gravel.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In support of the new name and branding process, Life Time established a task force composed of Emporia business and tourism leaders, representatives of the cycling media, members of the cycling community&amp;mdash;including a past champion and a two-time podium finisher&amp;mdash;alongside its internal brand and marketing leaders. Additionally, other members of the gravel cycling community, along with partners and athletes, and a survey of many members of the DK community were instrumental in validating that &amp;lsquo;UNBOUND Gravel&amp;rsquo; meets the event&amp;rsquo;s future vision. Finally, members of the Emporia-based events team visited Kaw Nation, Okla. to visit with members of the Tribal Council to openly discuss the renaming of the event and share the planned path forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;This rebrand is the end of a chapter for us as the DK, but we&amp;rsquo;ll continue to embrace the history of the land on which we ride. We hope that each time riders touch the gravel roads in the Flint Hills, they take a moment to remember what has been,&amp;rdquo; said Kristi Mohn, UNBOUND Gravel Marketing Manager. &amp;ldquo;UNBOUND Gravel provides an opportunity to reimagine what an event&amp;nbsp;can look like, and this rebrand is only step one in the process. So much is yet to come for the gravel community.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In keeping with the establishment of its DEI Coalition, Life Time is committed to providing access and education to all individuals, while initiating industry shifts around inclusiveness at events. The organization has&amp;nbsp;&lt;a data-saferedirecturl=&quot;https://www.google.com/url?q=https://my.lifetime.life/policy/commitment.html&amp;amp;source=gmail&amp;amp;ust=1604085665088000&amp;amp;usg=AFQjCNGqI3tRJS1DXAwdqbsgNVzXDAwzTQ&quot; href=&quot;https://my.lifetime.life/policy/commitment.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;pledged to impact change across the industry&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;as a whole, using its 30+ events as a platform. The team is taking deliberate steps to enact change for riders and runners across BIPOC, LGBTQ+, gender-focused, economically disenfranchised and para groups, including lowering the barrier of entry to the sport, providing access to start lines, gaining a clear understanding of who we are, so that we can identify and implement the work that must be done and evoking change to benefit the entire Life Time family of athletes, volunteers, partners, team members and the broader endurance sport community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthering the Company&amp;rsquo;s commitment to the community, the event rebrand comes on the heels of the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a data-saferedirecturl=&quot;https://www.google.com/url?q=https://www.ltfoundation.org/&amp;amp;source=gmail&amp;amp;ust=1604085665088000&amp;amp;usg=AFQjCNEUbmFJZA8WPu2Ci2gyxLrwiF6kyA&quot; href=&quot;https://www.ltfoundation.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Life Time Foundation&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;announcing a multi-year partnership with Emporia Public Schools, through which it has committed $95,000 in funding for a School Food Program that will impact more than 4,300 students across nine schools.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 2021 All Things Gravel Expo will kick off on June 3, with race day being Saturday, June 5. 2021 deferral registration will launch for participants with entry from the cancelled 2020 event on Monday, November 16. Learn more and register at&amp;nbsp;&lt;a data-saferedirecturl=&quot;https://www.google.com/url?q=http://unboundgravel.com&amp;amp;source=gmail&amp;amp;ust=1604085665088000&amp;amp;usg=AFQjCNER_yw-AsUy3XmVgRBwsB0VbawiBg&quot; href=&quot;http://unboundgravel.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;unboundgravel.com&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp;Pre-order UNBOUND Gravel merchandise is available for purchase, with Life Time contributing 15% of all proceeds towards its DEI initiatives for UNBOUND Gravel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About Life Time&amp;reg;, Inc.&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a wellness pioneer, Life Time is reshaping the way consumers approach their health by integrating where we play, work and live &amp;ndash; all with the primary objective of helping people lead healthy, happy lives. With more than 150 destinations in 41 major markets across the U.S. and Canada, Life Time operates luxury athletic resorts, owns and produces iconic athletic events and is expanding its brand through Life Time Work premium coworking spaces and Life Time Living high-end leased residences. For more information visit lifetime.life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;# # #&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Facebook: @unboundgravel&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Twitter: @unboundgravel&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instagram: @unbound_gravel&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 29 Oct 2020 20:31:57 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/dirty-kanza-is-unbound</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/dirty-kanza-is-unbound</guid>
        
        
        <category>Industry</category>
        
        <category>Gravel</category>
        
        <category>Dirty Kanza</category>
        
        <category>Unbound Gravel</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Katy Trail Trip 2020 Trip Report</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;2020, the year that took away bicycle events, gravel rides, get togethers. The year that took away interactions with coworkers, friends, family. The year that took away jobs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2020 is also the year that thousands of people purchased bicycles for the first time in a long time and started riding. Thousands of them out there, on the trails, some even on the streets. E-Bikes, mountain bikes, road bikes, cruisers, you name it, they are out there. We were out there with them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Originally fall 2020 was supposed to be consumed with the Pedal The Cause charity ride here in St. Louis, followed by the Cuban Gravel Crisis in Cuba, Missouri, and wrap up October with the Big Sugar Gravel ride in Bentonville, Arkansas. Well, all that got tossed out the window. With all the rides gone, we started planning our own adventure. Taking on the full 237 miles of the Katy Trail, for myself, again, and for Wagner and Luigi it would be their first time. We were the three bearded amigos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During initial planning we had upwards of 8 guys that were going to do the ride, but as we got into the month of August and I started pushing for people to commit, the numbers dwindled.&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bicycletips.com/home/2020/09/2020-katy-trail-shakedown-ride&quot;&gt;Back at the beginning of September we did a shakedown ride to get gear tested out&lt;/a&gt;. We'll possibly do another post in the future on what gear we took/used/didn't need to carry, but I won't cover much of that in this writeup.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Planned Route&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Day 1: Clinton to Pilot Grove (60 miles)   &lt;br /&gt; Day 2: Pilot Grove to Portland (90 miles)   &lt;br /&gt; Day 3: Portland to Machens (90 miles)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Planning out the ride we decided to do the same direction as three of us did back in 2017, West to East, starting in Clinton, MO and finishing in Machens, Mo. Why west to east? Three reasons:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;The wind typically blows west to east.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;The elevation on the Katy Trail is primarily on the western half, so get that out of the way earlier in the ride. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;We live near St. Louis, figuring we wouldn't want to do a 3-4 hour car drive after finishing, a 30-45 minute drive home is much more appealing.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;Originally we planned to do this over 4 days, not the aggressive three day ride like '17. The plan was to start late Thursday morning, finishing up late Sunday morning. That all changed a few times though, when we departed Clinton on Day 1 we had the above route in mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Katy Trail Stats&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Direction: &lt;/strong&gt;West to East&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Number of Days: &lt;/strong&gt;3&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dates:&lt;/strong&gt; October 1st, 2nd, 3rd, 2020&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Total Distance Rode&lt;/strong&gt;: 249.5 miles&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Total Time on Trail&lt;/strong&gt;: 27 hours 48 minutes&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Total Moving Time&lt;/strong&gt;: 19 hours 53 minutes&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Longest Day:&lt;/strong&gt; Day 3&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shortest Day:&lt;/strong&gt; Day 1&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Max Speed:&lt;/strong&gt; 25.5mph&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Moving Average Speed:&lt;/strong&gt; 12.5mph&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Overall Average Speed:&lt;/strong&gt; 9mph&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Day 1 – Thursday 65 Miles Clinton to Pilot Grove (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.strava.com/activities/4139181219&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Strava Ride&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2020/KatyTrail2020/KatyTrail2020-2-800-f37254632.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;Katy Trail Clinton Missouri Trailhead&quot;&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2020/KatyTrail2020/KatyTrail2020-2-400-f37254632.jpg 400w, /assets/images_out/Content/2020/KatyTrail2020/KatyTrail2020-2-600-f37254632.jpg 600w, /assets/images_out/Content/2020/KatyTrail2020/KatyTrail2020-2-800-f37254632.jpg 800w, /assets/images_out/Content/2020/KatyTrail2020/KatyTrail2020-2-1000-f37254632.jpg 1000w&quot;&gt;
 

 &lt;p&gt;The trip started with everyone loading up bikes and gear in my Tahoe at 630 in the morning on 10/1. We drove from Wildwood, MO to Clinton and arrived around 1030am. From there we loaded the gear on to the bikes, and I rode over to the trailhead restroom to throw on my riding clothing. My father in law snapped our photo and we headed out on the trail around 11:10am. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The weather on Day 1 was great, though we had a headwind most of the day. It was somewhere between 60 and 70 most of the day and sunny except for when we were under the tree canopy provided throughout the trail.&lt;/p&gt;

 &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2020/KatyTrail2020/KatyTrail2020-7-800-7c598794f.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;Flat Tube on the Katy Trail&quot;&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2020/KatyTrail2020/KatyTrail2020-7-400-7c598794f.jpg 400w, /assets/images_out/Content/2020/KatyTrail2020/KatyTrail2020-7-600-7c598794f.jpg 600w, /assets/images_out/Content/2020/KatyTrail2020/KatyTrail2020-7-800-7c598794f.jpg 800w, /assets/images_out/Content/2020/KatyTrail2020/KatyTrail2020-7-1000-7c598794f.jpg 1000w&quot;&gt;
 

&lt;p&gt;We made it to the High Point on the trail, 955 feet above sea level, my Garmin showed 935 feet at that point. It didn’t take long before we were stopped on the side of the trail replacing a tube in Luigi's Trek.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2020/KatyTrail2020/KatyTrail2020-8-800-d98eb4500.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;Flat Tube on the Katy Trail&quot;&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2020/KatyTrail2020/KatyTrail2020-8-400-d98eb4500.jpg 400w, /assets/images_out/Content/2020/KatyTrail2020/KatyTrail2020-8-600-d98eb4500.jpg 600w, /assets/images_out/Content/2020/KatyTrail2020/KatyTrail2020-8-800-d98eb4500.jpg 800w, /assets/images_out/Content/2020/KatyTrail2020/KatyTrail2020-8-1000-d98eb4500.jpg 1000w&quot;&gt;
 


&lt;p&gt;After Luigi's tube, the rest of the day was rather uneventful. Lots of slow climbing up the trail, I forgot how much elevation to expect on the western side of the Katy Trail, total for the day according to my Garmin was 1300 feet of ascent. With the Katy, you're never going up steep hills, but it is hard some times to tell if you're flat, downhill, or uphill. MOST of the time it looks like you're going uphill.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Sedalia&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We pulled into Sedalia sometime after 2pm and jumped off the trail east of the bridge that goes over Highway 65. You can cut through a field into a neighborhood that resides behind the various fast food restaurants on 65. We rode for a bit until we got to the area near Burger King so that I could fill my vegan desires with an Impossible Whopper. We couldn't go inside due to covid, so we rode our bikes through the drive thru and sat down on the curb of a closed business across from BK to eat our food.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2020/KatyTrail2020/KatyTrail2020-9-800-d34c4db4d.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;Sedalia Burger King Drive Thru&quot;&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2020/KatyTrail2020/KatyTrail2020-9-400-d34c4db4d.jpg 400w, /assets/images_out/Content/2020/KatyTrail2020/KatyTrail2020-9-600-d34c4db4d.jpg 600w, /assets/images_out/Content/2020/KatyTrail2020/KatyTrail2020-9-800-d34c4db4d.jpg 800w, /assets/images_out/Content/2020/KatyTrail2020/KatyTrail2020-9-1000-d34c4db4d.jpg 1000w&quot;&gt;
 

&lt;p&gt;As we went through Sedalia we expected to come across some of the BAM riders, a group doing a 5 day ride from Defiance to Clinton. We never came across them, though we did see a sign for them directing them off the trail, so we figured they must of made it to their &amp;quot;camp&amp;quot; before we got into town.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2020/KatyTrail2020/KatyTrail2020-11-800-9f506ad3a.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;Sedalia Missouri Trailhead Katy Trail&quot;&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2020/KatyTrail2020/KatyTrail2020-11-400-9f506ad3a.jpg 400w, /assets/images_out/Content/2020/KatyTrail2020/KatyTrail2020-11-600-9f506ad3a.jpg 600w, /assets/images_out/Content/2020/KatyTrail2020/KatyTrail2020-11-800-9f506ad3a.jpg 800w, /assets/images_out/Content/2020/KatyTrail2020/KatyTrail2020-11-1000-9f506ad3a.jpg 1000w&quot;&gt;
 


&lt;p&gt;There's a Katy Trail Detour in Sedalia, basically a section of trail that simply doesn't exist yet, so you have to head off on some city/country roads to get to the trail again. Going through on a Thursday afternoon, I don't think we came across a single car while on that section of the ride.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Pilot Grove&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We pulled in to Pilot Grove around 5:30 on Thursday night. We found a local who told us what our food options were in town Deon's Bar and the Casey's Gas Station. I called the local police number to tell them we were going to stay the night in the park, they asked for contact info, how many were in our party, and how many tents/hammocks and what color tent. There was no charge to stay in the park for the night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2020/KatyTrail2020/KatyTrail2020-16-800-3b7aeb7a8.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;Pilot Grove City Park Katy Trail&quot;&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2020/KatyTrail2020/KatyTrail2020-16-400-3b7aeb7a8.jpg 400w, /assets/images_out/Content/2020/KatyTrail2020/KatyTrail2020-16-600-3b7aeb7a8.jpg 600w, /assets/images_out/Content/2020/KatyTrail2020/KatyTrail2020-16-800-3b7aeb7a8.jpg 800w, /assets/images_out/Content/2020/KatyTrail2020/KatyTrail2020-16-1000-3b7aeb7a8.jpg 1000w&quot;&gt;
 


&lt;p&gt;We headed over to the park, setup the gear for sleeping, and got changed to grab a bite to eat. We headed back to the trailhead where Deon's was located and locked our bikes up outside to grab a bite to eat. I think I ate a small salad and tater tots for dinner that night, along with a Coke (mistake due to the caffeine). Deon's was nice enough, mid-Missouri bar, so, smoking occurring inside and Adam's Family on an old rear projection TV. It is also a package liquor store, so I looked to see if they had anything I wanted to try to haul on my bike for 3 days, fortunately I didn't find anything I needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2020/KatyTrail2020/KatyTrail2020-17-800-685bdae6e.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;Inverted Niner RLT&quot;&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2020/KatyTrail2020/KatyTrail2020-17-400-685bdae6e.jpg 400w, /assets/images_out/Content/2020/KatyTrail2020/KatyTrail2020-17-600-685bdae6e.jpg 600w, /assets/images_out/Content/2020/KatyTrail2020/KatyTrail2020-17-800-685bdae6e.jpg 800w, /assets/images_out/Content/2020/KatyTrail2020/KatyTrail2020-17-1000-685bdae6e.jpg 1000w&quot;&gt;
 

&lt;p&gt;From there we stopped at Casey’s, I picked up 2 packs of brown sugar cinnamon Pop-Tarts and then we headed back to the camp. My bike had managed to flip itself over a wall while I was inside, fortunately no damage was incurred with that incident.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Chilly Night&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;It was supposed to get rather cold that night, so we were concerned about how warm we would be in our hammocks. I had my rain tarp down low, trying to keep it close to where the hammock was to try and keep some warmth inside my space. I had a sleeping pad, sleeping bag, and an insert for the sleeping bag for extra warmth. I ended up not having the sleeping back zipped up all the way most of the night. I was uncomfortable all night, but not from the cold, I just simply couldn't get into a position that worked for me in the hammock and had a horrible night of sleep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know that Luigi also had the same problem, because I could hear him moving around throughout the night as I lay awake. He unfortunately also had the discomfort of being cold as well. His sleeping pad didn't provide near the insulation that mine did, and his body isn't as well insulated as mine either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wagner slept in his tent, and while chilly, I think he actually got a comfortable sleep.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Day 2 – Friday 75.41 Miles Pilot Grove to Tebbetts (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.strava.com/activities/4142810405&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Strava Ride&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;We set our alarms for 6am on Friday and got up well before the sunrise to start packing up all our gear and load the bikes back up. We left the park around 7:15am and headed over to Casey's to grab some breakfast and a coffee, only to find that it was &amp;quot;closed for cleaning&amp;quot;... Thanks covid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2020/KatyTrail2020/KatyTrail2020-19-800-482da4bf3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;Flat Tire Pilot Grove&quot;&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2020/KatyTrail2020/KatyTrail2020-19-400-482da4bf3.jpg 400w, /assets/images_out/Content/2020/KatyTrail2020/KatyTrail2020-19-600-482da4bf3.jpg 600w, /assets/images_out/Content/2020/KatyTrail2020/KatyTrail2020-19-800-482da4bf3.jpg 800w, /assets/images_out/Content/2020/KatyTrail2020/KatyTrail2020-19-1000-482da4bf3.jpg 1000w&quot;&gt;
 

&lt;p&gt;We stopped at the trailhead to top off the air in our tires. Not 60 seconds in Wagner managed to BREAK the stem on his tubeless tire/wheel setup, somehow it didn't lose any air. The valve stem was clogged with sealant, even broken off with no valve in place, the air remained. We debated just riding with it like that, but I encouraged him just to go ahead and throw a tube in it. We were at a trailhead, had a pump, and a place to sit. Might as well change it there instead of running the risk of it losing all air 5 minutes outside of town.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Breakfast&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Especially because the Casey's was closed we were hungry for breakfast and decided to find something in Boonville. We arrived in town around 9am, maybe a little before, and found the Main Street Diner, a fine establishment with good food and great service. After a warm meal, heat, and a few conversations with a couple of other cyclists we decided to head back to the bike shop at the train station in Boonville. Google said the store was to have opened 9am, and since we were down two spare tubes (I still had my original 2) it was a good idea to grab one for both Luigi and Wagner. Unfortunately when we got back over to the bike shop they had a note on the door &amp;quot;Due to covid, closed, open Saturday and Sunday&amp;quot;... So that was that. No tube replacements would be purchased for the remainder of the trip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2020/KatyTrail2020/KatyTrail2020-23-800-16d2610a4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;Boonville, MO Trailhead&quot;&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2020/KatyTrail2020/KatyTrail2020-23-400-16d2610a4.jpg 400w, /assets/images_out/Content/2020/KatyTrail2020/KatyTrail2020-23-600-16d2610a4.jpg 600w, /assets/images_out/Content/2020/KatyTrail2020/KatyTrail2020-23-800-16d2610a4.jpg 800w, /assets/images_out/Content/2020/KatyTrail2020/KatyTrail2020-23-1000-16d2610a4.jpg 1000w&quot;&gt;
 

&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2020/KatyTrail2020/KatyTrail2020-24-800-72f4d8f2a.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;Boonville, MO Trailhead&quot;&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2020/KatyTrail2020/KatyTrail2020-24-400-72f4d8f2a.jpg 400w, /assets/images_out/Content/2020/KatyTrail2020/KatyTrail2020-24-600-72f4d8f2a.jpg 600w, /assets/images_out/Content/2020/KatyTrail2020/KatyTrail2020-24-800-72f4d8f2a.jpg 800w, /assets/images_out/Content/2020/KatyTrail2020/KatyTrail2020-24-1000-72f4d8f2a.jpg 1000w&quot;&gt;
 

&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2020/KatyTrail2020/KatyTrail2020-25-800-90d01ee16.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;Boonville, MO&quot;&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2020/KatyTrail2020/KatyTrail2020-25-400-90d01ee16.jpg 400w, /assets/images_out/Content/2020/KatyTrail2020/KatyTrail2020-25-600-90d01ee16.jpg 600w, /assets/images_out/Content/2020/KatyTrail2020/KatyTrail2020-25-800-90d01ee16.jpg 800w, /assets/images_out/Content/2020/KatyTrail2020/KatyTrail2020-25-1000-90d01ee16.jpg 1000w&quot;&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;Out of Boonville we made it through Old and New Franklin, and on to Rocheport. The Tunnel outside of Rocheport is always a cool site. Before getting to Rocheport though we had to deal with a little detour. It was actually pretty easy to reroute, and not have to go on the highway anywhere. You basically ride up to the closure, and take a right on the gravel road, hang a left, up and over the levy and you'll pass through a dry creek bed. We actually went to the left, climbed a grassy level and rode that east back to the trail/detour. It wasn't wet for us. Once you're through the creekbed you are basically back on the trail and on your way.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Burr Oak&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2020/KatyTrail2020/KatyTrail2020-30-800-24b19deaf.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;Burr Oak Tree&quot;&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2020/KatyTrail2020/KatyTrail2020-30-400-24b19deaf.jpg 400w, /assets/images_out/Content/2020/KatyTrail2020/KatyTrail2020-30-600-24b19deaf.jpg 600w, /assets/images_out/Content/2020/KatyTrail2020/KatyTrail2020-30-800-24b19deaf.jpg 800w, /assets/images_out/Content/2020/KatyTrail2020/KatyTrail2020-30-1000-24b19deaf.jpg 1000w&quot;&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;    
    Out of Rocheport we started looking for the Burr Oak tree. Another must see stop on the Katy trail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the tree we continued on, planning to stop in Hartsburg, MO for lunch. The route was uneventful, we passed by the spur that connects the trail up to Columbia, MO. Shortly after that we came across three guys sitting on a bench on the side of the trail. I didn't pay too much attention to them, made the assumption that they were some college kids from Mizzou out for a ride, when passing by them one of them yelled out my name. I realized it was Justin, another buddy who told me he was riding the Katy Trail that week too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They were riding Wednesday - Sunday staying in hotels and B&amp;amp;Bs along the way. I stopped to chat for a few minutes and then got on our way to Hartsburg. Upon entering Hartsburg we started scouting out some locations for lunch. It was after noon on Friday, so we assumed that we would find something open. A local at the trailhead said that everything was closed until the weekend, I looked online, and sure enough, online results told me the same thing. We decided to ride around town and check to see if the bar, or Dottie's were open, even though the online results said otherwise. The bar was closed until 3pm, but as we pulled up to Dottie's the open sign was flashing. In I ran, and sure enough, they were open!&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2020/KatyTrail2020/KatyTrail2020-32-800-e975515fe.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;Boatillac Ranch&quot;&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2020/KatyTrail2020/KatyTrail2020-32-400-e975515fe.jpg 400w, /assets/images_out/Content/2020/KatyTrail2020/KatyTrail2020-32-600-e975515fe.jpg 600w, /assets/images_out/Content/2020/KatyTrail2020/KatyTrail2020-32-800-e975515fe.jpg 800w, /assets/images_out/Content/2020/KatyTrail2020/KatyTrail2020-32-1000-e975515fe.jpg 1000w&quot;&gt;
 

    
&lt;h3&gt;Lunch&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We sat down and had lunch at Dotties, followed by a trip to the restroom there and then back on the bikes for the afternoon. The plan as we left Hartsburg was to try to find a gas station where we could refuel, and make it to Tebbetts for the night. We made it down to the North Jefferson trailhead and didn't come across a gas station or grocery store. We pulled out the old Google and looked to see what our closest option was for a grocery store. It was going to easily be a 1 hour round trip to get something, so we started discussing if we had enough food for the night. Could we survive on snacks, and then do 25 miles in the morning to get to The Corner, in Rhineland, MO?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Tebbetts&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2020/KatyTrail2020/KatyTrail2020-36-800-873d91a3c.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;Tebbetts Missouri&quot;&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2020/KatyTrail2020/KatyTrail2020-36-400-873d91a3c.jpg 400w, /assets/images_out/Content/2020/KatyTrail2020/KatyTrail2020-36-600-873d91a3c.jpg 600w, /assets/images_out/Content/2020/KatyTrail2020/KatyTrail2020-36-800-873d91a3c.jpg 800w, /assets/images_out/Content/2020/KatyTrail2020/KatyTrail2020-36-1000-873d91a3c.jpg 1000w&quot;&gt;
 

&lt;p&gt;We discussed it and decided we could. So we headed further east to Tebbetts to look for the hostel. Upon arrival in Tebbetts it was pretty easy to spot the Turner Katy Trail Shelter (the hostel) so we jumped off the trail at the trailhead and rode on over. There was a rider outside having a meal at a picnic table when we pulled up, we said hello and I went inside to check the place out. There was another rider inside, John (or was he Jim?). John was from Oregon, but apparently had been on the road for 7 years, over 60k miles bikepacking. He was headed back west, hoping to make it to New Mexico or SoCal and then perhaps take a break.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jim was from Springfield, IL, and had only a few days earlier started after his wife had given him the go ahead for a quick trip. He was heading to Sedalia to take a train back home. Wagner, Luigi and I all took the opportunity to get our bikes inside and unpack some things for the night. A local drove up and let us know that there was a fish fry in town, Jim was the first one to grab a &amp;quot;plate&amp;quot;. The three bearded amigos all cleaned up, took showers, and walked over to where the fish fry was occurring. There was quite a line, and for the first time in a few days, pretty much everyone was wearing masks. (Masks aren't a big thing in Mid-Missouri, but the group putting on the fish fry had them on.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Fish Dinner&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Only Wagner actually grabbed a box from the fish fry, myself being vegan, and Luigi eating extremely clean, there wasn't anything for us. So Wagner got a good meal, and we ate our planned bars/snacks for the night. We aren't really sure who was putting on the fish fry, but I assume it was a local church. They told us that this was the first one that they have had since Covid hit, and even though they ordered extra fish, they were quickly running out as they received far more orders than imagined.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By 7pm both Jim and John were in their bunks, so the three of us got everything ready for our own bunks and I think by 730pm the lights were out. I ended up going to sleep with my air pods in, with the noise canceling enabled and Ohms from Deftones playing. I can't tell you the last time I went to sleep with music going (wifey won't let me), but I was out like the 13 year old me when I would listen to the radio every night going to sleep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did end up waking up a little while later when the music stopped and turned it back on. About 11pm I remember waking up with sore ears, but the noise canceling was still working so I kept my buds in. Sometime early in the morning I took them out as the noise canceling had stopped. Our alarms went off at 6am and we packed up our gear and headed out the front door of the hostel.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Day 3 – Saturday 108.71 Miles Tebbetts to Machens to Black Walnut (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.strava.com/activities/4147602686&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Strava Ride&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2020/KatyTrail2020/KatyTrail2020-37-800-7fcb4da6e.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;Tebbetts Missouri Turner Katy Trail Shelter&quot;&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2020/KatyTrail2020/KatyTrail2020-37-400-7fcb4da6e.jpg 400w, /assets/images_out/Content/2020/KatyTrail2020/KatyTrail2020-37-600-7fcb4da6e.jpg 600w, /assets/images_out/Content/2020/KatyTrail2020/KatyTrail2020-37-800-7fcb4da6e.jpg 800w, /assets/images_out/Content/2020/KatyTrail2020/KatyTrail2020-37-1000-7fcb4da6e.jpg 1000w&quot;&gt;
 

&lt;p&gt;The morning started early in Tebbetts, taking off from the hostel around 7:10am. The plan was to ride to Rhineland and get some breakfast, there would not be many options between Tebbetts and Rhineland to grab anything else. As we stood outside the hostel making last minute adjustments before riding off, I mentioned to the amigos that I really wanted to try to get the remaining 105 miles completed that day, instead of breaking it up into 2 days. The last real option for camping was going to be Defiance, MO, that would put our total for the day around 70 miles. Wagner and Luigi agreed that we would try to finish, but if something came up, weather, mechanical, we would be open to finishing on Sunday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The route would take us through Portland, but there were no food options that we know of open early there, we had breakfast at The Corner in Rhineland a month ago, so we were pretty sure it would be worth the 25 mile ride to eat there. Before getting there though we needed to get through the rock fall on the trail just west of Portland. We were told by fellow riders that it was passable, though the website said there was no detour for the fall. We rode up to the rock fall and started to make our way up and over the rocks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Rock Fall Detour&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2020/KatyTrail2020/KatyTrail2020-47-800-9a7a014c3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;Katy Trail Rockfall Closure&quot;&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2020/KatyTrail2020/KatyTrail2020-47-400-9a7a014c3.jpg 400w, /assets/images_out/Content/2020/KatyTrail2020/KatyTrail2020-47-600-9a7a014c3.jpg 600w, /assets/images_out/Content/2020/KatyTrail2020/KatyTrail2020-47-800-9a7a014c3.jpg 800w, /assets/images_out/Content/2020/KatyTrail2020/KatyTrail2020-47-1000-9a7a014c3.jpg 1000w&quot;&gt;
 


&lt;p&gt;This was no easy task, we actually climbed up one route and found that there was no way down, so we backtracked and went a different way. Definitely an exercise in patience and balance, and carrying heavy bikes. We made it down, towards the river, and came across a beaten down trail that took us the rest of the way. I'm pretty sure if we had just started looking prior to the rock fall we likely would have found a path there people had gone off the trail and made their own trail around the rocks, we took the hard way instead. The trail where closed was extremely overgrown, you can tell it isn’t getting traveled much, it is amazing how much nature can take back on her own.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Breakfast in Rhineland&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;From the rock fall to Portland, and then on to Rhineland was uneventful. It was starting to sprinkle a bit as we arrived at The Corner, so we quickly got ourselves inside and found a table to sit down. I ordered oatmeal, hash browns and a bowl of fruit, and plenty of coffee, the same order I had back in early September. I will admit though, this meal wasn't as pleasing as it was a month earlier. The oatmeal was super watery, and not very warm. The bowl of fruit, instead of being mixed berries, was canned peaches, and the hash browns were far from toasty as well. The coffee though, the 5 or 6 cups, hit the spot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From Rhineland we headed east, the plan was to ride to Marthasville to get some lunch at the Gas Station south of the trail/ballfields. While we had breakfast it had rained quite a bit, and it would continue to spit and sputter the rest of the day, but it wasn't raining hard on us at any point while riding. We ended up having fairly dry trails, with little rooster tailing or mud throwing until we got much closer to St. Charles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2020/KatyTrail2020/KatyTrail2020-51-800-4e33baa06.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;Katy Trail Layers for Weather&quot;&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2020/KatyTrail2020/KatyTrail2020-51-400-4e33baa06.jpg 400w, /assets/images_out/Content/2020/KatyTrail2020/KatyTrail2020-51-600-4e33baa06.jpg 600w, /assets/images_out/Content/2020/KatyTrail2020/KatyTrail2020-51-800-4e33baa06.jpg 800w, /assets/images_out/Content/2020/KatyTrail2020/KatyTrail2020-51-1000-4e33baa06.jpg 1000w&quot;&gt;
 

&lt;p&gt;The weather kept the traffic down, we pulled into Marthasville and headed straight to the gas station to grab some snacks, the first time we picked up food from somewhere other than a restaurant besides my pop-tarts at Casey's on Thursday night. While at the gas station, we saw a group of classic cars, probably 20+ deep, pass down the road, including a Shelby GT 350H that pulled in to fill up at the station. We took our snacks and headed back to the trailhead to sit down and eat. As we were there a couple pulled up on bikes, they were daytripping from Hermann. They asked about restaurants, we told them there was one in Dutzow if they wanted to ride on a little further.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By Dutzow we were ready to take a break every 8-10 miles, we were well over 175 miles for the trip by this point, so I wasn't concerned about taking a few extra breaks, though I was worried that if we took too long on the breaks it would stretch our day out past the available sun. We were in the end game now, the home stretch, on parts of the Katy Trail we regularly rode.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Augusta&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We stopped again in Augusta, grabbed some waters from Kickstand Katy and took the opportunity to have a few snacks and use the restroom at the trailhead. There was an event going on in Augusta, but there were very few bikes on the trail all day. The event, we believe, had something to do with the local brewery, but we weren't about to try to ride around and see what it was all about, it was time to continue east.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2020/KatyTrail2020/KatyTrail2020-52-800-44c65cd3d.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;Greens Bottom Katy Trailhead&quot;&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2020/KatyTrail2020/KatyTrail2020-52-400-44c65cd3d.jpg 400w, /assets/images_out/Content/2020/KatyTrail2020/KatyTrail2020-52-600-44c65cd3d.jpg 600w, /assets/images_out/Content/2020/KatyTrail2020/KatyTrail2020-52-800-44c65cd3d.jpg 800w, /assets/images_out/Content/2020/KatyTrail2020/KatyTrail2020-52-1000-44c65cd3d.jpg 1000w&quot;&gt;
 

&lt;p&gt;We ended up riding through Defiance and stopped again at the Weldon Spring trailhead, as we passed through Defiance I was probably 10 miles as the crow flies from my house. The ride from Weldon Spring took us to the Green's Bottom trailhead for another break/snack, and from there we rode in to St. Charles for our last bathroom break of the trip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From St. Charles to Machens it was around 13 miles, so we placed a few phone calls to our wives, to let them know we would likely be ready for pick up around 630pm. The plan was to ride to Machens, and then ride 3 miles back to the Black Walnut trailhead for pickup, as there is not a way for cars to get out to the Machens trailhead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2020/KatyTrail2020/KatyTrail2020-54-800-a328524cc.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;Katy Trail St. Charles Trailhead&quot;&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2020/KatyTrail2020/KatyTrail2020-54-400-a328524cc.jpg 400w, /assets/images_out/Content/2020/KatyTrail2020/KatyTrail2020-54-600-a328524cc.jpg 600w, /assets/images_out/Content/2020/KatyTrail2020/KatyTrail2020-54-800-a328524cc.jpg 800w, /assets/images_out/Content/2020/KatyTrail2020/KatyTrail2020-54-1000-a328524cc.jpg 1000w&quot;&gt;
 

&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2020/KatyTrail2020/KatyTrail2020-56-800-9379ed636.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;Katy Trail Low Point&quot;&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2020/KatyTrail2020/KatyTrail2020-56-400-9379ed636.jpg 400w, /assets/images_out/Content/2020/KatyTrail2020/KatyTrail2020-56-600-9379ed636.jpg 600w, /assets/images_out/Content/2020/KatyTrail2020/KatyTrail2020-56-800-9379ed636.jpg 800w, /assets/images_out/Content/2020/KatyTrail2020/KatyTrail2020-56-1000-9379ed636.jpg 1000w&quot;&gt;
 

&lt;p&gt;St. Charles to Machens you ride past cricket fields and junk yards, followed by nothing but farmland. You will pass through the low point on the Katy Trail, 436 feet, though if you blink you might miss the sign, especially at dusk. We quickly rode through Black Walnut, not seeing any of our vehicles there yet. As we neared the end of the trail we came across the section of trail that had recently been repaired from a washout. As we went through this area, probably .25 from the end of the trail, I hit a soft spot on the trail and about wiped out. I pictured myself losing the front wheel and face planting right there, 1/4 mile from the end, fortunately that didn't occur.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Eastern Terminus Machens&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2020/KatyTrail2020/KatyTrail2020-59-800-8ff140145.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;Katy Trail Eastern Terminus Machens, MO&quot;&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2020/KatyTrail2020/KatyTrail2020-59-400-8ff140145.jpg 400w, /assets/images_out/Content/2020/KatyTrail2020/KatyTrail2020-59-600-8ff140145.jpg 600w, /assets/images_out/Content/2020/KatyTrail2020/KatyTrail2020-59-800-8ff140145.jpg 800w, /assets/images_out/Content/2020/KatyTrail2020/KatyTrail2020-59-1000-8ff140145.jpg 1000w&quot;&gt;
 


&lt;p&gt;Machens provides the terminus for the ride, we pulled in there at just about 106 miles for the day. Just after 6:20pm, over 11 hours after we left Tebbetts that morning. We didn't stick around Machens too long, we took a few pictures, rang the bell (maybe broke a bell too, see video later) and then jumped back on our bikes. We wanted to get back to Black Walnut before dark, and that was going to take some riding. We started off slow, but as we plugged along we started picking up the pace, from our earlier day pace of 12-13mph we were cranking along at 15-16mph and even up to 20 mph in a final sprint to the trailhead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we arrived, everyone's wives and families were there, except mine... Natalie showed up a bit later, I said hello to everyone there and started unloading my bike and its gear at the trailhead. Taking the bags off so that I could get the bike back on the rack of the Tahoe without struggle. Just about the time I had everything ready, Natalie and my kids pulled up. Hugs and congrats were shared and then I packed up the Tahoe so we could get on the road and find some food. I planned on another BK Impossible Whopper as my reward for finishing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Review&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Overall it was a great trip. Only two flats, no other mechanical issues on any of the bikes. My trusty Niner RLT performed flawlessly with its Maxxis tires (so glad I dumped those Panaracers).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Will we do this ride again? Never say never, but I can't imagine I will do it again trying to camp. It would be much easier to just try to plan around B&amp;amp;Bs or Hotels and the Hostel, rather than trying to carry all the gear needed for camping. That's not to say I won't try bike packing again in the future, I definitely will, but I'll be buying a tent and selling off my recently acquired hammock gear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you're thinking about riding the Katy Trail, do it. It is such a great ride. While we didn't see much bike traffic on this trip, we totally expected more. The trail has been packed with new riders in 2020, I hope they continue to come out. We did benefit from weather that kept riders away on Saturday, but weather that wasn't so miserable that we suffered on the ride because of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We didn't get to see much fall color, perhaps doing the ride 1 or 2 weeks later in October would help with that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2020/KatyTrail2020/KatyTrail2020-60-800-01bf86913.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;Niner RLT Bikepacking&quot;&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2020/KatyTrail2020/KatyTrail2020-60-400-01bf86913.jpg 400w, /assets/images_out/Content/2020/KatyTrail2020/KatyTrail2020-60-600-01bf86913.jpg 600w, /assets/images_out/Content/2020/KatyTrail2020/KatyTrail2020-60-800-01bf86913.jpg 800w, /assets/images_out/Content/2020/KatyTrail2020/KatyTrail2020-60-1000-01bf86913.jpg 1000w&quot;&gt;
 


&lt;h2&gt;What's Next&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Who knows what big adventure is next. I hope to continue riding the gravel bike this fall, and have already cleaned it up from the trip and removed all the racks used for the trip. Some time later this fall I am sure we will start planning some adventures for 2021. I am already in for the Dirty Kanza 2021 (or whatever the new name becomes) so I will plan to continue training for that. I have real concerns about being able to finish that 200 miles in the 21 hour time limit, so I need to really keep up on riding and training between now and early June 2021.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I'm also really interested in crossing Missouri by boat. Perhaps that will be something to plan in 2021.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/chammond/albums/72157716369902207&quot; title=&quot;Katy Trail 2020&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/50457319077_8bfce7de79_c.jpg&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;600&quot; alt=&quot;Katy Trail 2020&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2020 03:37:01 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/katy-trail-trip-2020-trip-report</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/katy-trail-trip-2020-trip-report</guid>
        
        
        <category>Bicycle Tips</category>
        
        <category>Travel</category>
        
        <category>Trips</category>
        
        <category>Missouri</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>2020 Katy Trail Shakedown Ride</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images_out/KatyShakedown-16-800-6977684b4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;Niner RLT loaded up for bike packing&quot;&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images_out/KatyShakedown-16-400-6977684b4.jpg 400w, /assets/images_out/KatyShakedown-16-600-6977684b4.jpg 600w, /assets/images_out/KatyShakedown-16-800-6977684b4.jpg 800w, /assets/images_out/KatyShakedown-16-1000-6977684b4.jpg 1000w&quot;&gt;
   
  My grand vision of building the Bicycle Tips brand/website in 2020 were apparently dashed with Covid. That hasn’t stopped the riding, though there has been less than planned, and no organized rides after The Mid South in March. Early in the summer we started the idea of riding the Katy Trail again. Once again planning for the end of September/early October as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bicycletips.com/home/2017/10/riding-the-katy-trail-from-clinton-to-machens-katytrail2017&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;a few of us had done in 2017&lt;/a&gt;. This time we started planning that we would do it fully self supported, no one meeting us each evening carrying our gear, we would carry our own gear this trip. In order to make sure that was possible, we planned a shakedown ride over Labor Day weekend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We would start at the LeCave Memorial Trailhead in Wildwood/Chesterfield, ride ~4 miles to the Katy Trail, and then head west towards Portland, MO. Why Portland? I was looking for somewhere to camp, along with a place that had somewhere to get food. Portland has the River’s Edge RV Park &amp;amp; Campground, as well as Holzhauser’s Bar &amp;amp; Grill. The plan was 70 miles out, camp, and ride back the same 70 miles home the next morning. We wanted to test out our equipment, make sure that we carried the proper gear, and hopefully not to much of it. I also wanted to try sleeping in a hammock as I had never done that before. I always sleep on my stomach in some weird contorted position, knee raised to the side, figuring a hammock wouldn’t work for that I needed to make sure I could actually get some sleep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luigi and I started at noon on Saturday 9/5. Wagner joined us for the start of the ride, but was not going all the way and staying the night in Portland. It would have been ideal to start at our usual 6am time, it was a hot afternoon on Saturday, but we really didn’t want to ride 6-7 hours and then sit around Portland all afternoon. We talked our wives and kids into meeting us in Portland for dinner on Saturday night, so they planned to bring some food and water just in case we didn’t find options at Holzhauser’s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Katy Trail was busy, as it has been in 2020, everyone is out, and it is great to see so much traffic both on foot and bicycle. We made our way quickly through Defiance and on towards Augusta when I noticed what appeared to be an odd coloring in my front tire on my Niner RLT, I thought maybe it had a leak and the sealant was discolored with dirt. We stopped in Augusta, primarily so I could go “#2”, I’m a big believer in pooping when you ride, I’m a pretty regular guy, and if I don’t poop I get to be pretty miserable while riding, so any time I can, I will. After doing my business I took a look at the front tire and notice it was horribly misshapen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;KatyShakedown-3&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/chammond/50316780131/in/album-72157715879059516/&quot; data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;480&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; alt=&quot;KatyShakedown-3&quot; src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/50316780131_55f54ce7c8_z.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went over to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://kickstandkaty.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;KickstandKaty&lt;/a&gt; snack bar to see if they had any replacement tires, as I had intended to carry a spare with me, but failed to pack it. Luck would have it, they did have a tire, but only a 700/32, which would have to do. She cautioned me that they were expensive, and then told me it was $30, to which I thought was cheap. She explained that she buys a couple from Big Shark just to have on hand, and only charges what she pays. Later when I got home I checked and the tire runs $12 online, but to be honest, that $30 saved the trip, more on that later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was running 700/43 Panaracer Gravelkings, having actually JUST replaced the rear tire the night before because it had failed a few times on recent rides on the Katy and I didn’t want to have to worry about it leaking (with a tube). So I purchased the 32 width tire and coiled it up on the back of the bike, hoping that I could make it to Portland on the Panaracer and have my wife bring me another spare tire from home, and have the 32 JUST IN CASE.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;KatyShakedown-22&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/chammond/50316774821/in/album-72157715879059516/&quot; data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;494&quot; style=&quot;display: block;&quot; alt=&quot;KatyShakedown-22&quot; src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/50316774821_907778a716_z.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, low and behold, we didn’t make it 4 miles out of Augusta before my tire started spraying sealant. I stopped, put the hole towards the top and let it seal back up. It seemed to hold, and have enough air remaining, so we continued on. Not 5 minutes later there was sealant spraying everywhere and the tire quickly lost the air it so needed to roll down the crushed limestone trail of the Katy. We stopped in the shade and performed surgery to swap out the tubeless Panaracer Gravel King with a Continental Ride Tour. The tire was noticeable narrower than the Gravelking, but you know what? It held air, which was more than those expensive Panaracers could say. I simply haven’t had good experiences with the Gravelkings. They might look cool, orange against my orange and white bike, but while riding the Katy trail in either late June or early July I had the rear tear (I won’t say it was a cut) in the middle of the tread, in two places, and I had to tube it and throw a barrier between the tube and tire. I don’t feel that the tire held up like the cost should. I got less than 1.2k miles on those tires, with a majority of those being on the Katy trail, a crushed limestone rails to trails path.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;KatyShakedown-5&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/chammond/50316111508/in/album-72157715879059516/&quot; data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;480&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; alt=&quot;KatyShakedown-5&quot; src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/50316111508_c8f0b9895b_z.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;KatyShakedown-12&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/chammond/50316109768/in/album-72157715879059516/&quot; data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;480&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; style=&quot;display: inline;&quot; alt=&quot;KatyShakedown-12&quot; src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/50316109768_529918ac29_z.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;script async src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From there, the rest of the day was mostly uneventful, except for water. We rode through Dutzow where Wagner departed and headed back to civilization. At this trailhead there was an aid station for a running group, I believe Run DRC, we would see these stations for the next hour or more as we went along the trail, it looked like they had runners doing either 50k and 50 mile runs. In Marthasville we stopped to take a break, I filled up the tire with the Katy Trail tools floor pump mounted at the station. Luigi rode down to the ballfields and picked up 2 bottles of water, one for each of us, and we headed on our way west. We made it to Treloar, and kept riding, thinking that water wouldn’t be any problem to find. Well, little did we realize at the time, Treloar to McKittrick is one of the longest, if not the longest, gap on the trail without stations. By the time we finally made it to McKittrick, just north of Hermann, MO we were running low on water, and I was most definitely running low on energy. The heat of the day was really taking it out of me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was having trouble keeping my pace above 11mph, sometimes dipping below 10, most of the afternoon I had a heart rate of 160, which to me is higher than I would like for a long ride. In McKittrick I stopped, took my shoes off to let me feet breathe a bit and laid on the bench at the station. We asked another rider who was getting into his car where the closest water might be, he told us that there was a gas station a mile down the road, south of the trail. We decided that we could make it on to Rhineland where there should be water, instead of taking a mile detour. Once we were back on the trail, before passing through the tunnel at McKittrick we could actually see the gas station, it was nowhere near a mile off trail, so we took a left on the connector to the road to Hermann and stopped at the BP station to fill up. I grabbed 3 1L bottles of water and a Gatorade. Filling up our bottles and my pack with water, we had 1L bottle left and got back on the trail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We passed through Rhineland, and I saw the restaurant we would be eating breakfast at the next morning, The Corner. We got to Bluffton and stopped at a bench so I could take on some more fuel. I told Luigi we might see our wives driving by on their way to Portland to meet us with our kids. As we were sitting there, my wife’s blue Kia goes driving by with Luigi’s wife sitting in the front seat, wearing a bright yellow shirt, making her easy to pick out. We waved and then met them at the crossing where the trail crosses 94 just west of Bluffton to say hello.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;KatyShakedown-15&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/chammond/50316776861/in/album-72157715879059516/&quot; data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;480&quot; alt=&quot;KatyShakedown-15&quot; src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/50316776861_59b367a587_z.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;KatyShakedown-16&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/chammond/50316957687/in/album-72157715879059516/&quot; data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;480&quot; alt=&quot;KatyShakedown-16&quot; src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/50316957687_02ae43c205_z.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We pulled into Portland just after 6:30pm, making it about 6.5 hours on the trail, with stops and repairs along the way. The minivan was in the trailhead lot, but the families were nowhere to be found, they had made their way down to the river to entertain themselves while they waited for us. Luigi and I got to work setting up camp. I had previously setup my hammock, but I hadn’t setup the bug screen or the rain cover before, so that slowed me down a bit. We picked our spots, I learned that you shouldn’t pick a spot with a dirt pile right outside your hammock, as in the dark you’re going to kick it many times and get dirt on your feet and flip flops. Pretty sure I have any bites on the top of one of my feet from those dirt piles. Once camp was setup the family showed back up and we started figuring out what to do for dinner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;KatyShakedown-23&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/chammond/50316774781/in/album-72157715879059516/&quot; data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;480&quot; alt=&quot;KatyShakedown-23&quot; src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/50316774781_24b11563f8_z.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We went over to Holzhauser’s Bar &amp;amp; Grill to see what options they had, pretty standard grill food, burgers, grilled cheese, fries, tater tots, maybe a chicken sandwich too? I ended up ordering tater tots and fries, I think I might have ordered two servings of tots and 1 serving of fries, neither of which got finished. The kids enjoyed their burgers. I ended up eating the two nut butter sandwiches I had made earlier in the day and had Natalie bring in case I couldn’t find any vegan options.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;KatyShakedown-24&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/chammond/50316774486/in/album-72157715879059516/&quot; data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;480&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; alt=&quot;KatyShakedown-24&quot; src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/50316774486_9835192176_z.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;KatyShakedown-25&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/chammond/50316955287/in/album-72157715879059516/&quot; data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;480&quot; alt=&quot;KatyShakedown-25&quot; src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/50316955287_b5b4ce33b2_z.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While we were waiting for our orders from Holzhauser’s we were outside and notice an off-road cart pull up to the campground, I figured that was Melody, the owner, so we ran down to get checked in with her and pay our $10 for the campsite for the night. She also made sure the bathroom door was unlocked and told us there is water via a spigot on the back of the bathroom. After dinner when the families left, Luigi and I took turns taking showers and making final prep for bed, locking up the bikes, putting any valuables that we wanted to secure into the hammocks with us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Around 930pm we hopped in our individual hammocks and tried to see if we could sleep. There was an RV or two parked in the campground, and music coming from one of them as the owners and guests hung out drinking around a campfire. I worried that they would be up all night playing music, but they ended up turning in before 10pm, and camp was quiet except for two other bike packers who came from Columbia, MO earlier in the day. They were sitting around a fire in their camp site talking till after 10 some time. I eventually fell asleep only to be woken at 1030 by another group of bike packers trying to get settled in for the night, having pulled in sometime after we got into the hammocks. They also came in from Columbia, having left Columbia at 9am. That’s a long day, 12 hours, ~65 miles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hammock worked well for me, I was glad I had the bug screen, were were surrounded by trees, and bugs everywhere. At one point while getting ready for bed I saw a spider with a body the size of a chickpea walking right under my hammock, it was at this point that I thought about crushing it, and then thousands of little baby spiders running about, so I flicked it away from my camp and thanked myself for setting up the bug net. I slept on a sleeping pad and sleeping bag in the hammock. The pad helped actually keep the hammock “open” above me, (under the bug net), which I think made things more comfortable for me. It was a somewhat warm evening, I never got cool enough to need the sleeping bag that night. I imagine, hope, it will be cooler in early October, I prefer being chilly and warming up under covers when I sleep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;KatyShakedown-27&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/chammond/50316773931/in/album-72157715879059516/&quot; data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;480&quot; alt=&quot;KatyShakedown-27&quot; src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/50316773931_394120187b_z.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I slept okay that night, waking up occasionally, but not really struggling to go back to sleep. The alarm at 5:45am came far too early. We hopped out of our hammocks and started working to get camp broken back down. It was nearly an hour later before we got back on the trail, Luigi was waiting for me. One problem with overpacking, it takes longer to load back up in the mornings. We took off eastbound from Portland and headed towards Rhineland to get to The Corner for breakfast. It was Sunday morning, and they opened at 7:30am, we arrived there just 2 or 3 minutes after opening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;KatyShakedown-28&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/chammond/50316773681/in/album-72157715879059516/&quot; data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;480&quot; height=&quot;640&quot; alt=&quot;KatyShakedown-28&quot; src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/50316773681_7ce3aa8803_z.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;KatyShakedown-29&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/chammond/50316773331/in/album-72157715879059516/&quot; data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;480&quot; alt=&quot;KatyShakedown-29&quot; src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/50316773331_6979daf3d5_z.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Breakfast was actually pretty good. I didn't know what to expect going in, but the place looks almost brand new. They had a breakfast buffet going, but nothing besides fruit on the buffet was vegan. I started by ordering hash browns and wheat toast, but before the waitress left, I asked if they had oatmeal and swapped out the hash browns for a bowl of oatmeal and a bowl of fruit. Once again Luigi was waiting on me to finish, kind of the story of the trip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;KatyShakedown-31&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/chammond/50316772951/in/album-72157715879059516/&quot; data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;480&quot; alt=&quot;KatyShakedown-31&quot; src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/50316772951_b4e3ef62ec_z.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;KatyShakedown-32&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/chammond/50316772771/in/album-72157715879059516/&quot; data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;480&quot; alt=&quot;KatyShakedown-32&quot; src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/50316772771_f2352da6aa_z.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From there, it was pedal down to get back home before the heat of the day set in. We didn't quite make it before it got hot, but we got to at least Marthasville before I feel like I started slowing down again. Ultimately we made it back to Chesterfield just after 1pm, so our trip time was just under 6:15, including breaks and breakfast. Luigi ended up pulling me most of the way, both days actually. That guy is a machine, he just gets on his bike and rides. He never struggles, never looks to be working too hard, just chugs along. I tried my best to stay on his rear tire when I could, because it helped me to save on my energy and try to keep the pace better, but often times I would fall off and he would slow down until I caught back up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We felt as though we were into the wind both days, going west, it the wind was coming from the west, going east the wind was coming from the east. Our actual moving time on Saturday I think started out faster, but by the time we got half way I was drained and had a hard time. Sunday, we started out a little slower, but kept an overall better pace. My heart rate stayed below 140 for most of the ride, and if you follow Strava Suffer scores, the difference between two days was 582 on Saturday to 266 on Sunday. Sunday we had an average moving MPH of 13.8, while it was 13.3 on Saturday. My average heart rate on Saturday was 150bpm, Sunday was 135bpm. We did 1 additional mile on Saturday with the trek to the gas station. The moving time between the two days only differed by about 16 minutes, take out that extra mile on Saturday and we spent just about the same time on the trails moving. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Lessons learned from the trip&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;So it was a shake down ride, what did we learn from it?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;Hammock camping works.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Hammond packs too much stuff.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Luigi is a great guy to ride with as he will pull you the whole way.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Carry less snacks/fuel.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Buy more water.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Panaracer Gravelking tires are shit.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Don’t forget things (gopro memory card, spare tire)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;I carried way too many snacks and things for eating along the way. I don’t think that I consumed too much, but I definitely carried a lot. I need to be careful about what I pack and take on the bigger trip in October. We will plan better with water in October. I need to do some research on where we can source water along the way. All of the fountains on the Katy Trail are turned off, but I hear that spigots may be on, so I need to check a few out before October to see if that’s true. During our October ride, we will work to take on water any opportunity we can, to avoid being without.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tried to pack the essentials for my GoPro with three different trips to my basement office to get everything I needed, two trips specifically to get the memory card. Somehow I still managed to leave without the memory card. I turned the GoPro on as we set out from LeCave and was immediately beeped at telling me that I didn’t have a memory card in it. When we got to Portland I took the GoPro off to give to my wife to take home. It now had a cracked lens. So I rode with the camera on the front of the bike, but didn’t get to use it, and broke it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other things learned: I haven’t ridden as much as I wanted to this year, I have some serious concerns about my fitness for doing the Katy Trail in 3 days in 2020. We did it in 2017, but we didn’t carry our camping gear, or food along the way. I’m thinking about actually changing the ride plan to do a half day on the 1st of October, starting in Clinton, instead of starting in Clinton on Friday morning. We’ll see how the rest of the gang takes to that idea. I was likely dehydrated after the ride. I came home, had a soda, and not near enough water before going to bed. Until mid day on Monday I had to watch myself standing up to fast, starting to get dizzy. After making sure to consume a lot of water today I think that went away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall the shakedown ride proved a success. I have already transferred the gear that was in my saddlebags to my NEW gravel bags from Ortlieb, transferring everything from the Topeak setup into these new bags which are just saddlebags, and not a third center bag. They should hold up better, and allow me some flexibility to strap something down in the middle of the rack if I wish as well. I have new Maxxis tires that I will get mounted to the Niner RLT this week, and I need to make some adjustments to the shifters as I ran out of the ability to shift the big ring on Sunday as we got into Chesterfield valley.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll be working on planning the route based on things learned during this ride, making adjustments for food, water and hammock space availability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re on the Katy Trail October 1st through 4th, keep an eye out for my #MOGravel sticker, I will have some extras with me if anyone wants any.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;instagram-media&quot; style=&quot;background: rgb(255, 255, 255); margin: 1px; padding: 0px; border-radius: 3px; border: 0px currentcolor; width: calc(100% - 2px); min-width: 326px; max-width: 540px; box-shadow: 0px 0px 1px 0px rgba(0,0,0,0.5), 0px 1px 10px 0px rgba(0,0,0,0.15);&quot; data-instgrm-version=&quot;12&quot; data-instgrm-permalink=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/CE0MzELDm-n/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=loading&quot; data-instgrm-captioned=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding: 16px;&quot;&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;border-radius: 50%; width: 40px; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; background-color: rgb(244, 244, 244); flex-grow: 0;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;border-radius: 4px; width: 100px; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; background-color: rgb(244, 244, 244); flex-grow: 0;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;border-radius: 4px; width: 60px; height: 14px; background-color: rgb(244, 244, 244); flex-grow: 0;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding: 19% 0px;&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;margin: 0px auto 12px; width: 50px; height: 50px; display: block;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;background: rgb(255, 255, 255); padding: 0px; width: 100%; text-align: center; line-height: 0; text-decoration: none;&quot; href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/CE0MzELDm-n/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=loading&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;svg xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot; viewbox=&quot;0 0 60 60&quot; width=&quot;50px&quot; height=&quot;50px&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot;&gt;&lt;g fill=&quot;none&quot; fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; stroke=&quot;none&quot; stroke-width=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;g fill=&quot;#000000&quot; transform=&quot;translate(-511 -20)&quot;&gt;&lt;g&gt;&lt;path d=&quot;M 556.869 30.41 C 554.814 30.41 553.148 32.076 553.148 34.131 C 553.148 36.186 554.814 37.852 556.869 37.852 C 558.924 37.852 560.59 36.186 560.59 34.131 C 560.59 32.076 558.924 30.41 556.869 30.41 M 541 60.657 C 535.114 60.657 530.342 55.887 530.342 50 C 530.342 44.114 535.114 39.342 541 39.342 C 546.887 39.342 551.658 44.114 551.658 50 C 551.658 55.887 546.887 60.657 541 60.657 M 541 33.886 C 532.1 33.886 524.886 41.1 524.886 50 C 524.886 58.899 532.1 66.113 541 66.113 C 549.9 66.113 557.115 58.899 557.115 50 C 557.115 41.1 549.9 33.886 541 33.886 M 565.378 62.101 C 565.244 65.022 564.756 66.606 564.346 67.663 C 563.803 69.06 563.154 70.057 562.106 71.106 C 561.058 72.155 560.06 72.803 558.662 73.347 C 557.607 73.757 556.021 74.244 553.102 74.378 C 549.944 74.521 548.997 74.552 541 74.552 C 533.003 74.552 532.056 74.521 528.898 74.378 C 525.979 74.244 524.393 73.757 523.338 73.347 C 521.94 72.803 520.942 72.155 519.894 71.106 C 518.846 70.057 518.197 69.06 517.654 67.663 C 517.244 66.606 516.755 65.022 516.623 62.101 C 516.479 58.943 516.448 57.996 516.448 50 C 516.448 42.003 516.479 41.056 516.623 37.899 C 516.755 34.978 517.244 33.391 517.654 32.338 C 518.197 30.938 518.846 29.942 519.894 28.894 C 520.942 27.846 521.94 27.196 523.338 26.654 C 524.393 26.244 525.979 25.756 528.898 25.623 C 532.057 25.479 533.004 25.448 541 25.448 C 548.997 25.448 549.943 25.479 553.102 25.623 C 556.021 25.756 557.607 26.244 558.662 26.654 C 560.06 27.196 561.058 27.846 562.106 28.894 C 563.154 29.942 563.803 30.938 564.346 32.338 C 564.756 33.391 565.244 34.978 565.378 37.899 C 565.522 41.056 565.552 42.003 565.552 50 C 565.552 57.996 565.522 58.943 565.378 62.101 M 570.82 37.631 C 570.674 34.438 570.167 32.258 569.425 30.349 C 568.659 28.377 567.633 26.702 565.965 25.035 C 564.297 23.368 562.623 22.342 560.652 21.575 C 558.743 20.834 556.562 20.326 553.369 20.18 C 550.169 20.033 549.148 20 541 20 C 532.853 20 531.831 20.033 528.631 20.18 C 525.438 20.326 523.257 20.834 521.349 21.575 C 519.376 22.342 517.703 23.368 516.035 25.035 C 514.368 26.702 513.342 28.377 512.574 30.349 C 511.834 32.258 511.326 34.438 511.181 37.631 C 511.035 40.831 511 41.851 511 50 C 511 58.147 511.035 59.17 511.181 62.369 C 511.326 65.562 511.834 67.743 512.574 69.651 C 513.342 71.625 514.368 73.296 516.035 74.965 C 517.703 76.634 519.376 77.658 521.349 78.425 C 523.257 79.167 525.438 79.673 528.631 79.82 C 531.831 79.965 532.853 80.001 541 80.001 C 549.148 80.001 550.169 79.965 553.369 79.82 C 556.562 79.673 558.743 79.167 560.652 78.425 C 562.623 77.658 564.297 76.634 565.965 74.965 C 567.633 73.296 568.659 71.625 569.425 69.651 C 570.167 67.743 570.674 65.562 570.82 62.369 C 570.966 59.17 571 58.147 571 50 C 571 41.851 570.966 40.831 570.82 37.631&quot; /&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding-top: 8px;&quot;&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;color: rgb(56, 151, 240); line-height: 18px; font-family: arial,sans-serif; font-size: 14px; font-style: normal;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;background: rgb(255, 255, 255); padding: 0px; width: 100%; text-align: center; line-height: 0; text-decoration: none;&quot; href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/CE0MzELDm-n/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=loading&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;View this post on Instagram&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding: 12.5% 0px;&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;margin-bottom: 14px; display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;border-radius: 50%; width: 12.5px; height: 12.5px; transform: translatex(0px) translatey(7px); background-color: rgb(244, 244, 244);&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;width: 12.5px; height: 12.5px; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translatex(3px) translatey(1px); background-color: rgb(244, 244, 244); flex-grow: 0;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;border-radius: 50%; width: 12.5px; height: 12.5px; transform: translatex(9px) translatey(-18px); background-color: rgb(244, 244, 244);&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;margin-left: 8px;&quot;&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;border-radius: 50%; width: 20px; height: 20px; background-color: rgb(244, 244, 244); flex-grow: 0;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;width: 0px; height: 0px; border-top-color: transparent; border-bottom-color: transparent; border-left-color: rgb(244, 244, 244); border-top-width: 2px; border-bottom-width: 2px; border-left-width: 6px; border-top-style: solid; border-bottom-style: solid; border-left-style: solid; transform: translatex(16px) translatey(-4px) rotate(30deg);&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;margin-left: auto;&quot;&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;width: 0px; border-top-color: rgb(244, 244, 244); border-right-color: transparent; border-top-width: 8px; border-right-width: 8px; border-top-style: solid; border-right-style: solid; transform: translatey(16px);&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;width: 16px; height: 12px; transform: translatey(-4px); background-color: rgb(244, 244, 244); flex-grow: 0;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;width: 0px; height: 0px; border-top-color: rgb(244, 244, 244); border-left-color: transparent; border-top-width: 8px; border-left-width: 8px; border-top-style: solid; border-left-style: solid; transform: translatey(-4px) translatex(8px);&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;margin: 8px 0px 0px; padding: 0px 4px;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color: rgb(0, 0, 0); line-height: 17px; font-family: arial,sans-serif; font-size: 14px; font-style: normal; font-weight: normal; text-decoration: none; word-wrap: break-word;&quot; href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/CE0MzELDm-n/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=loading&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The film from the #katytrail #gravel #mogravel #gravelgrinder #ninerbikes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;padding: 8px 0px 7px; text-align: center; color: rgb(201, 200, 205); line-height: 17px; overflow: hidden; font-family: arial,sans-serif; font-size: 14px; margin-top: 8px; margin-bottom: 0px; white-space: nowrap; text-overflow: ellipsis;&quot;&gt;A post shared by &lt;a style=&quot;color: rgb(201, 200, 205); line-height: 17px; font-family: arial,sans-serif; font-size: 14px; font-style: normal; font-weight: normal;&quot; href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/thechristoc/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=loading&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; Chris Hammond&lt;/a&gt; (@thechristoc) on &lt;time style=&quot;line-height: 17px; font-family: arial,sans-serif; font-size: 14px;&quot; datetime=&quot;2020-09-07T00:43:23+00:00&quot;&gt;Sep 6, 2020 at 5:43pm PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;script async src=&quot;//www.instagram.com/embed.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Photo Gallery&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;Katy Trail Shakedown Ride&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/chammond/albums/72157715879059516&quot; data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;600&quot; alt=&quot;Katy Trail Shakedown Ride&quot; src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/50316112438_c7c0852d89_c.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 05:06:30 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/2020-katy-trail-shakedown-ride</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2020-katy-trail-shakedown-ride</guid>
        
        
        <category>Bicycle Tips</category>
        
        <category>Equipment</category>
        
        <category>Tips</category>
        
        <category>Travel</category>
        
        <category>Trips</category>
        
        <category>Bike Packing</category>
        
        <category>Camping</category>
        
        <category>Gravel</category>
        
        <category>Missouri</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Dirty Kanza 2020 has been postponed, what about your hotel?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;So Dirty Kanza had their &amp;ldquo;virtual gravel camp&amp;rdquo; this weekend. Going into this, I figured it would be leading up to something. Some change, I assumed a cancellation for 2020 and reschedule for 2021, due to coronavirus. I was wrong (I am glad I was), this evening they announced that they were moving the ride to September 12th, 2020.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://dirtykanza.com/2020-dirty-kanza-postponement-faqs/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of information on the FAQ&lt;/a&gt;, my completely unofficial summary for those who are already registered for 2020:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol&gt; &lt;li&gt;You can ride on 9/12, without changing anything about your reservation&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;You can defer to 2021 (6/5/2021) without any fee, and not having to pay again next year) if you do so by 5/15/2020.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;You can get a refund for your 2020 entry fee, if you choose to do so by 5/15/2020, but you will need to enter the lotto again for 2021.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you aren&amp;rsquo;t registered for 2020, but want to, at this point, I don&amp;rsquo;t believe that&amp;rsquo;s an option. Will it stay that way, who knows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I quickly looked through the FAQ (linked above) earlier and realized, crap, my hotel reservation is for the original weekend. I booked that hotel in the middle of June 2019, just weeks after DK 2019. I immediately logged into my hotel honors account and looked to try to change my reservation. No dice, the hotel is completely blocked from 9/9/2020 through 9/13/2020.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I checked every hotel I could in Emporia, they are ALL Blocked that week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was despondent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to try to call the hotel, at 9:20pm on a Sunday night, in the middle of Coronavirus lockdowns. I got a remote reservation agent, she checked, she couldn&amp;rsquo;t find me a spot either, the hotel is blocked off. She offered to call the front desk and see, so I took her up on that offer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After quite a hold, she came back and told me that the hotel is currently blocked off, BUT, they were taking names and going to be calling people back. It sounds like, and remember this is completely unofficial, and possibly wrong, they might actually be blocking that week for existing reservations from the original dates, to move them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was told that they would call me back this week, and see about moving the reservations for me. &lt;strong&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m extremely hopeful that this works out!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My advice: Call your hotel, see if they are doing something similar, hopefully for you they are! I have a feeling that hotel space, as always, will be a premium, especially with the new date and school being in session at the college, where they normally open up dorm rooms for DK participants to use in late May/early June.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update 4/6/2020:&lt;/strong&gt; I was able to get in touch with my hotel this morning and they moved my reservation. The rate is quite a bit higher, but at this point I wasn&amp;#39;t going to argue.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update 4/8/2020:&lt;/strong&gt; I reached out to the hotel again via their online chat, they talked to the manager, who then emailed me. I was inquiring about the rate that has doubled my overall cost for loding for DK 2020.&amp;nbsp; Basically they said:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;They were already charging this rate before DK moved, there is another event in town that same weekend, and with the dorms unavailable, and a hotel having recently closed down completely, rooms are at a premium...&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;So at this point I don&amp;#39;t have any belief that I&amp;#39;ll get my rate lowered down to less than $299 a night that we are currently being charged. That being said, I do have two rooms right now, long term I might not hold on to that second room, but I am keeping both depending on who all comes and rides, if more friends get in, or my wife decides to help crew, I need the extra space.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2020 03:25:03 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/dirty-kanza-2020-has-been-postponed-what-about-your-hotel</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/dirty-kanza-2020-has-been-postponed-what-about-your-hotel</guid>
        
        
        <category>Bicycle Tips</category>
        
        <category>Travel</category>
        
        <category>Trips</category>
        
        <category>Gravel</category>
        
        <category>Dirty Kanza</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Mid South 2020 Ride Review</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Mid South 2020 was held in Stillwater, Oklahoma on March 14th, 2020. Team Bicycle Tips was represented by Chris^3 (Chris Cubed, Chris Hammond, Chris Lybarger and Chris Wagner).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chaotic times we are in, this chaos leads to delays in doing ride reviews, so here we are, 16 days after The Mid South, and here we go. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;The Mid South 2020&quot; href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/chammond/albums/72157713688711937&quot; data-footer=&quot;true&quot; data-header=&quot;true&quot; data-flickr-embed=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;480&quot; alt=&quot;The Mid South 2020&quot; src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/65535/49717081612_bd149bf5c7_z.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;script async src=&quot;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where to start? I don’t even know where to start… Let’s start back in January. On January 8th, I, Hammond, got let go from my VP of Product Management role with a SaaS company here in St. Louis that built and managed software for the fitness industry. At this time, I was personally ready for the change in career, and was setup to be able to not need to find a job quickly. I took this opportunity to try to make some changes in my life, one of those changes was to start riding the trainer in prep for The Mid South, the other was to change my diet to a full vegan diet, with whole plant based non-processed foods.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the month of January was able to get some good training in, 278 miles either on the trainer, or outside on the bike. Starting in February though, my training dropped off, I only got 155 miles in, with the first training ride being the 10th of the month. On the 16th of the month, I rode the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bicycletips.com/home/2020/02/2020-prairie-roubaix-100k-rural-assault-ride&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;2020 Prairie Roubaix 100k Rural Assault Ride&lt;/a&gt; in St. James, MO. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the early weeks of March came to be, the world started to buzz about the coronavirus, and the week before The Mid South, news started talking about the risk of the virus. As the week progressed, things started to change quickly, emails from The Mid South said that they would not be cancelling, and the ride would continue, but offering up “deferrals” to riders who wanted to defer to ride in 2021 instead of 2020 (having to pay the entry cost again though). We left for Stillwater Oklahoma from St. Louis the morning of Friday the 13th, and on the way down listened to President Trump address the nation. We honestly thought they were going to shut the country down, and we would simply turn around and drive the 6 hours back.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;The President Speaks&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;None of that came to fruition, and we made it to Stillwater mid-afternoon. We checked in for the ride, walked around the expo. The Expo was fairly well spread out, but it was windy, so the vendors were having to battle gusts trying to take down their displays and pop up tents. The expo was no where near the size of the Dirty Kanza expo in 2019, but I don’t know how much of that is just the size of the event or due to changes with Coronavirus. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After perusing the expo we decided to take a drive out of town and check out what the surface we would be riding the following day looked like. It was shortly after 5pm. We drove about 6 miles of the route, and we were pleased, the roads were dry as a bone. We took a photo or two, and then went to check in to our hotel. We didn’t eat dinner, because we were short on time, and wanted to be at the rider’s meeting at 7pm, and figured it would be done by 730 and we’d head out to grab a bite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the time we arrived back to the street outside of District Bicycles, just before 7, it was raining and very cold. We stood around in the rain, fortunately with umbrellas, but social distancing ourselves from other attendees. There was a band on the stage when we arrived, we figured they must be running long and the rider’s meeting would happen after they played. Long story short, it was 8:20pm or so before the guy (Bobby) who was going to conduct the meeting was up on stage. He was setting up with ANOTHER band. Did I mention it was raining now? Those dry roads at 6pm, were getting drenched, and it was COLD (low 30s), and we were getting very hangry. After the band started playing, with no rider’s meeting announcements having occurred, we took off, it was time to eat, warm up, dry off, and get some sleep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For dinner we headed over to Elm Ave, to check out The Garage Burgers &amp;amp; Beer. I found an impossible burger that worked to fit my diet while the other Chris(es) found burgers to fit their needs. The Garage is right across the street from Eskimo Joes, which Wagner was enamored by, due to it’s “fame”. I’ll be honest, I’m not sure I had ever heard of Eskimo Joes, but he claimed it to be famous and pointed out that they were known for T-Shirts. We thought it was an ice cream bar, so we figured we might give it a try on Saturday night (more on that later).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Up and At ‘em&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Saturday morning we got up early to find that the Hampton Inn was FULL of Mid South riders, and the breakfast offerings were slim due to the demand of everyone up at 6am trying to get out the door. I had brought my own oatmeal along, so I fixed that while Wagner got in line to grab something from breakfast choices. The hotel went out of their way to try to make the best of things, so they were restocking as fast as they could.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We then headed to downtown Stillwater to get ourselves ready for the ride. We found a good parking spot, right near where we had parked the previous day, and sat in the Tahoe for a few minutes. It was pouring rain, and there was plenty of standing water and even streams running down the streets. It had been raining all night, with signs of letting up LATE morning. Things were not looking good. The ride was supposed to start at 8am, but around 730am or so they announced that they were pushing the start back to 830. Took our time getting things ready, I ran off to the port-a-lou and tried to make my day a little more comfortable. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the way back to the Tahoe I stepped in a big old puddle, completely soaking my shoe/foot. That prompted me to change socks before we even started riding. About 815 we made our way over to the starting area, it was packed. The night before we had seen maybe 100 people standing around for the rider’s meeting, that led me to believe that the ride would be small and attendance had been damped drastically by #Covid19. I was mistaken. There were probably two thousand people waiting to get started, and a few hundred townsfolk there to see us all off. There was no social distancing this morning, it was cold, it was pouring rain, and we were packed together.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Heading Out&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;About 8:36am I think I crossed the line and headed out on to the course. The route started with (if I recall correctly) 2 miles of paved roads, and then quickly turned into MUCK. The very roads we drove the night before, that were pristine and perfect, were now a sloppy mess. And it only got worse from there. I really wish I could have seen what things looked like for the riders at the front of the group, but I am not anywhere near a rider of that caliber so we got to see the course after 1k other people rode through it first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We made it to Mile 12 (at right about 1 hour into our ride) and decided that it was a good place to stop to refill, and empty the bladder. With the conditions, it was discussed that there would be no refueling while riding, you simply had to maintain control of your bike at all times, there was no down time to try to grab something to eat, or to try to take a drink, even from a Camelbak. While stopped, a young lady pulled up and grabbed her phone, she immediately called the SAG line and asked for a ride back, she was done. I honestly can’t blame her, she said it was her first 100 mile bike race, and there was no way she was prepped for these conditions. I had wished she had gone further, but she was probably one of the smarter folks to actually started the ride. The SMARTEST people were likely the ones who didn’t even start at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing I quickly figured out, nothing was going to stay clean on this ride, including my phone. So you’ll see only a few photos in the gallery above. I had intended to take more photos, but it simply didn’t happen, and the ones I did take were often smudged with mud.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can’t even begin to describe the mud. Oklahoma is known for red clay, and these roads, with 1k+ riders were TORE up. The mud was 5-6” deep at times. It got on everything. If you couldn’t keep pedaling, and had to walk, your bike quickly added weight. That weight came in the form of red clay, and frequently got so bad that it acted like brakes being applied, the mud would pule up in the fork and the tire would continue to throw mud into that fork causing everything to come to a halt. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We made it to around Mile 14 where the first closed road/bridge crossing was, the bridge was passable, but you had to get off your bike and haul it up and over concrete put in place to keep vehicles off both sides of the bridge. The further we went along, the worse the roads got. At a couple of points we came across 50 mile course diversions, and at one point we stopped to discuss whether we should abandon the 100 mile route and jump on the 50 mile route. We continued to truck on with the 100 mile route however. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Some Of The Conditions&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;As the roads got worse, people were walking through the grass on the side of the road, even that surface was soft and mushy, and hard to walk on. Early on people started having problems with their bikes, ripping off derailleurs, losing braking ability, and various other ailments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The surface overall was simply bad. So sloppy and muddy. If you could manage to try to ride in someone else’s track you might be able to keep your momentum up, but if you got off the line (and many places the lines were non-existent) you were screwed. I don’t know how many times I yelled “oh shit oh shit oh shit” as I was riding along about to completely lose it, the brand new (almost) Panaracer Gravel Kings barely able to keep the bike upright.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many times going down hills I would pass someone with their feet dragging, trying to slow themselves down because there brakes were gone. I thought, how is it possible that all these people are having braking problems. Well, later I would find out. I experienced brake problems of my own.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Time For A Bath&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;At one point, I’m guessing around Mile 37, we came across a farm that had a hose out, people were taking the opportunity to wash their bikes off. I took the opportunity to rest and wait in line to wash my bike off. There were two farm dogs hanging out with all their new bicyclist friends, enjoying the pets that came as people waited for the hose. Not 5 minutes later my bike was completely covered again as if I hadn’t wasted 15 minutes waiting in line to wash it. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we were going up a hill not too far after this farm, I saw a truck at the top of the hill, it was pointing towards us, and I secretly, almost audibly, hoped it was a shuttle bus and would offer us a ride home. It was not, it was some sort of milk/tanker truck, slowly making his way down a really nasty part of road, that on an average day was likely okay, but today was sketchy at best. (More on him later.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After about 5 hours we had gone a total of 38 miles, averaging less than 8 miles an hour. We came to a paved road, one of the few that we’d seen up to this point, maybe the first since we touched dirt. We were heading west towards Perkins, OK. The road ran North/South, and would take us back towards Stillwater and other paved roads. If we decided we wanted out, it would be the path of least resistance for returning to the start. The three of us talked about it, and Lybarger decided he was going to keep going, so off he went. Wagner and I were discussing what to do, thinking we were going to try to keep going to Perkins. Next thing you know a red Chevy Colorado pulls up and asks us if we want a ride back to Stillwater. Yes, sold, take us home. We were done, and this opportunity provided us our out. We shouted to Lybarger who came back to us for a discussion. The truck could take 3 bikes, and 3 riders, but Lybarger decided he as going to keep going. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Abandoned&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Wagner and I loaded up, and spent the next 30 minutes riding around with two guys from Colorado who were looking to fill the extra spot on the bike rack before taking us back up to Stillwater, which would be about a 30 minute drive. Come to find out that the gentleman who picked us up was &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.usacycling.org/about-us/team&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Chuck Hodge, the Chief of Racing and Events for USA Cycling&lt;/a&gt;. He spoke about how pretty much every other USA Cycling event for the next 5-6 weeks was being cancelled, or had already been cancelled, and this was likely the last for quite some time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We came across a few riders who could use a ride, but none chose to do so. One guy had just recently gone head first over his handlebars and cut his chin. Chuck got of the truck, grabbed a first aid kit cut, cleaned him up, and offered him a ride. He chose to continue. Another gentleman that we had passed while riding, was walking his bike west. He had broken his bike, but he already had someone coming to pick him up, so he kept going towards the road ahead.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Nope That’s Not It&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;We turned north (we had been heading east backtracking on the course), asking riders if they wanted help, and came across a lady stopped in the middle of the road to refuel. She was in the middle of nowhere, in fact, she was not even on the course, she had missed a turn. We informed her of this, and she questioned our sanity. She couldn’t believe she was in the wrong. We told her how to easily get back on course, she wasn’t far from the actual course. She was offered a ride, an out, but she chose to keep riding. We end up coming back towards the course and were going to drive back out the road we had come east on, towards the paved road where we were picked up, when we could see the Milk Truck off in the distance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was climbing the hill, or attempting to, that it had been coming down when we passed it about an hour earlier, it was now stuck. It did not appear that it was going to make it up that hill, and there was no way that we believed we could get the Chevy Colorado around it due to the way it was lodged in the road. Chuck called this in on race radio to let organizers know, and we headed south to try to find another way around and back to the course. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the location where Chuck had picked us up, we came across another rider, from Kansas, who had walked 2 miles back, to get to that point. He had ripped his derailleur off, and needed a ride back. Golden, we had our 3 bikes, 3 riders, and a ride back to Stillwater. Chuck end up dropping Wagner and the other rider off at our hotel. The idea being that Wagner could work on cleaning his bike (the hotel had a hose out front for this purpose) and I could head back to the Tahoe. I figured I was going to need to drive to Perkins in the Tahoe to get Lybarger. Chuck dropped me off near the finish line and I grabbed my bike, and backpack (but not my helmet) from the back of his truck, along with a selfie. I went over to the Tahoe to get my bike loaded up and a somewhat clean change of clothes put on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was right about Lybarger, he had spent the 2 hours since we split from him, riding 12 miles into Perkins. They had closed up the aid station and most people were trying to find rides back to Stillwater. On my way down to Perkins I passed probably 30 riders who were all heading north towards Stillwater, riders who had chosen to abandon the ride and take paved roads back to civilization. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I dropped Lybarger off at his hotel and headed over to my hotel to try to get my bike, and myself cleaned up. That evening we headed back downtown and hung out around the finish line for a bit. We grabbed some additional swag (one thing about The Mid South, they had a ton of swag, and with the lowered attendance due to coronavirus, there was plenty of extra).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Dinner With Joe&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;We then headed back to Elm Ave to visit Eskimo Joes for dinner. It ends up Eskimo Joes is bar and grill, a very large one, with a huge merchandise store, with hundreds of Eskimo Joe apparel items, and while they might sell some ice cream for desert, they are not an ice cream shop. They started out as a bar in the 70s, and added food after the drinking age was changed from 18 to 21. The food was okay, nothing fancy for my vegan palate. I had another impossible burger to continue to stick to my vegan diet, that was pretty much the only thing on the menu that would fit that requirement. I ended up picking up a couple of shirts, &lt;a href=&quot;https://eskimojoes.com/faqs/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;since EJ’s is apparently known for their T-Shirts&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sunday morning we loaded up the Tahoe, grabbed some breakfast at the Hampton Inn and hit the road for the 6.5 hour drive back to St. Louis. We stopped in Springfield MO for lunch, and picked up a few grocery items as we were hearing that more and more things were becoming scarce in St. Louis. We drove through Rolla and I pointed out a few of my old college haunts to Wagner.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;The Mid Summary&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;While initially we were disappointed that we abandoned the ride, we were not the only ones, there were hundreds, I imagine (wild ass guess) over 50%, probably close to 75%, of the entrants who entered, abandoned. The conditions were that brutal. That being said, while we were riding, besides the mental breaking down that the mud caused, we had a blast. Everyone was friendly and muddy together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even with the lower attendance, and the much smaller festivities in town, and the very very very poor route conditions, no regrets were had for attending and attempting to ride the ride. The only thing I think we would have changed, we would have early on decided to do the 50 mile route, and attempted to complete that. 100 Miles simply wasn’t going to happen for us on the 14th of March 2020. Averaging less than 8 miles an hour for 5 hours was not going to get us to 100 miles. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;The Aftermath&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;While we had fun, and we made our bikes dirty, we also did some damage. While nothing “broke” during the ride, that I knew of, my brake pads (new in January) were shot and needed replaced. I also had to replace my bottom bracket, my rear shift/brake lever and complete replacement of all cables. Ultimately I had about $500 in repairs/parts completed on my bike as a result of The Mid South, so it was an expensive 38 mile Saturday bike ride...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Would we recommend it in 2021? If you can get in, absolutely. But if there is any rain, or it rains for 16 hours straight starting at 6pm on Friday night before the ride, go into it with gear that you don’t mind just completely trashing, or stay in your hotel and sleep instead.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 15:24:21 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/the-mid-south-2020-ride-review</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/the-mid-south-2020-ride-review</guid>
        
        
        <category>Tips</category>
        
        <category>Travel</category>
        
        <category>Trips</category>
        
        <category>Gravel</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>New Gear: Salsa Woodchipper Carbon</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: This is not a paid advertisement, these bars were purchased by BicycleTips.com via our local bike shop at retail. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last weekend we got out to the Prairie Roubaix 100k Rural Assault Ride down in St. James, MO. A few days before the ride I picked the Niner RLT up from Trailhead Bicycles after getting a mid winter tune up and new bars installed!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometime last year I decided I was going to upgrade my bike in 2020, initially that meant replacing it, I was thinking about trying to fork over the cash for&amp;nbsp; Niner RLT MCR, but after seeing that they are limited in the size of the frames that they have (I&amp;rsquo;m 6&amp;rsquo; 4&amp;rdquo;) I decided that I would stick with the current bike and look at doing some upgrades to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing I decided was the &lt;a href=&quot;https://salsacycles.com/components/category/road_handlebars/woodchipper_carbon&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Salsa Woodchipper Carbon bars&lt;/a&gt;, in 44mm. I had them wrapped in Fi&amp;rsquo;zi:k bar tape, a mint/olive color which I thought was the best option (available in the shop) to go along with my orange/white RLT. I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to do black on the bars this time around, and might change the tape up before Dirty Kanza.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So a quick review on the bars, after doing 100k on Sunday:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found that going down into the drops was an experience, once I got used to it, I loved it, but it was definitely wide and felt odd at first. Reaching the brakes can be a little struggle at first, but once you get the feel for it I think it is much better. The overall ride was better, it was a cold ride, so I had my winter gloves on, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t experience any numbness or reduced grip strength as I have in previous long rides.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve still got a lot of training to do, and The Mid South coming up, so we&amp;rsquo;ll see how my hands hold up as we get into some real distance in the coming months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re looking for a nice upgrade for your current ride, be sure to check out the Salsa Woodchipper.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&quot;instagram-media&quot; data-instgrm-permalink=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/B8j3hUAJzF2/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=loading&quot; data-instgrm-version=&quot;12&quot; style=&quot; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:540px; min-width:326px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&quot;&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding:16px;&quot;&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/B8j3hUAJzF2/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=loading&quot; style=&quot; background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding: 19% 0;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;display:block; height:50px; margin:0 auto 12px; width:50px;&quot;&gt;&lt;svg width=&quot;50px&quot; height=&quot;50px&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 60 60&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; xmlns=&quot;https://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot; xmlns:xlink=&quot;https://www.w3.org/1999/xlink&quot;&gt;&lt;g stroke=&quot;none&quot; stroke-width=&quot;1&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot;&gt;&lt;g transform=&quot;translate(-511.000000, -20.000000)&quot; fill=&quot;#000000&quot;&gt;&lt;g&gt;&lt;path d=&quot;M556.869,30.41 C554.814,30.41 553.148,32.076 553.148,34.131 C553.148,36.186 554.814,37.852 556.869,37.852 C558.924,37.852 560.59,36.186 560.59,34.131 C560.59,32.076 558.924,30.41 556.869,30.41 M541,60.657 C535.114,60.657 530.342,55.887 530.342,50 C530.342,44.114 535.114,39.342 541,39.342 C546.887,39.342 551.658,44.114 551.658,50 C551.658,55.887 546.887,60.657 541,60.657 M541,33.886 C532.1,33.886 524.886,41.1 524.886,50 C524.886,58.899 532.1,66.113 541,66.113 C549.9,66.113 557.115,58.899 557.115,50 C557.115,41.1 549.9,33.886 541,33.886 M565.378,62.101 C565.244,65.022 564.756,66.606 564.346,67.663 C563.803,69.06 563.154,70.057 562.106,71.106 C561.058,72.155 560.06,72.803 558.662,73.347 C557.607,73.757 556.021,74.244 553.102,74.378 C549.944,74.521 548.997,74.552 541,74.552 C533.003,74.552 532.056,74.521 528.898,74.378 C525.979,74.244 524.393,73.757 523.338,73.347 C521.94,72.803 520.942,72.155 519.894,71.106 C518.846,70.057 518.197,69.06 517.654,67.663 C517.244,66.606 516.755,65.022 516.623,62.101 C516.479,58.943 516.448,57.996 516.448,50 C516.448,42.003 516.479,41.056 516.623,37.899 C516.755,34.978 517.244,33.391 517.654,32.338 C518.197,30.938 518.846,29.942 519.894,28.894 C520.942,27.846 521.94,27.196 523.338,26.654 C524.393,26.244 525.979,25.756 528.898,25.623 C532.057,25.479 533.004,25.448 541,25.448 C548.997,25.448 549.943,25.479 553.102,25.623 C556.021,25.756 557.607,26.244 558.662,26.654 C560.06,27.196 561.058,27.846 562.106,28.894 C563.154,29.942 563.803,30.938 564.346,32.338 C564.756,33.391 565.244,34.978 565.378,37.899 C565.522,41.056 565.552,42.003 565.552,50 C565.552,57.996 565.522,58.943 565.378,62.101 M570.82,37.631 C570.674,34.438 570.167,32.258 569.425,30.349 C568.659,28.377 567.633,26.702 565.965,25.035 C564.297,23.368 562.623,22.342 560.652,21.575 C558.743,20.834 556.562,20.326 553.369,20.18 C550.169,20.033 549.148,20 541,20 C532.853,20 531.831,20.033 528.631,20.18 C525.438,20.326 523.257,20.834 521.349,21.575 C519.376,22.342 517.703,23.368 516.035,25.035 C514.368,26.702 513.342,28.377 512.574,30.349 C511.834,32.258 511.326,34.438 511.181,37.631 C511.035,40.831 511,41.851 511,50 C511,58.147 511.035,59.17 511.181,62.369 C511.326,65.562 511.834,67.743 512.574,69.651 C513.342,71.625 514.368,73.296 516.035,74.965 C517.703,76.634 519.376,77.658 521.349,78.425 C523.257,79.167 525.438,79.673 528.631,79.82 C531.831,79.965 532.853,80.001 541,80.001 C549.148,80.001 550.169,79.965 553.369,79.82 C556.562,79.673 558.743,79.167 560.652,78.425 C562.623,77.658 564.297,76.634 565.965,74.965 C567.633,73.296 568.659,71.625 569.425,69.651 C570.167,67.743 570.674,65.562 570.82,62.369 C570.966,59.17 571,58.147 571,50 C571,41.851 570.966,40.831 570.82,37.631&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding-top: 8px;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; color:#3897f0; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:550; line-height:18px;&quot;&gt; View this post on Instagram&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding: 12.5% 0;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #F4F4F4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;margin-left: 8px;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg)&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;margin-left: auto;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background-color: #F4F4F4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center; margin-bottom: 24px;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 224px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 144px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/B8j3hUAJzF2/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=loading&quot; style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;A post shared by Chris Hammond (@thechristoc)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&quot; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&quot; datetime=&quot;2020-02-14T20:18:27+00:00&quot;&gt;Feb 14, 2020 at 12:18pm PST&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async src=&quot;//www.instagram.com/embed.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2020 16:46:19 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/new-gear-salsa-woodchipper-carbon</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/new-gear-salsa-woodchipper-carbon</guid>
        
        
        <category>Equipment</category>
        
        <category>Industry</category>
        
        <category>Gravel</category>
        
        <category>Dirty Kanza</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
