<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="https://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>BicycleTips.com</title>
    <description>A cycling website dedicated to bringing you the latest tips, tricks, product and ride reviews, primarily focused on gravel cycling.</description>
    <link>https://www.bicycletips.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://www.bicycletips.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 17:07:49 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 17:07:49 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.3.4</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title></title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Dark Morning&quot; src=&quot;/portals/18/Content/1-5-12-Goals_337.jpg&quot; style=&quot;float: right;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For 2011 I personally set 3 goals, you can read about them fully on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.chrishammond.com/blog/itemid/2048/2010-year-in-review-and-whatrsquos-coming-in-201.aspx&quot;&gt;my post from 1/1/2011&lt;/a&gt;. Basically they were to lose 30 lbs (goal weight of 255, I&apos;m a big guy), inline skate 100 miles (I do like me some skating, I&apos;m a freak I know this) and ride a bike 500 miles. At the beginning of 2011 the bike I had was a 2004 Diamondback XTS Moto, not exactly something you could see yourself riding 500 miles on (at least not me). So in June I picked up a Cannondale Quick CX 1 and began my journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I posted back in November, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bicycletips.com/tips/aid/16&quot;&gt;I met the goal of riding 500 miles on the bike&lt;/a&gt;, and I fully intended to hit the skating goal of 100 miles. I am sad to say however, that I didn&apos;t skate 100 miles, and I didn&apos;t lose 30lbs last year, more like 7lbs. The weight was a rather lofty goal, but skating was definitely doable. I did manage to skate ~55 miles, but I really fell in love with cycling last year, so the skating definitely fell by the way side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My final bicycling total for 2011 was &lt;strong&gt;572.36 miles&lt;/strong&gt;, and while looking at other people&apos;s riding numbers, it isn&apos;t much, it was a great achievement for me, and hopefully a great start to many years of riding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For 2012 I am setting some new goals, but this time I am not going to say &quot;I want to lost the remaining 23lbs (I did lose/keep off 7lbs in 2011). I am not going to set any inline skating goals, while I hope to still skate some in 2012. I am also not going to set an official mileage goal, though I would think that 12-1500 should be doable with the other goals listed below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am going to set the following goals, and hopefully they will help me towards getting in shape and losing weight, the weight is not the focus. With all of the following goals, I would hope that I can find some friends, or make some new ones, that want to participate with me. If so, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bicycletips.com/about&quot;&gt;please use the Contact form on the About page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LiveSTRONG Challenge Davis Century Ride, Davis, CA, June 2012 (&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.livestrong.org/Take-Action/Team-LIVESTRONG-Events/Ride/Team-LIVESTRONG-Challenge-Davis&quot;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt; My primary goal is to participate in the LiveSTRONG Challenge in Davis California on June 24, 2012. I am planning to attempt the 100 mile ride that hot day in June, in order to do this, I have a lot of training to do. As part of the LiveSTRONG Challenge I am working to raise money to raise awareness and fight cancer, it hit close to home in 2011 as my father was diagnosed with prostate cancer. You can donate to my fund raising at &lt;a href=&quot;https://laf.livestrong.org/goto/chrishammond&quot;&gt;https://laf.livestrong.org/goto/chrishammond&lt;/a&gt; I appreciate any and all donations, no matter how large or small! If you are interested in riding with me (please do) you can join &lt;a href=&quot;https://laf.livestrong.org/site/TR/Challenge/General?pg=team&amp;amp;fr_id=1181&amp;amp;team_id=1581&quot;&gt;Team DotNetNuke&lt;/a&gt; for the challenge, even if you don&apos;t want to ride the 100 mile ride, you can do a shorter distance as part of the challenge.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wine Country Metric Century, Santa Rosa, CA May 2012 (&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://srcc.memberlodge.com/Default.aspx?pageId=750791&quot;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;) &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt; In May of 2012 I plan to partake tin the Wine Country Century (metric) put on by the Santa Rosa Cycling Club. I hope that this will be right in line with my LiveSTRONG training, 62 miles on a Saturday in early May. Registration for this opens in February 2012, so hopefully I can get in as there is a limit to the number of registrants.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tierra Bella 2012 60k, Gilroy, CA April 2012 (&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tierrabella.org/tb_reg.php&quot;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;) &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt; As prep for the above to events I hope to take part in the 60k route of the 2012 Tierra Bella bike ride put on by the Almaden Cycle Touring Club near Gilroy California. This will be around 35 miles. Registration is open, though I haven&apos;t yet registered as I am waiting to see if my wife is going to participate in this as well.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Marin Triathlon (sprint), Marin County, CA, November 2012 (&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://marintriathlon.com/&quot;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;) &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt; To close out the year, I am planning to participate in my first triathlon. I&apos;m not a runner, not really a fan of it, I used to swim a lot as a kid, so I am hoping that with the riding to get ready for the LiveSTRONG Challenge I will manage to get in shape enough that I can take part in and complete my first sprint triathlon. My wife is also likely going to do this one as well.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;Following my goals? Well, you can follow my rides and stats by checking out my &lt;a href=&quot;https://app.strava.com/athletes/194984&quot;&gt;Strava.com profile&lt;/a&gt;. I&apos;ll be doing another writeup here in the next week on strava.com and why I think it is the best website for tracking rides, and even finding new ones. I just signed up for it about a week ago, and I am totally addicted to it now. Stay tuned for that post.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 17:07:49 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.bicycletips.com/2012-01-06-setting-goals-for-2012/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bicycletips.com/2012-01-06-setting-goals-for-2012/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What to look for at Unbound Gravel 2024</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I won’t be at Unbound Gravel this year (I’ve been on the bike all of 2 times since December 31st) but I am getting the itch to be in Emporia Kansas this week, it’s Unbound time!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If this is your first time to Emporia, here’s a little bit of what you can expect based on my previous visits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Get there early! You’re going to want time to do some of the things below.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Get out on group rides! There are plenty of group rides going on this week. Join a couple of them. Most of them are not long/complex rides, but can be a good intro to some of the course that you’ll see in the 50/100/200 mile rides on Saturday. You might also get some sponsor swag at their organized group rides too.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;No you don’t need to actually be entered into Unbound Gravel to enter some of these group rides! Check with organizers to be sure.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lots of sponsor swag! Keep on the look out if you like collecting things. Anyone want to see my bandana collection from DK/Unbound? I don’t even know what to do with them all.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;EXPO, this is the big one. The All Things Gravel Expo is a must see event! It has limited hours, only on Thursday and Friday, you won’t find it on Saturday or Sunday!
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Thursday, May 30, 2024   2:00 PM – 7:00 PM&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Friday, May 31, 2024     10:00 AM – 5:00 PM&lt;br /&gt;
  Definitely get out there and check if out. If you like swag this is the place to be. You can find t-shirts, bottles, food samples, bandanas and who knows what else as giveaways, and you can purchase even more!&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Some of the Emporia local shops are great, check them out! Also be sure to check out Daylight Donuts if they are still open, holy flaky goodness. Merchant Cycles is absolutely worth a stop as well.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Be sure to attend/watch the rider’s meeting for important info.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Check in early to get everything you need for your ride, and make sure you’ve got a plan for where/how you are meeting your support crew! YOU NEED A SUPPORT CREW and a PLAN.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After your finish your ride you’re going to want to take part in the bike washing stations!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take care of yourselves out there, be preapred, be ready for anything, and most of all, just enjoy the week! You’re in for it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope to see you out there again next year.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 10:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.bicycletips.com/unbound-gravel-2024</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bicycletips.com/unbound-gravel-2024</guid>
        
        
        <category>Bike</category>
        
        <category>Gravel</category>
        
        <category>2024</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Coming in 2024, and 2023 a year in review</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;So here we are, another year later. 2023 wasn’t much in terms of riding, but I’ll get to that in a bit. 2023 was quite the adventure from a family perspective. Both my parents were in memory care most of the year, fortunately in apartments side by side. In early summer my father really started struggling, had a couple of falls and spent time in the ER and hospital recovering. By the end of summer he had another couple of falls and ultimately a stroke took him from us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall the family held up well during this time, but it was not without stress and struggle to get through most of the year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I haven’t actually ridden my bike since September 17th. At that point I still had plans to ride Big Sugar Gravel in Bentonville Arkansas a month later. That didn’t happen, along with Unbound Gravel, I managed to not make either of the scheduled rides I had for the year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what did get accomplished on the bike this year? Almost 50% less riding than 2022, and only 1/4 of the riding from 2020! Here’s a simple breakdown.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;2023-bike-riding-stats&quot;&gt;2023 Bike Riding Stats&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;37 Rides&lt;br /&gt;
507.5 Miles&lt;br /&gt;
8,790’ of elevation&lt;br /&gt;
42 hours&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So overall, a pretty down year! But 2024 will be different! I hope.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve only got one scheduled ride so far this year, but it’s another big one, 100 miles at Unbound Gravel in June.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How am I going to ensure I get to participate this year? Well, hopefully my riding buddies will help me be accountable! Wigs and Wags are both planning on being there, though Wags will be there as our support crew.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hope to see you out on the bike!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 09:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.bicycletips.com/2023-year-in-review</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bicycletips.com/2023-year-in-review</guid>
        
        
        <category>Bike</category>
        
        <category>Gravel</category>
        
        <category>2023</category>
        
        <category>2024</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Unbound Gravel 2024: Your Guide to Registration Options</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;So Unbound Gravel 2024 is coming up, with registrations opening already (depending on your status and distance).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are you gearing up for the Unbound Gravel 2024? Here’s everything you need to know about registration:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;random-selection-process-lotto&quot;&gt;Random Selection Process (Lotto)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due to overwhelming demand, a random selection process determines participants for the 350-mile, 200-mile, 100-mile, 50-mile, and 25-mile events. Registration is free, but credit card details are required upon application. Charges apply only upon acceptance. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.unboundgravel.com/&quot;&gt;More info&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;lottery-registration-dates&quot;&gt;Lottery Registration Dates&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;UNBOUND Gravel XL Lottery: December 1-15, 2023.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;UNBOUND Gravel 200, 100, 50, and 25 Lotteries: January 5-20, 2024.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;life-time-members-early-access&quot;&gt;Life Time Members Early Access&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Life Time members, with a minimum of six months’ membership, get early access to event registrations and guaranteed spots in lotteries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(sourced from social media)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The LT early access doesn’t open until a week prior to the lottery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Gravel XL – May 31, 2024&lt;br /&gt;
Member Guaranteed Registration: November 24, 2023&lt;br /&gt;
General Lottery: December 1-15, 2023&lt;br /&gt;
Member registration opens at 10 AM MST on 11/24/23&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;UNBOUND Gravel 200/100 –June 1, 2024&lt;br /&gt;
Member Guaranteed Registration: December 29, 2023&lt;br /&gt;
General Lottery: Jan 5-20, 2024&lt;br /&gt;
Member registration opens at 10 AM MST on 12/29/23&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;notification-and-fees&quot;&gt;Notification and Fees&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Selected participants will be notified by email. Event fees, processing fees, and taxes will be charged upon selection. Entry fees for various distances are yet to be determined.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;registration-rules&quot;&gt;Registration Rules&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Only one application per person is allowed. Special consideration is given to multi-time finishers nearing the 1,000 Mile Club status. Life Time members with a qualifying membership duration can bypass the lottery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;deferral-policy&quot;&gt;Deferral Policy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Participants can defer their entry to the following year, with varying fees based on how far in advance the deferral is requested. No refunds or transfers are allowed. (deferred registration was November 2023, and is closed now)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;alternative-entry-options&quot;&gt;Alternative Entry Options&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apart from the lottery, you can gain entry by collaborating with charity partners, signing up for UNBOUND Gravel Training Camp, or opting for a coaching package. Volunteering at the event also offers future participation benefits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stay tuned for more updates and start planning your journey to one of the most challenging and rewarding gravel events in the world!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2023 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.bicycletips.com/unbound-gravel-2024-lotto</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bicycletips.com/unbound-gravel-2024-lotto</guid>
        
        
        <category>Bike</category>
        
        <category>Gravel</category>
        
        <category>Unbound</category>
        
        <category>LifeTime</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Bicycle Maintenance Tips and Instructions</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Bike Maintenance Instructions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cleaning:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Regular cleaning is an essential part of bike maintenance. Before performing any maintenance, you should start by cleaning the bike frame, chain, gears, and other parts.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;To clean the bike, you’ll need a degreaser and a soft cloth. Apply the degreaser to the areas that need cleaning, such as the chain, gears, and frame, and scrub gently with the cloth.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;This will help remove grime and dirt that can build up over time. Once you’ve finished cleaning, rinse the bike with water to remove any leftover degreaser.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lubrication:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;After cleaning, you should lubricate the chain and gears.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;A good lubricant will help protect the metal parts from rust and corrosion, and it will also make the bike run more smoothly.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Apply a few drops of lubricant to the chain, and then use a clean cloth to spread it evenly. Be sure to lubricate the gears as well, especially those that are exposed to the elements.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tires:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Check the tires for proper pressure and inspect them for damage or wear.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;If you’re using a road bike, you should aim for a pressure of around 100-130 psi, while mountain bikes typically require a lower pressure of around 30-50 psi.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;If the pressure is too low, use a pump to fill the tires to the correct level.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Check the tires for cuts, punctures, or other signs of damage, and replace the tire if necessary.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Brakes:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Check the brake pads for wear and adjust if needed.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;If the brake pads are worn down to the metal, they will need to be replaced.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Check the brake cables as well, and make sure they are tightened properly.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;If the brakes are not functioning properly, you may need to take the bike to a professional mechanic for a more in-depth inspection.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Drivetrain:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Check the tightness of the bolts on the crank arm, pedals, and bottom bracket, and tighten any that are loose.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Check the gears to make sure they are shifting smoothly.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;If the gears are not shifting properly, you may need to adjust the derailleur.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Steering:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Check the tightness of the stem bolts, headset, and handlebar, and tighten any that are loose.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Make sure the handlebars are positioned correctly, and that the bike is easy to steer.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;If the steering feels loose or wobbly, you may need to take the bike to a professional mechanic for further inspection.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Suspension:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;If your bike has suspension, it’s important to check it regularly to make sure it’s functioning properly.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Check for proper suspension function and adjust accordingly.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;If the suspension feels stiff or bouncy, you may need to make some adjustments.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Wheel true:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Ensure that the wheels spin straight and true.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;If the wheels are not true, you may need to make some adjustments to keep the bike riding smoothly.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Chain wear:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Over time, the chain will start to wear down and stretch.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;To check for chain wear, use a chain wear indicator tool.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;If the chain is worn, it will need to be replaced to avoid damage to the gears.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;A worn chain will cause shifting problems, so it’s important to replace it promptly.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Final Inspection:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;After performing all the above checks and maintenance, give the bike a final inspection.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Test ride the bike to ensure it is running smoothly and everything is functioning properly.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Check the brakes, gears, and steering, and make any necessary adjustments.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;If anything seems out of place, take the bike back to a professional mechanic for further inspection.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note:&lt;/em&gt; Regular maintenance is important to keep your bike running smoothly and to extend its lifespan. If you are unsure about performing any of these maintenance tasks, take the bike to a professional mechanic for assistance.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.bicycletips.com/bicycle-maintenance</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bicycletips.com/bicycle-maintenance</guid>
        
        
        <category>Bike</category>
        
        <category>Maintenance</category>
        
        <category>Tips</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Getting into Unbound Gravel 2023</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Did you know that the Lotto for entry into Unbound Gravel 2023 opens today? (January 5th, 2023). If you are interested in getting into the event, you should definitely check out our post from last year on various registration options &lt;a href=&quot;/unbound-gravel-2022-registration-options&quot;&gt;Unbound Gravel Registration Options&lt;/a&gt; page for more information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good luck if you are trying to get in! I just got my registration squared away and will be riding 100 miles again this year, planning to drop time from my finish last year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t forget, if you don’t get in through the Lotto, you can still volunteer in ‘23, if it is like past years, if you volunteer 10 hours, you get to bypass the lotto for ‘24.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.bicycletips.com/unbound-gravel-2023-lotto</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bicycletips.com/unbound-gravel-2023-lotto</guid>
        
        
        <category>Bike</category>
        
        <category>Gravel</category>
        
        <category>Unbound</category>
        
        <category>LifeTime</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Finding a place to stay at Unbound Gravel</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;So you’re thinking you might want to go to Unbound Gravel 2023? The lottery won’t open up until January 2023, but if you haven’t booked a hotel already, you’re out of luck.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Emporia’s hotels book up really quickly. If you haven’t booked already, you are likely out of luck, but if you follow some of the tips below, we’ll try to help you find a place to stay that doesn’t take you an hour plus of driving each way (Topeka).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(6/30/2022) I was able to book a room at a hotel this morning, so there are still some available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So here are the tricks to finding a hotel in Emporia Kansas for Unbound Gravel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Start early. I start looking at hotel websites the weekend of the current year’s event. Most hotels don’t open up their booking windows that far in advance, but some do, and the rest have them open soon there after.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Look often. Check your hotel websites DAILY, if not morning and evening, to increase your odds of finding when they open up the booking window.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Check all the hotels in Emporia&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Avoid the Knight’s Inn. People apparently are able to book here, but from what I hear the past two years, it actually doesn’t exist anymore, it isn’t open.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Check again&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Don’t fret if you don’t find a hotel, keep looking! In January people who don’t make the lottery will start cancelling their bookings.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Look into the college dorms, they typically open up for registration in January or February, but sell out quickly. Their rates include meals as well.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;As we get closer to the ride, pay attention to the Unbound Gravel (unofficial) Facebook Group. People often times post there when 9hey are cancelling their rooms.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Look outside of Emporia, get a room that can be cancelled at no charge in case you find something in town.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Keep looking!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re diligent, you can almost assuredly get yourself a hotel room in Emporia for Unbound Gravel!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2022 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.bicycletips.com/unbound-gravel-hotels</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bicycletips.com/unbound-gravel-hotels</guid>
        
        
        <category>Bike</category>
        
        <category>Gravel</category>
        
        <category>Unbound</category>
        
        <category>LifeTime</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Unbound Gravel 100 2022 Ride Review</title>
        <description>
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2022 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.bicycletips.com/unbound-gravel-2022-ride-review</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bicycletips.com/unbound-gravel-2022-ride-review</guid>
        
        
        <category>Bike</category>
        
        <category>Gravel</category>
        
        <category>Unbound</category>
        
        <category>LifeTime</category>
        
        <category>Mud</category>
        
        <category>Ride Review</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Ordering a bike from Canyon</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;For the past few years I’ve had dreams of buying a new bicycle. I went back and forth on what to get, where to get it, etc. Last year when Canyon announced the Grizl, I knew what I was going to buy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was a little concerned about purchasing a direct to consumer brand, but after seeing Canyon’s support of the gravel scene last year, and getting some of their swag at Unbound, I decided I felt safe enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ordered-a-canyon-grizl&quot;&gt;Ordered a Canyon Grizl&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was early/mid December when the bike finally came in stock in my size, so I placed the order. The first two rides were great, I was getting adjusted to the bike, the new shimano components (first time with Shimano components on a bike). On the third ride I noticed that the big ring up front seemed to have issues, like it was deformed/bent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Originally I thought it was just a bent tooth on the ring, I’ve experienced that before, but upon further inspection I wasn’t able to find a single tooth that was off. I was able to see when hand pedalling that the chain looked to shift over when it got to a couple of teeth, causing the bike to feel like it wanted to shift to the smaller ring up front. I was able to ride, but if the rear cassette was in any of the 4 or 5 larger rings, pedalling was inconsitant as it wanted to continually downshift up front.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;canyon-grizl-with-a-bent-front-chain-ring&quot;&gt;Canyon Grizl with a bent front chain ring&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Upon getting home from the ride I inspected further and was able to determine that the main chain ring looks to be misshapen. I ended up calling Canyon’s support number, was told it would likely be under warranty as I hadn’t had the bike for long, and that I needed to go online and submit a support request with photos of the problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2022/CanyonSupport/Canyon-2-800-9bfb9a93a.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;/assets/images_out/Content/2022/CanyonSupport/Canyon-2-200-9bfb9a93a.jpg 200w, /assets/images_out/Content/2022/CanyonSupport/Canyon-2-400-9bfb9a93a.jpg 400w, /assets/images_out/Content/2022/CanyonSupport/Canyon-2-800-9bfb9a93a.jpg 800w, /assets/images_out/Content/2022/CanyonSupport/Canyon-2-1166-9bfb9a93a.jpg 1166w&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;canyon-customer-service&quot;&gt;Canyon Customer Service&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I did that, I went through the process of putting together photos trying to document the problem for them. I uploaded those photos and submitted the form on February 2nd, 2022. I immediately received an email with a case number, and in the email it said something to the effect of “if you don’t hear from us in 12-15 business days, please give us a call”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From a customer service perspective, this is NOT a great first introduction to direct to consumer customer service. Actually, my first experience was calling them and they told me to submit the form, so that was a pretty poor experience initially, followed by an even worse one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So here we are, February 17th, 2022. I went for another ride the other day, the chain ring definiteyl still has problems, making riding in the big ring a chore unless I’m really up to speed, causing me to run the small ring more than I typically would. I called Canyon’s customer support line today, and after waiting on hold for 15 minutes (their call back option wouldn’t take my button press for some reason) I finally spoke with a rep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;great-news&quot;&gt;Great News&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He asked me for my case number, read the case, looked at the photos, then informed me that I had a 2 year warranty on components.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;bad-news&quot;&gt;Bad News&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would have to go direct to Shimano for the warranty work for the chain ring. He provided a phone number I would need to call to open up a support request.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;15 days, two weeks, and I had to call Canyon, to be told that I would need to call Shimano to get support instead? Why couldn’t someone at Canyon have told me that two weeks ago?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So now I have a call back request in with Shimano. I called them 30 minutes ago. I’ll update this post as I find out how big of an ordeal it is trying to actually get support from a direct to consumer bicycle brand….&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;update-after-response-from-shimano&quot;&gt;Update after response from Shimano&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Got a call back from Shimano today. They provided me two options to get the warranty work done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) I can go to a local bike shop (assuming they need to sell shimano, but he didn’t say that directly) and they can do the inspection and file the warranty request with Shimano.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) I can fill out a form on Shimano’s website, then I can mail in the part and have them inspect it and determine if it is under warranty….&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I will lean towards option 1 and hope that Trailhead will help me out on this one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;direct-to--consumer-bicycles-is-it-good-for-you&quot;&gt;Direct To  Consumer Bicycles, is it good for you?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am not sure….&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2022 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.bicycletips.com/ordering-a-bike-from-canyon</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bicycletips.com/ordering-a-bike-from-canyon</guid>
        
        
        <category>Online</category>
        
        <category>Bike</category>
        
        <category>Gravel</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>2021 Year in Review and 2022 Coming Into View</title>
        <description>
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 16:31:57 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.bicycletips.com/2021-year-in-review-2022-coming-into-view</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bicycletips.com/2021-year-in-review-2022-coming-into-view</guid>
        
        
        <category>Life</category>
        
        <category>2021</category>
        
        <category>2022</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
